Heat.
Hey, Heat.
Hello everybody. Good evening and good
day and welcome back to the Ask Abij
show. This is episode 346.
I hope you're all doing great. We're
going to be discussing what's happening
in the world, the war in Iran and
anything else that you would like to
discuss. And before we get into that,
let's see who all is there on this on
this live stream this fantastic day. We
have Push Sa Dashan Patel from Dip,
California.
California, Canada. Okay. Himman Hawati
Kumar Himawati Kumar Luish Tind Ritik
Pawar One Punch Man the posture CEO
Chira Shinat Mar good morning Pratt Dana
Namaste Geopolitical Dub is here from
Indor good evening sir Ashwani Sharma
Shanda Abhinavil Doohi Vodhavos
Aryasi S KC9
HR Jimmy Lee Jimmy Lee are you sing pron
Nam Sar gi uh feel strong man namaste is
field strong man is here from Chennai
namaste good to see you know vhav u
nirvana shanks a
dic shrian poly nomial abishek shukla
live somi once again soldier boy says
where is the chava index it is in the
process of being uh reconstructed
because it's been a while so we need to
ingest new data to recalculate the score
so it's in the process we Ranu Nahapana
good to see you. Sanju geopolitical way
from Indoor good to see you. GK GK
Nabari Tadas good evening Nisha live
invites me to visit Kpur. I would love
to visit Kandur. Thank you. Silicon two
stars the feminist slayer
good to see you. Rendam Roy hello
unpopular opinion. Uh Rishab
Ashish Tomar Tesh Pand really now Miss
Patel. Namaste Shatabish. Good uh good
afternoon. Good afternoon to you. Jimmy
Kudo Hershit Goyel. Good evening. Basant
Ramar Sarji Priyani Sud Om. Good evening
ma'am. Alak Lada. Hey. Hey. Uh DI
Shrian. Swami is here from Jaipur. Good
to have you. Swami Paswal. Dr. Atul from
Kochi. Hello. Prane Karm. Karmmoker.
Good evening. Um Random Skull. Good to
see you. Vanish Achara Shubankar
Gulkarni. Chat DSP. Namaste. Good to see
you. We'll talk about that. Martian Viml
Chri unknown radar unknown dar Somalia
Paul uh Somalia Paul from West Bengal.
Thank you so much sir. Good to see good
to see you. Good to have you. Thank you
so much. Really appreciate that. Um and
so many other people. Sagar Gumar
Kumar is here. Shankal Pativari Ashin
Dragon from Kerala. Namaskarum
Kahan. Kahan is here. Good to see you,
Sumatari Chiva Chhat DSP Makavin
Durandu. I haven't seen it yet. Still
haven't seen it. Maybe tomorrow. We'll
see. We'll see. Okay. All right. Uh,
Hard Candy, good to see you. Hard Candy.
Uh, Anabil Sarkcar Meshv Martian.
Martian is here. Marin Minmoy Dar.
Namaste. Namaste.
Oh, Ready. I was ready. Good to see you.
Good to see you. Uh, Namo Indra XIT
Trump T2B.
Okay.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Let's get going with
what's happening. So before uh who else
do we have? Um um EXO XD Kanglay
Kurumjari Naval Keshor Kopu
and Pritir Singh Rajput from
Maharashtra. Good to have you. Pray
Karmukar. Thank you so much. Been
following for four years. Thank you so
much. Thank you so much.
Okay. So what's happening in the world?
Before I take some questions, let's uh
before I take your questions, let's see
what's been happening. Let's take a look
at what Trump has been saying. What
Trump has been saying, okay, the past 2,
three days. So, we did the last live
stream like two, three, three days ago.
Uh, yeah, about 3 days ago. And it seems
like a lot has happened in the past 3
days. So, let's take a look at Trump,
Mr. Trump, President, American President
Trump's uh true social account, which is
where he expresses his opinions very
liberally. So, this is from 3 days ago.
This is by Trump himself. The biggest
bridge in Iran comes tumbling down.
Never to be used again. Never to be used
again. He's so confident. Much more to
follow. He promises it is time for Iran
in capital letters to make a deal before
it's too late. So he is desperate for a
deal with Iran. He's begging the
Iranians for a deal. It's time for Iran
to make a deal before it's too late. And
there is nothing left of what still
could become a great country. President
DJT.
So yeah, this is how he negotiates,
you know. So he's asking for he he wants
the Iranians to come to the table and uh
make a deal with him with the United
States.
Uh this is from April 3 once again just
like okay this is from 2 days ago. Today
is April 5 I think. Yeah it's April 5
today. Our military the greatest and
most powerful by far anywhere in the
world hasn't even started destroying
what's left in Iran. Bridge is next.
Then electrical electric power plants
new regime leadership knows what has to
be done and has to be done fast.
President DJT. So more threats and more
supplication, right? He says that we're
going to send you back to the stone age.
Essentially, we're going to destroy your
bridges, destroy your electric power
plants. Isn't this a war crime to
destroy civilian infrastructure? But if
Donald Trump does it, it's I suppose
it's okay. Yeah. So, okay. So, he's
still he's once again asking the
Iranians to uh, you know, come to the
table and uh make a deal make a deal
with him, a negotiate a deal with him.
What else?
Um, with a little more time we can
easily open the hormone straight, take
the oil and make a fortune. It will be a
gusher for the world. President Donald
J. Trump. This is once again from April
3, 2 days ago. So he says that just a
little more time we will reopen the
state of Hormos. We'll open it ourselves
and we will take the oil from wherever
oil exists in this region because you
know we are so powerful. We can just
take it. It's ours and we'll make a
we'll make a fortune. We'll make a
fortune. So this is the same exact
mindset that the you know the west has
had for the past 500 years because you
know might is right. If we can do it
then we shall do it. That sort of thing
doesn't matter who it belongs to. So
yeah what else do we have? Keep the oil
and I have no idea what it means but I
suppose he's talking about he he's going
to keep the oil that belongs to Iran and
other nations. I suppose that's what
he's trying to say. Uh okay this is from
yesterday
evening about 24 hours ago. He says
remember when I gave Iran 10 days to
make a deal and or open up the hormone
straight time is running out 48 hours
before all hell will reig
down on them. Glory be to God the
President Donald Trump. So this is a
threat you know he's giving an
ultimatum. Uh he's giving them a hard
deadline 48 hours. This is yesterday. So
I suppose 48 hours or 24 hours of of
that has gone. What else? Uh this is a
truth. This not truth. This is a tweet
or a post from uh today early very early
morning today for us in India. Many of
Iran many of Iran's military leaders who
have led them poorly and unwisely are
terminated. Terminated means murdered
assassinated by by the Americans along
with much else with this massive strike
in Thran. President Donald Trump. Uh
yeah, more more death, destruction,
murder, assassination. I suppose that he
that's what he's claiming. What else we
have? Uh yeah, some he's claiming that
the US has rescued one of their uh
downed F15
fighter pilots. So this is what he says.
This is from um today evening like this
is from about 3 hours ago. Less than 3
years ago, less than 3 hours ago. We
have rescued the seriously wounded and
really brave F-15 crew member/officer
from deep inside the mountains of Iran.
The Iranian military was looking hard in
big numbers and getting close. He is a
highly respected colonel. This type of
raid is seldom attempted because of the
danger to man and equipment. It just
doesn't happen. The second raid came
after the first one where we rescued the
pilot in broad daylight. Also unusual
spending seven hours over Iran. An
amazing show of bravery and talent by
all. I will be having a news conference
with the military at the Oval Office on
Monday at 1 p.m. God bless our great
military warriors, President DJT. Okay,
so they have apparently I mean that's
what they claim that they have rescued
one of you know you know both the both
the uh uh pilots of that F-15 that went
down over Iran over Iran. Uh what else?
This is a more unhinged statement uh
that that came about about 10 minutes
after the previous one. Trump says
Tuesday will be power plant day and
bridge day all all wrapped up all
wrapped up in one. There will be nothing
like it. Open the effing straight you
crazy bastards or you'll be living in
hell. Just watch. Praise be to Allah.
But
what is he trying to say? So obviously
he's he's uh he's uh making threats.
Obviously he's he's saying that you know
we have blown up a few of your power
plants. We we've destroyed one of your
bridges on Tuesday. We're going to do
way more than that. We're going to be
we're going to be we're going to destroy
way more power plants. We will we'll
destroy many more bridges. That's what
he's saying. So, make a deal with us.
Give in to our demands and things will
be fine. Otherwise, I'm going to I'm
going to, you know, make you live in
hell and then please open the straight.
Please open the straight of Hormos,
you crazy bastards. And this is the kind
of language a US president uses. Okay,
sir. Okay. Uh yeah. So that's about
Trump and let's take a this seems to be
a reasonably accurate uh tally of how
many uh aircraft and aerial assets the
Americans have lost thus far over the
past 35 or so days. So US Army aircraft
losses to um
oh this is just about the this is just
about the F-15. Okay. US Army aircraft
losses to rescue the two crew members of
downed F-15 jet over Iran.
Iran confirmed losses current tally one
F-15 aircraft destroyed two times HH60
helicopters destroyed one MH6 Little
Bird helicopter destroyed one A10
Thunderbolt Wartthog aircraft destroyed
two C130 Hercules transport aircraft
destroyed uh one or two MQ9 Reaper
drones destroyed and there's more
unconfirmed or possible damage of one
F-16
uh one KC 135 straight tanker uh
refueling aircraft and one more A10
warthog per possible emergency landing.
So in the course of one military
mission,
these many aircraft are definitely
destroyed.
Okay?
And that is acceptable.
You see when you have a milit a set of
military objectives, you decide what
kind of losses are acceptable and you go
ahead and lose those things. I mean,
they have lost massive, massively large
aircraft. C130 Herculus, that's a
ginormous aircraft. They've lost two of
those. They claim that they they blew
them up themselves or whatever, doesn't
matter.
So, how many? 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 eight
aircraft are guaranteed destroyed.
Okay. and and and in India.
Yeah. Indians cry about let's say Trump
was Trump was claiming last year that
India lost seven fighter planes or
something right over the three-day war.
And Indians are like oh my god all hell
has broken loose. We have lost the war
because we lost seven fighter planes. We
don't even know if we lost seven fighter
planes. I don't know how many we
possibly lost or not. Trump was claiming
it was four then five then six then
seven. He kept on ramping up the numbers
and he knew that the Indians are going
to take that as a as a military defeat.
Indians seem to have no brains
whatsoever.
It is perfectly fine to lose military
assets. These are called tactical
it's it's called um tactical losses.
It's not it's not a loss actually. It's
an expenditure of military equipment.
Why do you have military equipment to
use it and possibly some some of it get
lo gets lost right?
If you you can lose a few tanks, you can
lose a few you know howitzers, you can
lose artillery, you can lose aircraft,
it's fine as long as you achieve your
military objectives. So in India it's
all about oh my god we lost aircraft
bahoo
the Americans are perfectly fine with
this. No one in the US media is claiming
that the US is losing the war even
though they actually are. They're still
claiming we're winning.
But you see they it looks like they have
I mean they're claiming they rescued the
two pilots and looks like they have. I
mean let's take them at their word. So
they achieved what they wanted to
achieve and they were okay with losing
these many aircraft.
So in India we need to grow up a little
bit. you know, stop complaining and stop
crying and moaning about things that
don't really matter that much.
We destroyed I mean, we hit so many
Pakistani military targets.
We hit so many a large number of
Pakistani terrorist training camps. We
took out a large number, maybe hundreds
of terrorists. In a in a matter of a few
hours, we hit 11 or 12 Pakistani air
force bases.
that we will not look at but we'll say
oh we lost seven aircraft this is an
major issue with the Indian mindset
right because someone from abroad is
saying something oh my god it means we
must have lost so that is something we
need to you know guard against and we
need to change the way we think and the
way we look at things military assets
are expendable assets they exist they
exist to be used and and expended if
required and that's perfectly fine what
really matters is the outcome of the of
the of the of the war or of the battle
or whatever. Okay. Okay. So now let's
take some questions shall we? What
questions do we have? Let me see. Um
okay, we have uh number of questions.
Okay. Uh Ritik P says, I don't think
Putin is a hardliner but if a hard if a
hardliner leader takes charge of Russia
after Putin, will Russia move westward?
Um what is the definition of a
hardliner?
It depends on well the context. Some
people can be hardliners in the matter
of culture that I'm going to be
culturally expansionist and I'm going to
expend spread my culture everywhere
without doing anything else.
Putin has been very hardline about
Russia's u national interest and
military and and and
um security matters right he has in the
past u made overtures to the west like
in the 2000s he actually proposed that
Russia wants to join NATO he proposed
that the US said no they slam the door
in Putin's face but yeah he did propose
that so he has tried his best multi on
multiple occasions to make peace with
the west. He has said that we don't
desire confrontation, but the west has
been confrontational with him. Uh so
overall, you could say that he's not
that sort of an expansionist
hegemonic-minded person, right? He just
wants Russia to coexist peacefully with
everybody else as far as possible and
the West hasn't allowed this to happen.
Um so yeah, he's not that hardline from
that perspective. There are certain red
lines he has and he doesn't tolerate
those being crossed and that's why the
Ukraine war has happened and other
things have happened but overall he's
not someone who seeks Russian hgemony
over the world he doesn't look like that
on the other hand was a pretty hardline
person but he never came to power of
course
so you're asking if a hardliner takes
charge of Russia after putin will Russia
move westward well it depends um if
Russia has the military wherewithal to
do
and a hardliner comes to power, yeah,
certainly they will possibly move
westward. It depends on Russia's
capabilities and what the leader seeks.
So in the future in India, if a hardline
leader comes to power and India has the
capacity to do certain things, then
certain things will happen. It depends.
So it depends on two things. First, what
the leader wants and secondly, whether
Russia is capable, Russia's
infrastructure, military, etc. are
capable of achieving that or not. It
depends on those two things. So we don't
know first of all if such a leader will
come to power in the future and secondly
we don't know that at that point in time
will Russia's capabilities be so and so
or so and so or whatever. So based on
those two main considerations things may
go in various directions. U so my point
is I don't know it will depend on lots
of factors. It will depend on lots of
factors. Uh right now we have no idea of
who could come to power in Russia after
Mr. Putin whenever decides steps down.
And secondly, we will we don't know as
of now what Russia's industrial
capabilities, economic capabilities and
military capabilities will be like.
Looks like Mr. Putin over the past 25
years has turned Russia around
completely, right? Uh so it looks like
Russia's military capabilities and the
industrial capability that that supports
the military capabilities these are all
in place. So yeah, Mr. Putin probably
has created the situation the
circumstances such that in the future if
someone who is hardline comes to power
they may perhaps uh think very seriously
of expanding uh Russian territory
possibly
the posture co says Iran got 500 ICBMs
from North Korea is that true
um I've heard some rumors about that but
there is no confirmation of that from
anybody some rumors over social media,
right? Some accounts expressing the
opinion that this sort of thing has
happened. So, let's let's see first of
all, let's see on Google. Does Google
have something to say about this? Uh,
give me a second to
Okay.
Russia
500 ICBN's
North Korea
Um, okay. Reports from April 2026
indicate a deepening military
partnership between North Korea and
Russia with with claims. So these are
once like I said these are claims with
claims that North Korea has supplied
Russia with extensive weaponry including
possible missile technology and has now
sent 500 18 ICBMs to Russia to Iran
to Iran
from by Russian territory. Okay. Okay.
Iran got 500 ICBMs. Iran not not Russia.
So it's possible. I mean the question is
why would look
so these are claims right? These are
these are claims.
Let's first of all look at the details
of the claims about that Russia is
heavily modernizing its own.
Um okay what about Iran? Right. Iran.
That was the actual question. Not Russia
but Iran.
Okay. Unverified sources have alleged
that Iran has acquired 500 ICBMs from
North Korea. Missile type was delivery
method reportedly transported by road by
China and Russia to avoid detection.
Da da da da. Okay. Source reliability.
These are obviously unverified sources.
Even I I don't take it very seriously.
There's no confirmation by official top
tier intelligence international
intelligence agency or governments. But
that doesn't mean that it's false for.
Okay, let's also remember that. So the
figure is unverified, but Iran and North
Korea, they definitely have a long
history of cooperating in various ways.
So I don't know if it's true or not,
right? Um it does make sense for Russia
and China and North Korea that that Iran
you know it makes sense sense for them
to help Iran out in this ongoing
conflict in which Iran is fighting
against more than 10 nations at the same
time. Uh but we don't know if this is
true or not. So I definitely am not
associated with any intelligence
agencies and I don't have my own sources
as such. I can only see what's out there
in the public domain. Right.
Um, so I don't know, but in case Iran
has received 500 ICBMs from North Korea,
well, that's interesting. If if that's
true, uh, what is an ICBM?
An ICBM is an intercontinental
range ballistic missile. Okay,
intercontinental is typically what? More
than 8,000 kilometers.
So when we're talking about see Iran
already has the capability to um you
know Iran has missiles with roughly
4,000 km ranges with the range of
roughly 4,000 km which gives Iran the
capability to strike anywhere in in
Europe. Let's let's take let's take an
example. Let's see um okay I am doing
this as an academic exercise. I'm not
I'm not suggesting Iran should do
anything. This is simply an academic
exercise that we are doing here. So
let's say uh you know what's the
distance from Thran for example to this
point in the Atlantic Ocean that's 5,000
km. Okay.
What's the distance from Thran to let's
say a North Sea? That's 3,000.
Okay. Just for
just for the sake of this academic
exercise, what's the distance from Thran
to London?
It's 4,380 km. So maybe London is just
too far away, but most of Western Europe
is within Iran's range if Iran so
desires to send missiles. And if if
instead of doing from Thran, we could do
from Western Europe, Western Iran. In
that case, I suppose London could be at
the edge of its range. Yes, very much
so.
So, uh, Iran does have have the cap
capacity capability to strike at any
nation in Western Europe given its
current missile capabilities. But let's
say it it receives ICBMs and wants to
hypothetically strike it somewhere in
North America. Can it do it? So let's
say the distance. Okay. Measure
distance. This is completely academic.
I'm not suggesting anything. Okay. Uh
let's say
so that's 8,000 km. Okay. 8,000 km.
Let's say
uh Okay. So the point is it gives if if
Iran does acquire ICBMs, it then gains
the ability to strike somewhere in North
America if it seeks to if it so desires
to and that would be
alarming for the United States but we
have no confirmation that this has
actually happened. Okay.
Tirangat says with the INS Arindaman
inducted and more submarines to be
inducted again under project S5 of the
Indian Navy should India prioritize
submarines over aircraft carriers in
today's day and age. Well, short answer
100% yes.
Aircraft carriers are increasingly going
to be a liability.
The United States has pulled out its
aircraft carriers from the uh you know
from the war zone. Why? because they
can't defend them. A nation like Iran,
okay, which is considered to be not a
very high-tech nation by some people, it
has the ability to wipe out America's
aircraft carriers. The American car
aircraft carriers are the best defended
aircraft carriers in the world and still
they had to pull them out. H the
American aircraft carrier strike groups.
So why do you have a strike group when
you have an aircraft carrier? Let's see
what a strike group looks like, shall
we? It's actually a defensive bubble.
Okay. So, let's see what an aircraft
carrier strike groups strike group looks
like. Aircraft carrier strike group.
So, let's see what it looks like.
So, this is what it looks like. It's an
aircraft carrier surrounded by a bubble
of a large number. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
11 12 13 14 about 15 16 20 other naval
assets. Okay.
at least 10 naval assets, destroyers and
there are unseen assets such as
submarines, a couple of nuclear
submarines loing around. Okay, and all
these other assets, okay, the this the
destroyers etc. They form a protective
bubble around the aircraft carrier. They
the Americans equip their destroyers
with Aegis systems, AEGIS, Aegis, you
know, uh systems that take care of
incoming aircraft that can shoot down
incoming missiles and so on.
So there's a large number of missiles,
maybe 200, 300 missiles,
uh, interceptors, maybe 500, let's say a
thousand interceptors that that the
entire group has. Uh, let let's let's
try and do the math, shall we?
How many Aegis missiles does uh can an
American destroyer carry?
Uh okay, let's say a missile carries uh
100 missiles and let's say you have
you've got um 15 destroyers, which is
actually overkill. Generally, it's 10 to
12. Okay, so let's see how many uh how
many ships are there in an aircraft
carrier strike group?
So, how many ships? How many ships?
So one aircraft carrier, two guided
missile carriers, three Arley Burke,
Burke class destroyers, two attack
submarines, one supply ship. So 3 + 2 is
five. Let's say it's 10. Let's say it is
10. And each each
ship can carries let's say uh 100 AUS
missiles. So that's a thousand Aegis
missiles plus some other assets like
machine guns, you know, the the the the
Gatling guns and all that they have. And
yet if you if you send a swarm of 2,000
or 1500 drones at the aircraft carrier
and slip in a few ballistic missiles or
cruise missiles, guaranteed destruction
of the aircraft carrier. The guaranteed
destruction of the entire aircraft
carrier strike group, not the
submarines, but everything else.
Destruction guaranteed.
Imagine
what effect it will have on the on the
Navy that suffers this loss. It's a
catastrophic loss. The US has about 10,
11, 12 aircraft carriers. H even if they
lose one, it'll be devastating to their
morale, but it's not it's it's about 10%
of their capability, right? Capacity. In
the case of India, if India loses an
aircraft carrier, it's a disaster that
you can't imagine.
So my point is India should completely
forget about
acquiring new aircraft carriers. We have
one or two. We have a couple, right?
Okay. Let's let's keep them for the next
20 30 years. And in if if we become if
we become a vishagur superpower in 30
years, we can get a couple more if you
want. Just for the sake of prestige that
we have this gigantic ships. They
actually do nothing. The only use
aircraft carriers have in today's day
and age is to bully the weak. Those who
can't attack you, you go and bully them.
Show them see I've got like 50 aircraft
on this on this uh aircraft carrier and
I can bomb the country. But you can't
send aircraft carriers into contested
environments. They'll be destroyed. So
India should definitely prioritize
submarines over aircraft carriers. I
know there's a lot of people even today
I suppose who say that aircraft India
should get more aircraft carriers. I
mean look at what's happening in the
Persian Gulf. Look at look at what's
happening in this region. Yeah. Aircraft
carriers the time is over. They are
obsolete. They're obsolete. You can't
send them into contested environments.
It's submarines that India should focus
on. Absolutely.
Mary Kane, good morning, Mary. Mary Kane
says, "A future global net
infrastructure of quantum sensors
utilizing Earth's magnetic fields and
anomalies/rifts
versus ancient Indian maritime
navigation grid. It's example landmarks
and use of magnetism. Question, same
thing.
The same thing. So, how did ancient
Indians navigate in the past let's say
2,000 3,000 years?" uh we did have ships
uh that pied between India and the west,
India and the east, India and the
Southeast Asia region, India and Rome
and so on. How did Indian sailors
navigate? Indian sailors used uh
magnets. So there was this this uh
instrument they use. It would be a bow
filled with oil and in the oil you'll
have a magnetized fish. It's it'll be
magnet. It will be bar magnet in the
shape of a fish. that fish would tell
you where you know you know where the
north pole was essentially. So that's
what Indians used for navigation in
addition to the magnet to the magnets
Indian sailors used the you know the
they used to reckon on the basis of
stars Indians knew the constellations
and stars etc really well. So they they
knew how to use stars for navigation. So
you would use magnets, you would you
would use stars and you would use your
experience and that's how you were able
to navigate. Obviously you would also
have landmarks etc that would tell you
uh how far you are from wherever you're
going and and so on. U so that's how
navigation was done and this happened
over a long period of time. this this
knowledge, you know, it it was acquired
over a long period of time, probably
thousands of years, and eventually if if
you were a sailor 2,000 years ago, let's
say, going eastwards or westwards, you
would essentially know exactly what
direction to go in for how many days
with so and so wind speed and you will
know all the landmarks and it will not
be that difficult to navigate. It would
be it would have been difficult for the
earliest navigators who were going
essentially into the unknown. So that's
how Indians used to navigate. how future
global infrastructure quantum sensors
using utilizing earth's magnetic fields
anomalies rifts etc. So, and India's
ancient uh maritime u u you know
navigation systems are they the same
thing? Not quite the same thing. Um see
when you use a compass essentially
that's what the the fish thing was.
you're using uh the earth's magnetic
field and even today we use the earth's
magnetic field but today most of most
navigation is done using GPS or
satellite positioning systems like the
Russian glonas or the Chinese buu and
the American GPS the Europeans also have
something so most navigation today is
done using that and you also have uh
maps of the subsurface topology how deep
the ocean is and what kind of features
are there in case you are sub you're
using submarines or if you're in case
you're sailing close to to the
coastlines in that case you need to know
where there's shallow water so that you
stay away from that and so on. So that's
how you typically navigate today. In the
future how will navigation happen? Uh I
suppose we're going to use much of the
same things.
Um mostly
it's going to be more advanced GPS like
systems in the future and of course you
still will have sailors using compasses
of course. Um, so it's not quite the
same thing. It's different now. Um, but
yeah, things change. Things change. Uh,
methods of navigation evolve in the
future. We're going to have u navigation
that we'll have to do outside of Earth's
atmosphere. You know, when you go to
other other planets and um celestial
bodies within the solar system and so
on. So, we're going to have to invent
new methods of navigation. That keeps
evolving and that's just the way it is.
Aryawasi says, "Isn't it disgraceful to
call Israel fatherland when Arya sphere
had West Asia in Israel territory a
thousand years before Israel existed
under the Bitani Hittites Casites?"
Um well, I I don't call Israel the
fatherland. I don't do it. Uh when
whether it is disgraceful or not, well,
I shall refrain from commenting because
I think you're hinting at some political
statement from uh a political person, I
suppose. See, I don't call Israel the
fatherland.
Okay. Um, you are absolutely right.
Um, West Asia,
um, the region of West Asia, including
the territory that's now called Israel,
and even um, north of Israel, Syria, and
west of Syria, Syria, Iraq, that region,
west of that region, Anatoli, etc. You
did have kingdoms whose rulers spoke
Sanskrit, right? The Mitani, the
Hittites, Cassides, possibly cases also,
right? So it was well our folks who
ruled there before Israel existed. That
that is indeed true. Uh but today you
have the nation of Israel there and the
people I there I suppose call it the
their fatherland. Well, I think it's
perfectly fine for those people, the
Jewish people, the people of Israel, to
call Israel their fatherland. Uh, I
think it is well, I certainly would not
call Israel the fatherland. It's not the
land of my forefathers. Absolutely not.
Right. Our fatherland, motherland, etc.
It's all bat. It's all Aryat. Right.
That's that's for us. For us, it is bat
that is our motherland and fatherland.
Um so yeah beyond that I shall not uh
say anything more. I shall refrain from
commenting about political matters.
Ktoasi says and okay this is a
continuation of that and a thousand
years after Israel under Persia Greeks
Romans
um besides Ashkin Ashkanazi Jews have
Arya blood through Europe who got it
from the migrations out of India.
very likely that a lot of people in
Israel have Arya blood. I mean if the
R1A lineage is indeed an area lineage or
most likely it originates out of India
then I'm pretty sure there will be
Ashkanazi Jews who have the R1A lineage
the the R1A hlo group. Let's let's let's
see that right let's let's check it out.
Do Ashkanazi Jews have the uh R1A HLO
group?
Of course they do. Yes, there we have
it. So Ashkanazu do have the R1A YDNA
HLO group though it's not the most
commonal lineage which is J U R1A occurs
at high frequencies exceeding 50% among
Ashkanazi Levites
uh especially specifically within the
subclate R1A Y2619
suggesting a founder event from a single
ancestor roughly a thousand or 1500
years ago. R1A is common in Eastern
Europe. R1A found in Ashkanazi Levites
is a distinct unique clay. Okay. So it's
a single ancestral event that happened
with a R1A origin you know you know a
person who carried the original R1A
lineage.
So overall R1A is relatively rare in the
general Ashkinazi population. It's
highly concentrated within the Levite
subgroup.
So yes just looking at R1A. Okay let's
see R1B shall we? Let's let's also see
R1B since we're doing this. Uh do let's
see R1B. R1B is the Yamaha HLO group.
Actually
there we have it. Ashkanazi Jews also
have the R1B uh YDNA HLO group. So the
R1B HLO group is is found it's pretty
rare in India. It's the sister HLO group
of R1A and it's the daughter of R1 of R1
itself which itself is an Arya HLO group
so to say. So even the R1B folks who are
essentially the western Europeans, they
are our cousins very clearly, right? And
they are the descendants of our
forefathers.
We are all descended from the from one
common ancestor
essentially, right? Whoever is the
originator, the progenitor of the Rwan
Applo group, that one man, one man.
So yeah, Ashkanazi Jews do have the R1B
YDNA HLO group. Very interesting, right?
What's the frequency like? It's a minor
yet present patternal lineage. Um they
have R1B. Okay. So yeah, both R1A and
R1B are found there among the Jewish
people, among the Ashkanazi Jews. What
about non Ashkanazi Jews? Since we're
doing this, let's do it that too. Do
Jews?
Yeah, Jews. Yes, many Jewish people,
particularly the Ashkanazi and Sephadic
communities carry the R1B. Okay. Not not
the What about R1A? That'll be even more
common, I'm sure. Yes. Ashkanazi
Levites.
Uh what about the Safarim? What about
the Miz? Not the Miz, I'm sure.
Okay. So clearly what you're saying is
is true. um Ashkanazi Jews even Sepharic
Jews have Arya blood through through
Europe and so on. So um from that
perspective their fatherland is
definitely not Israel right if they are
are member are if they are part of the
R1 A and R1B families. Yeah definitely
not Israel as their fatherland.
Okay as says should we pref prepare for
World War II? If so, then how?
We should be prepared for economic
shocks, oil shocks in the world already.
We should be preparing for that, energy
shocks.
Um,
see what Trump is achieving here is he's
achieving something very interesting.
Trump is failing miserably in the in the
ongoing war. He's running out of
options. He is threatening and begging
in the same same post on the in the same
truth social post. Right? Let me show
you once again. Ruth social where is it?
Um
I mean this this infamous post of his.
Okay. This infamous post of his. Where
is it? Here. This one here. So he's
begging, right? He's saying, "Please
open the goddamned uh please
open the the effing straight, you crazy
bastards."
So, he's he's now exasperated. He wants
this the straight of Hormos to be open,
but the Iranians aren't willing to open
it. So, he's threatening and pleading in
the same tweet. That's what Trump is
doing. So, clearly things are going
badly for him. But you see if you look
at if you zoom out and see the bigger
picture understand what's happening
the straight of hormos you could say
it's kind of close or the Iranians are
allowing ships that are going to China
India etc some some nations to pass
through so we are getting oil from there
we are apparently India is apparently
also buying Iranian oil now uh there is
that okay but for India gas is a big
issue LPG LNG that stuff And that is not
really forthcoming now so much like it
was before. Qatar's gas uh production
and export export uh capabilities have
been hit very badly. Uh Russia can send
us gas from far away it will take 35 40
days to reach us. But if the trade of
babble babal mandib is closed by the
houthis then it's a big big big problem
for us. Even that won't reach here
otherwise unless it goes all the way
down south from the cape of good hope
which you should add another 20 30 days
for that. So essentially it means it
will take Russian oil more than two
months, Russian gas more than two months
to reach India which is a big problem.
Right? So that's the kind of situation
we are in. When it comes to other
nations, African nations, China, Japan,
uh Southeast Asian nations, even
European nations, um it's very hard for
these nations to now um you know acquire
the the the import the oil and gas that
they need. So if this situation persists
for 6 months, it's going to be a
disaster for the world. half more than
half the world will go into a recession
and the net outcome of this is going to
be that the US is going to be the
biggest gainer because they will then be
able to replace
to to stand in for the state of foremost
region nations GC nations in Iran the US
is the world's top oil producer so they
will export oil then to all these
countries possibly at at premiums and
maybe even gas I suppose I don't Does
the US produce gas? Not so much. So the
US will gain bigly from this. Now coming
to World War II. Look, Trump wants the
European nations, NATO nations to get
involved in the war in some way or the
other. He says, "Look, you need to come
in, step in and open the street of
Hormos. You can't ask us to do
everything. Listen, Trump, you started
this war and now you're asking somebody
other other nations to to pitch in to
help you out." But it is what it is. The
US is asking European nations to pitch
in and uh send their forces, military
forces to uh to open the street of
Hormuz. And even if the European nations
do that, I doubt if they'll be able to
uh force Iran to open the state of
Hormuz. And now it looks increasing
increasingly like if Trump doesn't get
what he wants in the next in the next
few days, there could be a land invasion
of Iran at some scale, maybe a 10,000
soldier scale or something at some
scale. It looks like Trump is very
seriously considering a ground invasion,
boots on the ground in Iran that will
most likely go very disastrously.
So yeah, looks like this war is not
ending. Looks like there is going to be
further escalations. If Trump is able to
drag the European countries into the
war,
okay, then you could see more
involvement from Russia, China, North
Korea in this war. It is also
significantly possible that Trump may
drag Pakistan into the war. Trump may
activate Pakistan, the eastern flank of
Iran in the war. So then there's one
more nation involved in the war and the
war is essentially directly at at our
doorstep because Pakistan is at our
doorstep and Pakistan could now get
involved in the war if Trump drags them
in. So the longer this lasts, the more
of a possibility there is that more and
more countries get dragged into the war.
There's also a very strong possibility
that the Ukraine war and the Iran war
get linked together which is already
happening of course. So I think we
should be very careful all of us. I
think we should be we should start
preparing for not worst case scenarios
but bad case scenarios. Yeah.
Uh and a lot of this
we civilians can prepare in our own
ways. How how do civilians how can
civilians prepare? You can stockpile
non-p perishable goods, non-perishable
foods and so on. You can perhaps if the
government allows stockpile some some
fuel but the real
precautions that have to be taken have
to be taken by the government of India.
So I think we should start preparing for
bad case scenarios not worst case
scenarios which is we don't want to
imagine that but bad case scenarios in
which you know there's a this war goes
on for a long time and the you know
there's a shortage long-term of cooking
gas possibly we are already seeing the
situation in India where restaurants are
no long no longer able to function
because of a shortage of cooking gas we
already seeing this now in India and
things could get worse in the coming
weeks and months
Unless there's a miracle. If unless it's
a miracle and the war ends somehow,
we'll see.
As says, let's say at this moment India
announces a huge discovery of sweet
crude in the bay of Bengal, let's say.
Okay. What would Trump's reaction and
America's reaction, what would that be
like? uh they will find some pretext
some some some kind of way of uh of
they will want to control it. Okay, they
will want to control it. You will very
quickly first of all start seeing
American freedom of navigation
operations in the region. Let me none of
you none of you is aware of this. Let me
show you this. Okay, give me a second.
Freedom of navigation.
Um,
give me a second.
So,
this is something you should know. Okay.
People say I'm very anti- US. I'm not
anti- US. I'm just pro India. Let me
show you something.
This is
from 2021.
I have absolutely nothing against the US
as long as they they don't bother us.
But look at this. H this is from 2021.
April 7, 2021. Today is April 5, 2026.
This happened six 5 years ago.
Okay.
7th Fleet conducts freedom of navigation
operation. Now we are aware that the
Americans conduct their so-called
freedom navigation operations in the
South China Sea. But look here on April
7, 2021 local time, USS John Paul Jones
asserted navigational rights and
freedoms approximately 130 nautical
miles west of the Lakshadep Islands
inside India's exclusive economic zone
without requesting India's prior consent
consistent with so-called international
law that they have defined.
India requires prior consent for
military exercises or maneuvers in its
exclusive economic zone or con
continental shelf. A claim in
inconsistent with their so-called
international law. The freedom of
navigation operation upheld the rights,
freedoms and lawful uses of the she of
the sea blah blah and ch by challenging
India's excessive maritime claims.
Okay. And these operations are are are
designed to demonstrate that the US will
fly, sail and operate wherever
international law which they have
defined allows.
Okay. So this is the US bullying India
in 2021 and none of your godamn media
reported this. And here is the same news
from the times of India which came a few
days later when they woke up and saw
this happen. So they reported it. They
reported it but you do not see any of
your your Indian media TV channels
anchors debating this or anything
right. So the US has already done this
despite uh positioning and portraying
India as as a nation with shared values
and whatnot as a friendly nation. The US
claims India we are friends of India and
this is what they do. So let's say India
announces a huge discovery of sweet
crude oil in the Lakshod region. The
Americans the first thing they will do
is they'll start sending ships through
this through this region through India's
exclusive economic zone. If it is
India's territorial waters, it they
can't do it. Even in in that case they
will start sending ships in the region
and they will try their best to somehow
disrupt India's ability to to to to uh
start extracting the oil
and they will possibly try to armrest
India in in back room conversations into
having American companies
you know extract the oil and obviously
take a take some kind of nice big fat
cut out of it and if India doesn't um
you know agree to these conditions that
they could do something nasty.
So they'll start imposing pressure on
India step by step by step by step
and if India doesn't give into their
demands they may even launch a war on
that region on that part of India. You
never know that's why it is not a good
thing for India even if this happens to
to announce a discovery. If India
discovers a huge
uh reservoir of oil, the first thing
India needs to do is to augment its navy
very rapidly and and militarize very
rapidly, way more than what the kind of
military uh posture we have right now
cuz we if we discover something like
this, we have to be able to protect it.
Okay.
Cleavian says, "Would Gavin Newsome be a
good president of the US?" I haven't
thought about it.
No idea. I haven't thought about it.
MKV says take out economic factor. Are
rods from God a good idea?
This it certainly works. They certainly
will work. Yeah. See rods of what is
rods from God? Rod from God is um
telephone telephone um
uh you have the electricity cables right
electricity poles
that you see all over the thing right so
imagine electricity pole sized roll rods
made of tungsten that are in space and
then they're shot at the earth and they
come in at very high velocity maybe mark
10 or whatever
Mac 10, Mac, Mac M 20, whatever. And
then the hit some some target and
there's no explosive on it, but the
kinetic energy itself is is so much that
it the the target is destroyed at this
huge explosion.
So that is the concept of these rods
from God.
Physically it makes sense. There is
nothing in the laws of physics that that
makes that prevents this from working.
Okay. So it's a it's not a bad idea from
a physics perspective.
Uh
but obviously you can't take out the
economic factor and you can't take out
the the complications. You have to see
if you are if you're going to position
these rods from God in space, it's going
to be an altitude at an altitude of at
least 150 200 km.
So you are shooting from 150 or 200 km
away max minimum then you have to
pinpoint hit a target with pinpoint
accuracy
otherwise you won't be able to destroy
the target right so it's an engineering
challenge
and you if you want to lift all these
rods into space it's going to be
economically pretty expensive so overall
considering everything into considering
all the factors I think it's it's not a
great idea you can't just remove the
economic factor. So from a physics
perspective, from an engineering
perspective, it certainly does work. But
the engineering uh
engineering challenge is to make it
accurate. Even if you have a 10 m
circular error probability, then you
know it may not achieve the results you
want. Somalia Paul says, "I wonder how
Iran survived 20 years sanctions, 8year
Iraq war, assassinations of key leaders
and scientists still find fighting two
stronger enemies at once and they're
still their education system is superior
to Arabs. What are your views?" Well,
it's a remarkable achievement, right? Uh
and what doesn't kill you? Look, if you
have the system, if you have the right
kind of system that's designed to
withstand these shocks,
in that case, if you have such a system,
then what doesn't kill you actually
makes you stronger.
There is this saying by nature is it
what doesn't kill you makes you
stronger. It doesn't apply to everybody.
See, I think it's by nature who said
that
what doesn't kill you makes you
stronger. Who said this?
nature
nature what does not kill me makes me
stronger. So that is not true for
everybody. It's not true for every
system. Fragile systems will be killed
and even if they survive they'll be
weakened and crippled. But if you have a
fault tolerant system then what doesn't
kill you makes you stronger. How is
Iran's system governance system fault
tolerant? So in Iran, it's not about one
political party. It's not about one
person. You kill the person, doesn't
matter. It's about the IRGC. The IRGC is
the system, the Iranian revolutionary
guard corps. And that's a decentralized
system with multiple nodes all across
Iran. You destroy one node, doesn't
matter.
You kill one person, doesn't matter.
They have a succession line that's like
five, seven deep. You kill him, another
guy comes in. It's already been
designated. Who's the successor? Who is
the success? success is also designated.
So like you have a chain of command and
a success succession line for each
position that is five to seven layers
deep
and you have so many positions in the
Iranian government. All of these
positions the succession is very clearly
defined. Not just one or two people that
multiple people like five or six or
seven people those many successors are
defined and then you have you know the
the the distributed nature of the system
then you have the mosaic warfare thing
and that's something they have been they
have been you know building for decades
decades.
Um so yeah assassinations of key leaders
makes no difference. It actually solves
problems for Iran that you know you
won't have a leader who has all these
outdated ideas. You will have newer
people coming in more hardline people
coming in younger people coming in fresh
talent coming in coming up rising to the
top. It's actually it solves big
problems that other nations aren't able
to solve. Elite over production.
This solves, you know, if if your key
leaders are routinely assassinated, it
actually is good for a nation with a 90
million population. It solves the
problem of elite poor production. It
forces you to do field promotions, which
are the best kind of promotion. Tragic,
but but good. Um,
scientists. Yeah.
Iran has one of the best education
systems.
Yeah. So and and they have been forced
to become self-sufficient in all manners
of things all kinds of things. And when
it comes to the Iranian education
system, okay, let's understand Iran's
education system. H
and the healthare system. Iran's
constitution guarantees free education
and Iran's government gives everybody
free basic healthare. If you have a
cough, if if you got a cold, if you got
a fracture, if you got something or the
other, right? You get your treatment for
free. It's only for complicated things
that you may have to pay for things for
pay for your treatment. But for all
basic healthcare, treatment is free in
Iran. When it comes to education,
education is free. There are private
institutes etc.
But the government gives free education
and education is the seats are allocated
on the on the basis of merit. There's no
reservation in Iran.
So the Iranian education system is far
superior to the Indian education system.
Okay, please understand this. The
Iranians are a very highly literate and
educated people.
You may have more PhDs in India but if
you compare the quality of the average
Indian PhD with the average Iranian PhD
like they say in Hindi Zabin Aman
okay the Iranian PhDs are genuinely they
genuinely know what they're doing in
India you can get a PhD by writing some
BS and publishing it
in Iran that doesn't work
okay so the Iranian engineers are far
better than India's The average Iranian
engineer is far better than the average
Indian engineer. And the average Iranian
scientist is far better than the average
Indian scientist. This is just a fact.
If you are if if what I am saying is is
offending you, well, it's the truth.
Facts don't care about anyone's
feelings.
So the Iranians have decided they're
going to survive all this nonsense.
What's happen what's being done to them?
And to survive, you have to adapt it.
You have to you have to improve. you
raise your standards to survive and they
have really raised the standards
right so this system actually is
designed to serve the people there is
very little corruption in Iran the
system serves the people it does it's
not a self-s serving system of course
it's an Islamic system and that's many
Indians will not like it well that's
okay that's a different thing it's a
totally different thing so that's how
Iran has been able to survive it's a
system that is fold tolerant. You take
out some nodes, you kill some leaders,
it actually strengthens the system.
That's what they've designed and there
are very few systems like this in the
world.
H okay.
Um Mishv says, "Want to read Chanakya
Artastra suggested publication?" Um I
have a Penguin version.
I It's not like I've read 17 different
versions and the best version I know.
I've there are online versions that are
available. There are uh there there are
various publications.
I have a penguin version. It's somewhere
somewhere somewhere here I suppose
somewhere here.
So yeah
get whatever you can you can either read
a free online version of the earth
shastra or you can buy one of the one of
the publications. I think as long as the
publishing house house is reasonably
reputed, reasonably reputed things will
be fine. I have not heard any complaints
about the Arthur Shastra's text being
distorted. We hear all kinds of
complaints and you know it it does
happen that the Vedas are distorted uh
translations into English. You have
distortions coming creeping in with
various religious texts. But it I've not
heard any such thing about the Art
Shastra. So hopefully things should be
fine if you get uh whichever version of
it.
Somalia Paul says could Iran have
supplied Balojasan with arms as there is
no adjoining country to get it? Look
there are two adjoining countries when
it comes to Balojasthan.
One is Iran, one is Afghanistan.
So if the Balois are getting arms and
ammunition, they are either getting it
from Iran or from Afghanistan.
Of course there could be some other
countries involved in that through
indirect means but uh that's all
speculation. Okay.
Um WBKD says do you know about the US
defeat in the battle of Mongadeshu? Of
course I know. Of course I was a
teenager then.
What was that uh
what was that American news week? I
don't know news. I forget which American
publication it was. They published
photographs of American Marines being
dragged through the streets of Moadeshu
by Somalian crowds. Those pictures
caused a tremendous uproar in the US.
Bill Clinton was the president. He took
a lot of flack for this.
Um and yeah, the Americans then made
movies about this Black Hawk Down and
all that. Of course, I know about the US
the disaster that happened over there. I
mean first of all what business did the
US have being in Moadeshu?
What business did they have being there?
Mogadeshu is in Somalia in Africa. Why
are the Americans there?
Who gave them right the right to be
there? Just like what business do they
have in Iran?
So yeah. So and then there was something
called the battle of Moadeshu. The
Americans went in with a bunch of
Pakistanis and God knows what else.
Okay.
And u
they got trapped there. They had to make
their way out of Mogadeshu. And it
looked like the whole city of Madeshu
was out there to kill them. And the
people of Mogadeshu had been given one
one single instruction. You kill one
invader and go home. All you have to do
is kill one invader then you go home. So
everyone was and so everyone was after
after the Americans and the Americans I
suppose they ended up killing more than
a thousand civilians
in their attempt to get out of Moadeshu
and a number of American marines were
killed and those were the ones who were
dragged whose bodies were dragged
through the streets of Madeshu. Um so
yes I'm aware of this.
Soldier boy says, "What do you think? Is
there
northeast
hope left or our fate is sealed?" What?
What's the question?
Is there northeast? Are you talking
about India's northeast? Is there hope
left
or the fate is sealed? Well, it all
depends on the approach and attitude of
the government of India. Since 1947,
India's government, India's successive
governments from that time have given
you could say the worst kind of
stepmotherly treatment to the region of
the northeast and they have allowed
foreigners to come in and completely
change the religion, religious
demographics of the northeast, the far
east, right? And that process still
continues for some reason right now. And
you have lacks of foreigners coming in
and settling in various parts of our
northeast especially Manipur which is
currently under attack right is there
hope well I suppose there is still hope
I suppose you should never give up hope
the fate look fate isn't sealed as such
we can still reclaim the territory
properly and rec you know reivilize the
people etc but it'll take time now this
whole process took decades.
So to undo the damage will also take
decades.
I don't think uh hope is gone but the
government of India it needs to show the
right um intention the right approach
and the right overall Yeah.
Yeah.
Somalia Paul says when you mentioned big
signs of vasal I lost all hope but kind
of rest assured after knowing Iran ship
refuge Russian imports and deputy prime
minister visit plus Iran oil imports
started any consequences.
Yeah. So this is still a work in
progress. Uh we are seeing good signs
from the way India has reoriented itself
its foreign policy since the war
started. Once the war started the first
four five days the prime minister of
India was tweeting condemnations of the
violations of sovereignty of all the GCC
nations. One day before the war started
he was in Israel. So it looked like
there was a very strong tilt towards the
US and its Gulf vasals and then slowly
and after the the supreme leader of Iran
was assassinated by the Americans and
Israelis the Indian government for a few
days said nothing about it. no
condolences to the people of Iran for
this completely uh unlawful act
and then India started and and then the
Americans they they torpedoed an an
Indian an Iranian warship that had just
left India south of Sri Lanka right they
did it south of Sri Lanka
and that's when things started changing
India gave refuge to another Iranian
warship in our port the Americans can't
reach our ports they they have no right
to and then the government of India not
at the prime minister level but lower
levels the foreign secretary level we
expressed our condolences to the people
of Iran over the over the murder of Mr.
Kamei Mr. Ali and then um
we have signed this agreement with
Russia
$25 billion worth of uh you know that
that sort of total quantum
that the of money we're going to be
purchasing Russian oil there's going to
be nuclear cooperation we're going to be
p purchasing Russian aircraft Russian
weapons
so that that is a very strong message to
the world and and to the US that we
you know, you may like it or not, but
we're going to go ahead with Russia.
Um, so a lot of things have happened. We
are now purchasing Iranian oil
apparently, possibly even Iranian
Iranian gas. We are not stopping our
imports of Russian oil. So overall,
India is charting a very independent
independent foreign policy.
Um, whatever tilt we had showed shown in
the first 3 4 days of the war, we have
reversed it.
So that tells you that India is not
being vasalized as of now at least.
But I said it it's going to be I said uh
there's a 50% chance over the next 5
years, right? So we'll have to see about
that. Right now this is good signs and
I'm very pleased with this. Right.
Um yeah, Russian imports deputy. Yeah,
the Russian delegation came to India
recently. Russia's deputy prime
minister. Yes. Uh so yeah, these are all
very good signs of India's sovereignty.
So yeah, one hopes that this continues.
Yeah. And if the US doesn't do well in
this war against Iran, that gives India
more leverage over the Americans, which
is a good thing for us. Yeah. And
anyway, it's not like I I am anti- US
and I'm pro Iran. I am pro- India. I am
pro-India sovereignty. And the fact of
the matter is that the US has no
business attacking Iran.
The US has no business being in this
region. The United States is on the
other side of the planet.
So uh yeah. Okay. Ashoto Dar says, "Mha,
Ministry of Home Affairs is exploring
border security using alligators and
snakes in unfensed India, Bangladesh
areas. Thoughts and concerns about
effectiveness.
We really have not aware of this. Snakes
and alligators,
alligators, we don't have alligators in
India. We have crocodiles. the uh
the saltwater crocodile, the largest
crocodile species in the world. That's
what we have in the region in on the
east coast of India. So that's a pretty
dangerous frightful crocodile. Let's
see. Let's see about this.
India Bangladesh border security
crocodiles snakes.
Okay. India's BSF border security force
is exploring the use of snakes and
crocodiles as natural eco-friendly
deterrence to prevent illegal crossing
and smuggling in roughly 175 km of
treachers riverine and riverine and
marshy stretches along the India
Bangladesh border. This unconventional
strategy proposed under the visionary
guidance of home minister Shri Shaji
focuses on areas where unconventional
fencing is impossible. target areas. The
focus is on porous river channels in
marshlands that are challenging to
monitor physically aiming to uh fill
security gaps according to whatever. Um
so the animals will serve as a
psychological and physical barrier. Uh
it will curb infiltration, cattle
smuggling, other illegal activities. Uh
the proposal is in the initial
exploration phase. The initiative phases
questions about ecological blah blah.
Who cares about the goddamn questions as
long as it um as it works?
Okay. So, snakes and crocodiles. Let's
ask the AI some more interesting
questions. Uh, yeah, that sort of thing.
Um, I mean,
are any other animal species being
considered at the moment?
Let's see what the EI has to say.
So, we're talking about crocodiles and
snakes. Um, in 2023, the BSF tried
honeybees.
Okay. Honeybees.
Okay. Indigenous dog breeds. That's
okay. Um, reptile shield. Okay. So, it's
about snakes and crocodiles. We not uh
uh thinking of deploying tigers or
rhinoes or any other thing. We're
talking about snakes and crocodiles.
Okay. I don't know what happened. Okay.
So, snakes and crocodiles. I'm not sure
if any other animals are being you are
being considered to be used. Um,
see, it's a it's an interesting thing to
consider.
See, if you have snakes and crocodiles
patrolling these areas, the border
areas, one advantage of having snakes
and crocodiles is that you can't bribe
them. A Bangladeshi infiltrator can't
give a crocodile 5,000 rupees and say,
"Let me cross over. A cattle smuggler
can't have a, you know, um, a weekly
payment that they'll give to the
crocodile or the snake and let the cro
snakes and crocodiles let them pass
across across the border." So I think
it's not a bad thing. I think it's a
very interesting strategy that the home
minister has thought of. It's actually
something you can take seriously.
So
how many crocodiles will be will be will
we deploy? Will they be free to roam
around the areas or will they be will
they have some
certain parameters they have to be
within? I'm not sure. Snakes. What kind
of snakes? I suppose we can use um
various cobra species. I suppose vipers
saw scale. No, saw scale vipers are in
dry environments. This is a marshy area.
I suppose you can we could use uh king
cobras and various cobra species.
Not pythons. Kuba pythons aren't that
scary compared to Yeah. Um I don't have
any concerns about this. I think it's
not a bad idea. Make the whole place
crawl with snakes and crocodiles.
and yeah that um that could be an
additional deterrent to any infiltrator
who wants to cross over into India. Um
so I think it's it's not a bad thing to
think about you know it'll also ensure
that you have more crocodiles and and
snakes in the world. I don't think
they're endangered as such. Is the
saltwater crocodile endangered? I don't
think it's an endangered species. It's
found all across the Indian Ocean region
all the way to Australia, Northern
Australia.
So yeah, I don't think it's a bad idea.
The only thing is how do you ensure this
this this stretch of land 150 200 km you
have sufficient snakes and crocodiles
there
I think you know snakes you can mitigate
by wearing leather boots or whatever
crocodiles are going to be the real game
changer I think so I think we should
have yeah maybe if it's 200 kilometers
how many crocodiles do you want to have
in one square kilometer
I would say if you have too many they'll
fight each other so I think which you
have to consider the the specifics and
the logistics and how you going to make
it happen. How you do you ensure
crocodiles are there along the border
and how do you ensure I mean
eventually even crocodiles get satiated
after eating a certain amount of food
then they go to sleep right like all
reptiles then how do you replace that
crocodile in case it is siated whatever
you have to think about the logistical
factors in this but it's an interesting
um thing to consider
dark side of the moon says search DHPM
operation Synindor PDF page 3839 last
paragraph 10th Mayo. Okay, let's let's
do that. Uh I hope it's something
interesting. Okay, so
CHPM operation PDF
what is that
prospective military military? CHPM CPM
CP um CHPM
What does page 38 have to say and 39
have to say? Let's see.
impact marks on the Kirana Hills complex
adjacent to Saroda Air Base and
suspected housing part of Pakistan's
nuclear arsenal.
Okay. Immunition impacts car. It's 100
meters from a sentry post. Okay.
Claims difficult to verify. Overall, the
Indian side estimated that at the
conclusion of the 88 hour aerial
conflict, it had destroyed between nine
to 10 Pakistani combat aircraft, one
eye, one morei and one more or one
electronic warfare aircraft, one C130
transport either through the responded
batteries or during their airto ground
strikes. Additionally, two surface to
missile batteries and at least six
radars were also repeatedly reportedly
neutralized.
Some of these claims are actually
supported by imagery. On the Pakistani
side, claims reached as many as eight
aircraft including four Rafals bearing
the serial number so and so and one S400
battery. That's what the Pakistanis
claimed. Nevertheless, and for both
sides, results claiming from claims
resulting from the long range engagement
of their surfaceto-air missile batteries
or fighter aircraft appear primarily to
stem stem for information collected
during the encounters by the radars and
electronic warfare and and electronic
intelligence assets. While this method
may seem at first sight entirely
reliable, it is based on technical and
objective data. The reality reality is
more complex. The sudden disappearance
of a target aircraft from Da.
Okay. So Pakistani losses claimed by
adversary visually documented. So this
claims that visually documented India
lost one Rafal, one miraoy
and the Pakistan has claimed much more.
Um,
okay. So,
okay. So, all right.
Um, okay.
Right.
24. Bat says, "What was the truth behind
the Bukha massac? Mass massacre?" I
don't know. What is the Bukha massacre?
Bkha.
Oh, Ukraine war. I I have no idea. I
don't know what the truth is. See, the
Ukraine war, there's no way to verify
what's happening, right? The Ukraine war
started in February 2022,
right? And all kinds of claims have been
made since there. Both sides have
accused the other of perpetrating
atrocities and massacres and whatnot and
whatnot.
Um, and of course, the the stronger
claims come from the Ukrainian side and
the western side, accusing Russia of all
kinds of horrific things. But how do you
verify that?
I don't know.
So I I don't bother with these things.
There's no I'm not saying it's not
concerning that human rights or abuses
may be happening, civilians may be
targeted. Obviously, it's it's horrible.
I don't bother with this because I have
no way to verify the claims.
I have no way to verify the claims. So I
have no idea. So I simply stick to
you know where the line on the map is
and what side is doing what and what
operation is going on currently and is
the line of the map going in this
direction or that direction or whatever.
That's that's all I'm trying to see
right now. Uh all these uh claims and
counter claims there it's very hard to
prove or disprove them. So yeah I I
don't know what the truth is.
B okayisha good evening ma'am. Abisha
says, "Is the straight open for us or
not?" The straight should open. The
straight uh I think the Iranians are
allowing ships to pass through if they
are destined for a certain number of
nations. Definitely India and China.
They're not allowing American ships or
Israeli ships to pass through or ships
that whose destination is the US or
Israel. They're not allowing those ships
to pass through. So for us the straight
is open. The Indian Navy is operating in
the region as as a guardian of Indian
ships. Okay. Not as a combatant and the
straight is open for us. But the issue
is this. Okay. The straight is open for
us. We are getting oil. Good. What about
gas? When it comes to gas,
Qatar's gas production facilities have
been damaged. um
and uh it is difficult for them to send
gas to India a lot of India's gas comes
from Qatar and if that gas production is
impacted then that's going to even if
the state of Hormos is open for us it's
not going to ensure that gas reaches
India so that's a bigger problem right
so LNG LPG is a problem for India oil we
will somehow or the other get the oil
that we need but gas is a problem now
how do we replace uh the gas that was
coming from Qatar. You could ask Russia
to send it but Russia also may be facing
problems. The Ukrainians are destroying
are trying to destroy their their ports
from which oil and gas is sent to other
countries. Uh and the Houthis could
close the state of Babel Mande based on
how depending on how things go. So these
are the challenges India is facing. It's
more about gas right now that is more
acute. That's where the situation is
more acute compared to the situation
concerning petroleum. Okay. uh the
straight should open well the straight
should open the world should not have
war all that we can keep saying but
see it is in Iran's interest to keep the
straight closed for certain nations and
that they will do
okayana
says Pete Hexath displays peak
Judeo-Christian values I suppose he does
yes so um
the the Trump administration likes to
say that the US was founded on Jud
Judeo-Christian values.
See, historically, the Americans have
been a Christian nation. Christians, how
did the Judeo tag get added to to
Christian? I'm not sure about that. But
anyhow, U Pete Hex does display peak
Judeo-Christian values. I suppose so
does Trump.
Okay. WBKT says there is some AI in
YouTube that doesn't allow to send
certain super chats, especially
something regarding the great freedom
and democracy loving nation of America.
Well, okay. I'm I would not be surprised
if this is the case because this is an
American platform that we are using and
that's why they will, you know, look out
for their interests and there are
certain things that you will not be
allowed to say. See, freedom, democracy,
freedom of expression, these are all
theoretical concepts. they don't
actually
uh apply in the real world. Okay,
censorship is a real thing. So, you're
going to have that. You're going to have
that. It is unfortunate or whatever, but
it is what it is. It's a fact.
Praradana says future of war is
underground military and air bases. Very
much so. Very much so. Yeah. Iran is
showing the way. Iran is showing the way
to the whole world how you can fight a
war against a much more powerful
opponent.
Make it impossible for them to destroy
your capabilities by taking your
capabilities deep underground where the
bunker busters and so on can't do a
thing.
Um
so yes and if you see the Chinese
uh approach to their force posture north
of the India Tibet border, you will see
the Chinese have also in the past few
years been digging deep tunnels in which
they are keeping their weapons and maybe
maybe even personnel.
So one of the issues that China faces in
the India Tibet border region is that
China is I mean there's no vegetation
there. The Chinese positions are are
very badly exposed. Let's take a look.
Excuse me.
If you look here, okay,
um let's go.
So you understand that oxychain is
currently under Chinese occupation.
Okay. Um
now where is that lake? That great lake.
Yeah, here it is. This is the Pangong
Lake.
Now, um where is uh Chushul Chushul?
Okay, so if you come here and if you
look at the satellite imagery,
I'm just giving you an an area that I'm
familiar with. There are lots of other
areas like this. As you can see, it's
snowy here. If you go from Chushul back
to u back to whichever place you will
find that there are Chinese possessions
that you can see
chushul towards let's say
no no no
okay here.
So if you travel from here, you will
definitely find Chinese possessions that
are very exposed.
Where is it? Where is it?
Chushul War Memorial. Okay.
And
Okay. So maybe not there. I'm not able
to locate the place very quickly. Okay.
Okay, let's say Mira.
Okay, here we should be able to see
Chinese positions in this area. Maybe
here man.
If you look here, you should be able to
see something
opposite man. Do you have Chinese
positions or do you have Indian
positions? The other side of the lake is
occupied at least some parts of the lake
opposite side are occupied by the
Chinese.
Um,
it's been a while since I looked here.
My point is, if you look at the terrain
here, there is no vegetation here. It's
pretty badly exposed.
And um, that's why the Chinese have been
digging tunnels and they've been, you
know, employing the essentially the
Iranian strategy. Okay. They've been
employing very much the Iranian strategy
to uh to safeguard their positions and
their assets north of uh north of the
India Tibet border in Chinese occupied
Tibet. So the Chinese are already doing
this
and I think it's something that every
sovereign nation should look into.
So there are lots of lessons to be
learned from the India from the from the
war that Iran is is is being made to
fought. One thing is that a lot of your
assets need to be stored underground
where nobody can destroy them no matter
what happens. Secondly, you have to
stockpile very large quantities of
drones and very large quantities of
missiles in order to be able to outlast
any any invading force.
You see in 1498 Wasco Dagama that
Portuguese creep he came to India and he
bombarded Kalikut
from his ships because he had the
ammunition and the and the weapons and
uh you know imagine if we had 10 times
the amount of ammunition or 100 times
the amount of ammunition he had and we
were able to destroy his ships and then
then history would have been different.
So the point is you need to have you
need to have in case someone comes
invading you need to have way more
ammunition and much larger stockpiles of
everything than than them. So yeah these
are the lessons that India needs to
learn and other nations also possibly
needs to learn from the war that we are
seeing right now.
Ran Hapana says why was there sudden
change in US stocks just before 911? I
have no idea. I don't know. No idea.
Was there actually a ch change? And
let's say there was then who did it?
See, I don't know about that. I have no
idea.
24 BAT says when Trump was elected, you
said he may be good for the US, but he's
neither neither good for the US empire,
elites, deep state, nor is he good from
the common US male men or the world. So
that means I was wrong. Let me tell you
something. Let's say this war goes on
6 months, one year, okay? and the US
let's say it loses this war then you
will say that you know the the this guy
Trump has been bad for the US and he's
bad for the world or is it so or is it
so
of course he's been bad for the world
let's say this war goes on another 6 to
12 months it's going to be terrible for
the world economy
and so Trump will have been bad for the
world but he also loses the war and Iran
is not defeated then you will say he's
even bad for the US. But is he really
bad for the US? Let's say this war leads
to the complete
secession of the export of oil through
hormones and babble mandib.
Okay. Let's say the war escalates
and the Americans start striking at
Iran's um oil production facilities,
power power generation facilities,
desalination plants and the Iranian hit
back at the oil production facilities
and desalination plants and power
generation plants of all the GCC
nations. Then the whole region is
devastated and it can't produce oil for
the next 10 years, let's say, or gas oil
and gas for next 10 years. Then it's a
disaster for the for the region. It's a
disaster for the whole world.
But is it a disaster for the US? Even if
the US loses this war,
this entire region goes out of
commission. You can't get oil from there
for a decade.
Then who benefits from this? The US
benefits from this.
The US becomes the world's largest
supplier of oil to the whole world. Then
okay. So shortterm there's going to be
pain for the US and the world. Longterm
there's going to be pain for the world.
But it's going to be good for the US.
Maybe that's the plan. Maybe the plan is
that whichever region we can't control,
we will destroy it.
So now if we can't control the Gulf
region, we're going to devastate the
Gulf region, send the whole region into
the stone age. And that will also be
terrible for China and India. So we are
not only destroying the Gulf region and
Iran, we're also
giving a huge setback to India and
China. A long-term setback.
And by closing the straight of Babal
month, it will ensure Russia also finds
it very difficult to send to sell oil to
India and China. So which means that
everybody is now under our control
and that is also great for their policy
of containing India and and uh hampering
China's you know endeavors of whatever
they're doing.
You see Trump even if he loses this war
may actually end up doing something
that's great for the US. All right. So,
think of it, think about it from
different perspectives. All right.
Abishek Bardaj says, "Namaste. Longtime
viewer. Haven't been too active
recently." Well, thank you so much and
welcome back. So, have purchased both
your courses. Any plans for updates in
your courses in the pipeline or any new
course planned? Thank you, sir. Um, I
don't have any any plans as such right
now uh for updates uh in the courses or
uh new courses in the pipeline. I am
right now focusing on writing.
So that's what I'm focusing on. So as
far the courses are concerned, the way
they are right now, they're going to
stay like that for for the time being at
least. All right.
Right. Thank you so much. And uh thank
you so much for purchasing the courses
and being a longtime viewer. I really
appreciate that. Thank you.
JRXna says how does PFBR's success
kalpakam break the U3235 trap and IA
oversight to unlock India's thorium
based autonomy by 47 also ario physicist
from where how do I become one too uh
pressurized fast breeder reactor success
kalpakam I am not aware I'm not keeping
track of what's happening in kalpakam
see overall India has a three-stage
uh nuclear program
India seeks to become have a major
producer of electricity from
nuclear reactors and we have a
three-stage program. The last stage is
producing
electricity from thorium based reactors.
Um so I am not sure what kind of reactor
kalpa is and what it does. What is the
physics behind it? I'm not sure about
that. So I won't be able to answer the
question without looking into what the
kalpakam reactor actually is and what it
does and what sort of fuel it uses.
Uh is it a
pressurized? So it's a fast breeder. So
its job is to produce plutonium or
something I suppose. Um not sure. So I I
don't know. I don't I'm not aware of
this. So I'll not look into it right now
because it'll take some time to dig all
the information out. And um right I
don't I don't know about the IEA
oversight also.
Are we under any obligation to have IA
inspect our facilities? Really?
I don't know about that. So am I a
physicist? He's a physicist. Yes, I am a
physicist. From where? From India. How
do you become one? Well, you have to
study physics to become one. And you
well, I suppose you also have to get
some educational degrees to be a
physicist. If if you want people to
recognize you as a physicist, you would
need a master's degree at least to to to
be a physicist, right? How do you become
one? You study progressively. You need
to be a physicist, you need to be really
good at math. So math is the language in
which you do physics without a very
strong foundational understanding of
mathematics. Uh you can't be a
physicist. You need to be really good at
ma mathematics. Uh so you start from
your basic school level arithmetic and
all that. Then you go higher. You learn
you know calculus and things like that
and eventually you need to have
university level understanding of
mathematics. What are the mathematical
tools you need to do physics? Well, you
need calculus, you need differential
equations, you need uh linear algebra,
you need matrices, you need tensors,
uh you need uh
you need uh need to know how to handle
complex numbers and and uh um
all of that I suppose. Is there
something else mathematically? Yeah,
most of it you know you take any
standard uh mathematical methods of
physics mathematical methods for
physicists book you go through that
Byron filler or whatever then that works
for you and then that's that's good
enough for you and then you need to
learn the physics so you need to learn
physics from the helidnic level uh
that's where you start then you go
through you know you need to be good at
classical physics which is Newtonian
physics and classical electronamics all
of that then uh you need to venture into
quantum mechanics
um and relativity and then you to decide
what field you want to be in whether it
is a purely theoretical field or an
applied field and so on. So it's a long
process. It's it takes years of effort
to become a physicist. You have to
absorb a lot of knowledge, a lot of
information and at the end of the day
being a physicist means you are solving
some problem. So you don't learn how to
solve problems too. solving actual open
problems in physics, right? Otherwise,
you're an engineer. If you're doing
applied physics, you're not really
solving an open problem, but you're
doing you're applying physics into some
real world problem. But there are very
big open unanswered questions in physics
and well, if you are especially
theoretical physics or astrophysics,
cosmology, you'll be typically tackling
some of these. All right, sir. All the
best.
24. Bat says, "How is Iran Pakistan ties
on paper words rhetoric versus truth?
Isn't it funny that Iran India are kind
of on the same axis and Israel Pakistan
are on the same side despite the
rhetoric?"
Yeah. So what's the truth about the
relationship between Israel and
Pakistan? Well, we don't know because
these things aren't like spoken about in
in the open. These are kept under wraps.
But understand the connections.
Understand the the the the
undeniable connections. What is the
undeniable connection between Israel and
Pakistan? Pakistan. Let's start with
Israel. Israel's number one ally is the
United States. The US gives
unconditional support to Israel no
matter what happens.
And Israel essentially, it's now known
to be true, it was Israel that dragged
the US into this war against Iran.
So Israel kind of is, you could say,
the dominant partner in the USIsrael
relationship.
Okay. So Israel's number one asset is
the US. Israel's number one
unconditional supporter is the US. Now
let's understand the USPakistan
relationship. Pakistan is a
long-standing American vasal.
Between 2012 to 2022, Pakistan became a
Chinese vasal temporarily. Now it is
back to being an American vasal.
And it's a very important asset for the
US to have because it allows the US to
counterbalance
and hurt India on demand.
Okay.
And also Iran possibly if required and
also Afghanistan. The whole region
Pakistan is a major is the world's
largest terrorist nation. Right. So
that's a deal. So Pakistan is a major
asset of the US and if the US seems to
be the a major asset of Israel. So that
means Israel can use Pakistan too in
some way or the other and maybe there
are connections between the two nations
possibly hypothetically potentially.
One
clear sign of this is that
recently when uh the Pakistani dictator
Aim Munir had visited the US when he uh
was there the Pakistani embassy or
consulate there had arranged a dinner in
his honor and there was an Israeli
military presence there.
Let's let's ask Google. Does it uh does
it uh maybe it will say I'm wrong, but
let's see. Let's ask Google.
Was there an Israeli military presence
at a dinner given by the Pakistani
embassy in honor of Aim in the US?
Let's see. Ah, it says there is no
evidence.
False parade rumors. Everything is
false. N no no no
no no. Okay. Okay. They are saying there
was no such thing happened.
They are saying no such thing. This AI
is saying there is no cred credible
evidence.
Okay.
Anyhow, so so the AI won't won't accept
this but this did happen. uh and
Pakistan is going to be playing some
kind of so-called peacekeeping role in
Gaza once the Trump towers start coming
up in Gaza after the flattening in of
Gaza and the evacuation and the
expulsion of its population. So in
during the process Pakistan Pakistani
troops will play a peacekeeping role who
will they be helping Israel. So there
clearly is some kind of connection
between Israel and Pakistan but it is a
it is a secret connection. It's not uh
out in the open.
Okay. So that's what I can say and yeah
it's funny that India and Israel well
India and Israel are not officially on
the same axis. It is Israel, China,
Russia and North Korea that are part of
the so-called axis. When the when the
west uses the term axis they mean that
these are bad guys and when you have
allies it means when you have a
coalition of western nations they are
called allies. And when you've got a
coalition of bad evil nations, they're
called the axis. So India is not part of
that alliance or that grouping of nation
nations officially. U mainly because of
the problem that China poses for India.
Otherwise, India isn't isn't has a good
relationship with all the nations. Um
but yes, you could say that that India
and Iran are both nations towards which
the US is hostile in different ways.
When it comes to Iran, the US is bombing
Iran and trying to destroy it. When it
comes to India, the US is trying to
control India, contain India and prevent
India from growing and trying to do all
kinds of stuff, you know, in India's
periphery. The civil war in Myanmar. Do
you people understand there's a civil
war going on in Burma, right next to
India, in just east of India along
India's border? We are worried about the
war in Iran but there's a war going on
in Burma and we are not even aware of
it. So that's also all all done by the
US. You know it's a civil war they've
caused in the region
right
okay 24 says why are experts who rant 24
by7 about Pakistan and China they why
are the silent on the northeast? I
wonder
see there are reasons for this. Indian
experts have no understanding of India's
far east. The Indian government for
decades have has had no understanding of
the far east of India's northeast. What
kind of people live there?
What are their traditions like? What
language do they speak? What is their
culture like? What kind of food do they
eat?
for the government of India. It's all
alien.
There are some so-called experts, okay,
who who are appointed from time to time
as northeast experts and they give the
government advice about what to do in
the northeast, what policies to have.
Then after a few years, they disappear
and you never hear from them again
because they've messed everything up.
There are some experts like that. But
most experts, geopolitics experts and
other experts
they they who speak about China and they
know everything about everything about
China. The Chinese president had the
seven strokes in the last 6 months. They
know everything allegedly that sort of
thing. They know everything that's
happening in China also. But they quite
about the northeast
because they understand nothing about
the northeast. That's the reason why
nowadays there are people who are also
talking about northeast because you will
ask chat GPD something chat GPD will
tell you everything and then you can say
yes hey
so that's a shortcut a lot of people
take these days chat GPD shortcut
yeah but you see it's very important for
India to not ensure that the people who
live in this region the far east of
India don't get alienated
it's very important we have the slogan
of national integration But we don't.
It's just a slogan. Do we actually
implement it is the question. Okay. WBKT
says, "Will you ever visit Tua? It's a
stunning. It has a stunning landscape."
Ah, I would love to visit Tua. Love to
visit it. Uh, suppose it's got
volcanoes. Do we have volcanoes in Tua?
I'm sure there's volcanism there.
Does Tuva have volcanoes?
Pretty sure it does. Yes, the Tuva
Republic. It does have volcanoes. Um
yes
right so in case some of you are
wondering where is tua it's in Russia of
course right in Siberia cir and let's
take a look at tua
tuva Russia
say that's where we have it okay this
whole region is stunning ly beautiful,
very sparsely populated. Okay.
Um and Tua I would say historically
historically tua has been part of
Mongolia. Okay. So Mongolia is is a very
unfortunate nation these days about half
of Mongolia.
I mean
if you see Mongolia today the size of
Mongolia that much area is currently
almost that much area is under Chinese
occupation right right now and the
Chinese call it inner Mongolia let's
let's uh search for inner Mongolia
Mongolia China
so it won't show you an outline but yeah
uh but the fact about Mongolia is that
even north of Mongolia there's a large
territory that is now part of Russia
which was historically Mongolia and the
Tua is part of that. Okay.
So I would love to visit Tua. I would
love to visit Kamchatka. I would I would
love to visit Sakalin. Right. This is
Sakalin. Lots of volcanoes here.
Kamchatka. Lots of volcanoes here as
well. Uh these islands are you're not
allowed to visit the Kurill Islands. You
got volcanoes there as well. So very
nice, beautiful,
you know, parts of the world that very
few people visit. I would I would
certainly love to visit u these parts of
the world for sure. Absolutely.
Push Shukla says, "Namaste ab big fan. I
prefer good health and ending." Thank
you very much. Thank you very much, PG.
In your last live stream, you said only
six sovereign nations.
Um,
what is US? US, China, Russia, Israel,
Iran, India. What about BR
CPI?
Brazil? No. Indonesia? No. What is CP?
I'm not sure what CP is. No, only six.
So when I say only six, it means only
six are there, right? Others are not
there. Brazil, how can you say it's a
sovereign nation? They come under the
new the new Monro doctrine, right? the
new American Mandro doctrine.
Trump has said that the the US is going
to be the the hedgemonic power in the
western hemisphere which includes all
the Americas. That's been the case even
without the doctrine being officially
u you know reestablished.
No nation in the western hemisphere is
genuinely sovereign. They are all under
the American thumb. Understand that.
Indonesia beautiful country. I love the
country. Wonderful place. Wonderful
people. great history but they are also
dominated by the US
and I don't know what CP is but yeah
right okay so there's only six genuinely
sovereign nations okay
wbkt says your opinion about Kim Jong
Lucashenko meet have they met I'm not
aware but if they met good for them
um
let's see let's see when did their meet
last
Lucashenko, Kim Jong-un,
Belerus leader, gift. This was in March,
friendship treaty. Okay, so good for
them. They are all on the same side,
right? Same grouping of nations. Belarus
is a very strong partner of Russia and
similarly North Korea is a very strong
partner of China and China and Russia
are in this mood this vivendi right now.
They are working together because they
have no choice. So it makes sense for
these nations to cooperate and
collaborate. So yeah.
24. Barat says, "If the US attacks North
Korea, what is Kim's response? Will it
tolerate aggression or be restrained,
measured, rational like Iran? If the
Iran had nukes, would the US have
invaded?
If the US attacks North Korea, what will
Kim Jong-un Kim Jong-un do?" No, that's
not the right question. The right
question is, will the US attack North
Korea? The answer is the US won't attack
North Korea. Why will they not attack
North Korea? Because North Korea has
nukes first of all and secondly the
North Koreans have ICBMs that are tried
and tested.
These North Korean ICBMs can reach any
part of the US. ICBM means
intercontinental ballistic missile.
North Korean missiles can reach the US
East Coast.
Okay. And you it's it's impossible to
defend an entire nation against ICBMs.
Some cities will be defended better than
other parts of the nation. But let's say
if a North Korean ICBM goes towards
Hawaii, there's nothing the US can do to
save Hawaii. If a North Korean IC ICBM
is is targeted at a certain US city,
most likely most likely the US can't do
a thing about it. So the US will never
try to attack North Korea
because the North Koreans will
hit back very hard and the North Koreans
will not hesitate at least they've tried
to make it look like they will not
hesitate from using nuclear weapons. So
North Korea will not be attacked by the
US. The Americans won't do it. And if
the Americans attack, the North Koreans
will make them pay a very heavy price
for that. They will not tolerate the
aggression. They will not be restrained
or measured or rational like like Iran.
Now if Iran had nukes, would the US have
invaded? No, they would not have invaded
in attacked. They have not invaded yet
land invasion, but they have attacked
North Korea. Sorry, Iran. They want they
would not have attacked Iran if Iran had
a few nukes.
So all Iran had to do was to test at
least one nuke, one nuclear test
minimum. If you do that, the whole
equation changes. So I think it was a
major mistake by Iran to not test
nuclear weapons.
Yeah.
Right. Okay.
Fraud Hulk says, "Good evening. Uh
what's your view about Israel Russian
relationship? In the past, Putin said a
large population of Israel is are of
Russian origin and striking them is
immoral. It's a diplomatic statement
that was made.
Okay. In diplomacy, you say nice things.
Please learn to ignore words and look at
actions.
Okay? So Putin said something nice about
Israel.
We will never attack you. So many of
your people are of Russian knowledge and
how can we attack you? It is immoral to
attack Israel.
Okay. So that's what he has said. It
doesn't mean a thing. It is not a
treaty. It's not an uh it's not a signed
agreement. It's just a few words. So I I
don't take words seriously. Now what's
my view about the Israel Russian
relationship
and
they're not friends. They're not they're
not on the same side. Israel has
initiated the war against Iran which is
one of Russia's major friends so to say
in geopolitics there's no friends or
enemies but
as a in a manner of taking their friends
Russia and Iran I mean Iran has sold
Russia a large number of shahed drones
and Russia uh is in the process of
selling Iran fighter planes of various
kinds and so on not various kinds one
kind Suko is something Suko 35 is it
possibly
Uh so yeah, so Iran and Russia are on
the same side and Israel is the sworn
enemy of Iran and they're currently
trying to destroy Iran. So the Russia
Israel relationship isn't the best
relationship. It's it's not the best
relationship, right? It's they're not
really very friendly.
Um yeah, that's how I see it.
Abai Singh says India is making an LICBM
missile. We are still inde undefeated in
making files and starting projects. I
hope it goes beyond a file this time and
in quick time. I hope so too. I hope
that it goes beyond um a slogan and an
announcement and file and so on. Uh so
India we have good missiles. We have we
have one of the best missile programs in
the world.
Um we tested a few of those during the
three-day oper operation zindur or
three-day war against Pakistan. Few of
the missiles were tested not the
ballistic missiles.
Um and now we are talking about a long
range ICBM which is I think necessary
for India to have.
So what's a long range ICBM? So
we have the AGNY 5 missile. The stated
range of Agni 5 is what? 5,000 6,000
8,000 km. Let me see what it is. Um what
is the stated range of the AGNY 5
missile?
The stated official range is over 5,000
km. Okay. Um so we have tested it around
5,000 km that sort of range but maybe u
the actual range may be more maybe 8,000
km
but 8,000 km isn't enough for India to
to have the entire world under
within our range right it's important
for us to have missiles that can strike
anywhere in the world if required it's
very important for us to have that right
why should we not have such capabilities
when other nations have it so now we are
making an longer range ICBM uh
intercontinental ballistic missile. So
maybe this time it will have a range of
15,000 km let's say I don't think that
should be too difficult for us to
achieve
right. So yeah I hope it happens soon
and I hope we induct a large number of
such missiles.
Ash ash visi ashwony says fuel tankers
move at just 10 to 15 knots. Ships that
departed before the war are still on
rout but new shipments will take much
longer. How will countries man how will
countries manage deal delayed fuel
supplies and shortages. They will have
to manage these shortages and delays as
best they can. Maybe rationing
rationing is something nations typically
do when they face such problems. You
know, you you you impose quotas and you
ration the fuel. Don't allow people to
buy as much fuel as they want. Don't
allow establishments to buy as much food
as they want. Give everybody a certain
quot you can buy only this much in in a
week or a month or whatever. That's what
countries can do. That's the best you
can do. See these problems that have
occurred because of the war, they are
beyond your control. Right? If you're
India, if you're China, if you're Japan,
if you're Indonesia, if you're Malaysia,
if you're Singapore, if you're Thailand
and so on, it's beyond your control.
There's nothing you can do about it. So,
the best you can do is to manage things
back home. Impose rationing, impose fuel
austerity measures, tell people to work
from home, tell restaurants to to
operate at half capacity or whatever or
or operate operate for only half the
hours you were generally operating
earlier. Impose such measures. use do
some such measures which will be bad for
the economy but there's nothing we can
do about it because the problem is the
root cause is outside and we can't
control that. So that's why this is bad
for for the global economy. It's bad for
the economy of various nations. More
businesses could go out could go out of
you know operation
just like with COVID if the longer this
lasts. So that's how we do it.
Okay. Time space theory says sage Canada
definition of atom and molecule 500
years before Democrus. This definition
is the same as Kasha but AI search
ignores it unless specified.
Okay. So, uh, Canada, Canada was an
Indian rishi. I don't know when he
lived. Was it 500 years before Democrats
or 5,000 years before him? I have no
idea. Uh, our timelines are all messed
up. Okay? And if your te textbook
teaches you that so and so person lived
in so- and so year, there is no
guarantee it's the truth. We have
defined our timelines based on western
concepts
and on on the basis of timelines the
westerners have given to us. So I don't
know that Canada lived 500 years before
democratus. Maybe it was much longer
before I don't know. Uh now when it
comes to uh definition of atoms and
molecules I don't think he spoke about
molecules. He spoke about atoms. He said
that if you take any substance any any
matter and you keep dividing it cutting
into half half half then eventually you
will reach a stage where you where you
when there is a small
um piece of matter that can't be divided
further and that is the anu the atom. So
he spoke about atoms I am not aware of
him speaking about molecules. molecules
are combinations of atoms, right? Like
H2O, NAC,
CH3 CO, K4, FCN6 and so on and so forth.
These are combinations of atoms based on
um the number of electrons you have in
the various shells and so on. Uh so
yeah, so I don't think Canada spoke
about molecules or wrote about
molecules. I know that he was the first
person to give an atomic theory, not a
quantum theory, but an atomic theory.
Um and I'm not sure about what Rishi
Kashab said but uh yeah uh AI search
will ignore India's contributions. See
first of all what Karnata said was
philosophical not scientific
because according to the scientific
method you need observational evidence
and Canada was simply speculating but
his speculation was correct. So
his was a philosophical school of
thought. All the Indian philosophical
schools of thought are essentially
different models of the universe
and his was possibly a more accurate
model of the universe compared to
certain others of that of from our past
history. But AI searches will ignore
most Indian contributions to philosophy
to science etc. Unless you ask it to
speak about the specific thing in that
case it will tell you what it knows but
otherwise it will most likely ignore it.
And that's why India needs to have
sovereign AI systems, our own AI
systems, right? Which are not trained on
western knowledge but Indian knowledge.
You should have AIS that are trained
only on Indian literature and knowledge.
So it would be nice if if the government
of India could do something to that.
Sergeant Skylin says what will be US's
next move? Most likely there's going to
be an escalation on Tuesday. Trump has
given Iran 48 hours to open the trade of
foremost. Iran's not going to do that
unless there is a major breakthrough
with negotiations. I don't think they
are even talking to each other. So how
can there be negotiations? So Iran is
not going to open the state of foremost
because Trump needs it open. So Tuesday
I think the Americans will launch major
strikes on Iran and it looks like the
Americans are preparing for some kind of
uh ground operation on Iran which could
happen sooner rather than later. So I
see escalations coming in this coming
week, right? The title of this uh live
stream is Iran, USI Israel, Iran war.
What's next, right? What next? Most
likely an escalation early in this
coming week in the next 48 hours. Most
likely at the end of 24 hours, you'll
have a major escalation coming from the
US. And I mean, you can see that that
Trump has been threatening this for a
while. So if you see this infamous
social media post of his, it's already
infamous even though it's just 3 hours 3
hours old, right? Trump is promising
this Tuesday will be power plant day and
bridge day all wrapped up in one in
Iran. So he's saying we will destroy
more bridges and more power plants in
one day on Tuesday. There will be
nothing like it. Open the FN straight,
you crazy bastards, Iranians, or you'll
be living in hell. Just watch. Praise be
to Allah. I don't know why he said that,
but whatever. So, Trump was saying that
this entire operation was about
liberating the people of Iran
and bringing them freedom and democracy
and human rights and and saving them
from the evil government of Iran. Right?
All about saving the people. Is this how
you save people? By targeting
civilian infrastructure, power plants,
bridges that people use, civilians use.
Is that how you do it? Is that how you
bring freedom and democracy to the
people? Or maybe that's how the US does
it.
So I think you're going to have an
escalation in the coming days very soon
unfortunately.
24 Bat says Cuba, Vietnam, El Salvador,
Nicar Nicaragua, Nicaragua so sovereign.
If not, why?
When you are a small nation, you have
constraints that prevent you from being
sovereign.
You have major constraints. No small
nation with a small economy can be
considered to be genuinely sovereign
because you are critically dependent on
so many other countries for so many
things
and if you are small let's say we talk
about Switzerland small nation small how
can a small nation be sovereign
if it is
independent
I'm talking about independence it's not
sovereignty
if it's independent it's because its
neighbors have decided not to not to
invade.
But the moment one of the neighbors gets
a crazy crackpot leader and who decides
to invade it's over, right?
And if you are a small nation, then you
are depend then you then you lack things
within your small territory. You lack
resources
which you will have to import from other
countries. So you're dependent on other
other countries from a technological
perspective, from a fuel perspective,
from an energy perspective in so many
different ways. So how can you be
considered to be sovereign? Right? So
Cuba right now,
Cuba is critically dependent on nations
like Russia
and Venezuela, etc. it was for oil and
now the Americans have embargoed Cuba
and Cuba is is being crippled by the
Americans.
Um, and Cuba doesn't have a million
missiles or drones. So, let's see how
long they last. Vietnam,
it's it's again a quasi sovereign
nation, but not fully sovereign. Well,
so all these nations, the same story.
Yeah. Hors Patel says, "I've been
experimenting the past four days with a
retrieval system based on your podcast
archive to make long- form discussions
searchable using 16k Q&A from 334
episodes. Surprisingly useful."
Very interesting. Andre Karpathi came up
with this uh system. He tweeted about
that. He tweeted about the concept that
you can use.
You can have an inbox in which you can
dump all kinds of files. You can dump
transcripts. You can dump PDFs. You can
dump dump uh images anything and you can
have an AI system parse through all of
that and create your own wiki in terms
of markdown files MD files and you can
then access the wiki using obsidian or
something and each time you ask ask the
the system a question if the answer is
useful it's going to go back into the
inbox and it's going to be processed and
it's going to become part of the wiki.
So the wiki becomes an evolving system
that you never touch. The AI maintains
it but you get insights from it.
Obviously there are there are questions
about how accurate it's going to be
because it will depend on the accuracy
of the AI system itself. It's a really
interesting concept if if you have a
self-healing wiki. If you can have a
process that runs periodically that that
looks at the Viki's accuracy that it
could be really interesting but yeah you
somebody will have to construct it. So I
suppose everybody can have their own
knowledge base based on that right. Um
it's interesting. So you have been uh
experimenting the past 4 days with a
retrieval system built on my podcast
archive to make long- form discussion
searchable. 16,000 Q&As's from 341
episodes. Okay. Well 341 episodes. So
you've downloaded all the transcripts I
suppose. Right. Surprisingly useful.
When asked when you asked the system
about what it thought about the idea, it
surfaced a segment suggesting you had
mentioned something similar in episode
211 which I haven't watched yet.
Interesting. Very interesting. So I'm
pretty sure he was using some form of AI
for this, right? I suppose GPD claude
whatever Gemini.
Very interesting. Maybe I should do this
for myself, you know.
Yeah, something similar so that I
understand myself better. my my own
thought processes
etc. Very interesting and I'm I'm glad
that you're doing this. Thank you so
much for sharing this with me. Very
interesting. Maybe I should implement
something similar. Yeah, have some AI
vibe code something or maybe I could
code it myself which will obviously take
longer but yeah interesting.
Awesome. Awesome. Thank you so much for
sharing this. It's very interesting.
Parth Ma says, "Do you see Dubai
salination desalination plants getting
hit in case US Israel hit Iran bridges
and power plants?" I think the Iranians
are being very reciprocal. So if the
Americans and Israelis will hit bridges,
more bridges, then Iran could hit
bridges in the GCC countries. If the
Americans and Israelis hit power plants,
the Iranians could hit power plants in
the region. If they hit oil refineries,
they will hit hit oil refineries. If the
Americans and Israelis hit uh oil
storage facilities, the Iranians will
hit oil storage facilities. And if they
hit desalination plants in Iran, then
Iran will hit descent plants. Iran has
been very reciprocal these 35, 36, 37
days. So I think you will see more of
that pattern. But uh the Americans and
Israelis have hit Iranian nuclear
facilities and Iran hasn't responded to
that yet by targeting Israeli nuclear
facilities. I think they are saving that
for later perhaps. Yeah. So I see Dubai
deselination plants or other
deselination plants being hit only if
the Americans and Israelis target
Iranian desalination plans. That's what
I expect.
Pushina says, "What's stopping the US
from displaying their real potential?"
The US is displaying its real potential.
Okay, why do I say this? It's because
the Americans have a certain number of
military bases in the Gulf region and
their potential depends on how much
military force they can deploy there.
and they deployed a certain amount of
military force there and started the war
and that military potential has been
destroyed to a certain extent at least
by Iran. Now they are bringing in more
transport aircraft in the region,
bringing in more personnel, more weapons
perhaps and that will define the new
regional potential of the US. So it's
not about the global potential, it's
about the regional potential. How much
force can they deploy in a certain
region? That is the regional potential,
right?
Uh so yeah that's what the US the US is
constrained by how much force it can
deploy in that region now they're
they're bringing in more eventually they
have other weapons that uh that also are
part part of their potential which we
hope they will never use but who knows
we'll see one hope it doesn't come to
that push says thank you sir for making
uh for allowing memberships you're very
welcome of course you're very welcome
uh podcast Punjabi podcast to Punjabi
says all Europeans countries have
bunkers why don't we have bunkers
um I suppose we have to ask the
government of India why haven't they
thought about bunkers
all European countries have bunkers well
do they have bunkers that can u
accommodate their entire populations I
would be very surprised if that is the
case because the European countries
haven't seen war for 70 80 years now
right the last major war in Europe
Because if you disregard the Yugoslavia
conflict, the crossover war, all that,
then the last major conflict before
Ukraine
in Europe was 1945,
right? After 45, there's not been any
major war until 2022 in Europe. Um, so
I'm not sure if all European countries
will have sufficient bunkers to uh
accommodate their entire populations.
They will have bunkers possibly left
over from from the cold war.
But uh it's it's very hard to make so
many bunkers, right? What's the
population of the UK? 70 80 million.
What is it? Let's see. UK's population.
How many bunkers does the US have? UK
have
the UK's population and how many bunkers
does the UK have?
70 million. 270 major nuclear bunkers
and thousands of smaller mostly closed
historical bunkers. Okay.
Yes. So most of those are closed the
historical bunkers. They could be
reactivated but it will take some time
you know to make them habitable and so
on. Um India doesn't have bunkers
because we have 1.4 billion people first
of all and we don't foresee too much of
a nuclear threat and you can't do much
about it I suppose.
Okay. Ashai Pande says um good evening.
My parents in Abu Dhabi have returned to
India during the Iran US conflict but
must go back for work.
Is it safe at the moment or they better
stay? What with respect to possibility
of escalation?
Um, look, I think there's going to be
escalation,
but I don't think that the escalation is
going to involve Iran hitting civilians.
Iran,
see, Iran doesn't do that. Why do I say
Iran doesn't do that? Because the
Americans have been bombing civilians
the past month. Iran has not hit
civilians. Iran has hit a few hotels
in the UAE
with drones but they have hit hotels
where the Americans were stationing
military personnel and they have hit
those floors and those rooms.
Uh so there have been very few very few
civilian casualties in the Gulf region
very few. I know people who live in the
UAE.
They're there. Um,
and see the US in the initial days of
the war, they sent a tomahawk missile
into a girls school in Iran, right? They
it killed more than 170 or so girls in
Iran, little girls. Did Iran respond in
the same manner? Iran did not respond in
the same manner. They did not target
civilians or children, right?
So I certainly foresee an escalation in
this coming week. The Americans will
once again hit Iran hard and hit Iran
harder. Bridges like like Trump is Trump
is promising, right? Bridges and power
plants and much more. It's going to be
hell in Iran. That's what he is saying.
And if that happens, Iran will
hit American Israeli assets and perhaps
GCC assets,
but those won't be civilian assets. So I
certainly see a see a see the
possibility significant possibility of
an escalation in the coming week in the
coming longer possibly but I don't see
civilians being targeted by Iran.
They're not crazy people. Okay they're
not mad like they being portrayed. Uh so
that is how I see things going.
So if your parents have to return to the
UAE to to Abu Dhabi for work,
I don't think it's going to be dangerous
for them. I don't think so. I'm sure the
airports Dubai, Abu Dhabi, etc. are
operating. Dubai, look, I don't know
what Dubai airport looks like right now,
but I'm sure it's operational.
Abu Dhabi definitely we've heard no news
of any any underward thing happening.
Maybe one or two incidents,
but nothing major. I think it should be
safe for them. But at the end of the
day, please do your own due diligence
because since your parents live there,
they know the the region better, they
know the place better. And if they feel
that what I am saying is incorrect and
maybe there's a higher chance of
something bad happening, then they
should make their own decisions based on
their their own understanding. The way I
see it, there's going to be escalation,
but hopefully it doesn't
affect civilians in the UAE. That's how
I see it. So, I'm hopeful and I'm pretty
sure it won't uh affect civilians. The
the Iranians won't deliberately target
civilians,
but it's a war zone, so you have to be
careful. Okay? So, yeah, that's what I
can say. But you see, understand one
thing about me. I'm not sitting in the
region. I am s I'm talking about these
things theoretically. I don't have skin
in the game. Keep that in in in your
mind when when you when you analyze what
I'm saying. Okay. I'm I don't have skin
in the game. And when you take advice
from somebody who doesn't have skin in
the game, you have to be very careful.
Okay. All the best. All the best to you
and your parents.
Pushina says just like Iran showed its
real capabilities in this war as a
surprise to the US. Do you think the US
would get the same surprise in North
Korea and China?
I think China has far more drones and
missiles than Iran. Far more drones and
missiles.
The Chinese have been churning out
warships like sausages, like samosas.
And North Korea, they also will be able
to spring a surprise or two. I think the
US will get a far more nasty surprise,
far nastier surprise with China and
North Korea than with Iran.
I think so.
Yeah.
Su says, "Do you think our population
will support the government in a
hypothetical long war?" I'm talking
about the people who go crazy about LPG
shortages and onion price hikes.
I don't know. I think if there's a war,
the people will unite at least well
maybe 70% of the population will will
unite. Hopefully.
The issue is that we've got I don't know
how many tens of millions of
Bangladeshes in India. There's going to
be they're going to be a problem for for
us and we have foreign infiltrators of
different kinds also in India. So they
they would be a problem for us. I think
our population will be reasonably
united. Uh all people go crazy about LPG
shortages and onion price hikes and all
that. But if there is an existential
threat to the nation, they will they'll
be happy to suffer any any such problems
as long as the nation is able to
overcome the threat. So people go crazy
about LPG shortages, onion price hikes,
etc. In peace time, in peace time
Indians love to complain. But in
wartime, I think Indians will unite. The
foreigners will be a problem for us. But
most Indians in in wartime will
definitely unite. Maybe more than 70%,
maybe 80 90% of Indians will unite. But
the foreigners who are embedded within
India, they could be a problem for us.
Okay.
Uh, Soldier Boy says, "I meant India. Is
there any hope or our fate is sealed?" I
think there's hope. India, why is our
fate sealed? I think India has a lot of
hope. I think India has a lot of lot of
hope. Okay. Abai Singh says favorite IPL
team and favorite Indian and
international cricketer. I don't watch
the IPL. The last IPL I watched
properly. Look, I watched the initial
IPL which was 2007. I think I watched
the first match. Brendan McCullum hit a
hit 157 I think.
And the first IPL Indian players did not
do do great. And I watched that IPL that
was the next one I think it was in South
Africa. One IPL is in South Africa.
After that I've kind of lost interest in
the IPL.
One issue is that they keep changing
teams every couple of years. So it's
they'll reshuffle the players all over
the place and it's a completely new
team.
Guys who are adversaries are suddenly
together in the same team. So there's a
lack of continuity in the IPL teams.
That's an issue for me. And uh one thing
I don't like about the IPL overall IPL
is fantastic as a concept. It's
fantastic.
It has made India a sporting superpower,
a cricketing superpower. It has made all
the foreign players, especially
Australians who used to be all nasty
towards Indians, now they are very
differential. Good for us. Excellent. So
from those perspectives, IPL is
fantastic. What I would like to see in
the IPL is a more of a balance between
bat and ball. You can't have 78 sixes in
a in a in a 40 over two winnings match.
Give keep something in there for the
bowlers too, right? I think lowcoring
matches can be even more thrilling than
matches when you see sixes. But in India
it's all about sixes. Yay. Six six and
all that.
So, um, so I don't really find the IPL
that interesting, unfortunately. I I I
know the IPL is on right now. I suppose
there must be an IPL match going on
right now, possibly live, but I don't
know who's playing. I don't
So, I don't really follow the IPL. Maybe
the the semi-finals and finals I may
watch, but for some of it at least,
maybe highlights. But yeah, a favorite
Indian ind Indian and international
cricketer. See I don't have one favorite
cricketer among the Indian cricketers
who I really have liked admired the ones
I have seen
there's many there's capilv of of course
shinat
I was a big fan of prabakar manos
prabakar despite everything
tendulkar ki
I was a big fan of kohli when he was
that aggressive player who used to win
matches for India I've always been
a great fan of aggressive players,
players uh who put fear into the
opposition's minds and hearts. Ganguli
was a big fan of his captaincy and his
aggressive batting.
I think he really undervalued his
bowling.
um
Kumblay Bumrah of course so many so many
there are so many players international
cricketers well there are many of them
whom I admire who I not may not like a
lot Glenn McGra I admire don't like him
I don't like him too much um
international cricketers Shane War the
late Shane War the late great Shane War
Richards uh Kurtley Ambrose
players I admire who I mean look Wasimi
Makum Vakarunis Iran Khan I admired
those players. No question about that.
They were outstanding players. Um,
Taunting, I admired him. Didn't like
him.
Um, Dean Jones, there's so many. There's
so many. I'm sure I'm missing out a lot.
Um, yeah.
Okay.
So, Sjani says, "Can you decode this
line with AI? Snakes and crocodiles to
secure 175 km using a equal to Z is Z
equal to 26
snakes. You want me to decode this line
with AI? Snakes and crocodiles are
secure 175 km using A equal to Z.
A equal to Z uh A equal to 1 Z equal 26.
I'm not exactly sure what you are asking
me to do. It would help if the
instructions were more clear.
Um,
okay. Give me a second. Let me ask an
AI.
No, I can't do that. Right. Yeah. Yeah.
I'm not sure what you're asking.
Let's still try what you're saying.
Please decode this sentence.
Snakes and crocodiles to secure 175 km.
Okay.
And you're saying using using
a = to z
and you're saying a = 1 and
z = 26.
Okay, let me see if AI understands what
you're saying.
Okay, so reverse alphabet cipher. So you
get is a good
uh so I'm not sure what you're asking.
Obviously the result is uh
incomprehensible.
So it would help if you could give
clearer instructions as to what you're
trying to say.
Sahil Akar says the greater Israel
project is rooted in Jewish escathology.
So in the end it was always about
religion. I am not uh familiar with
Jewish esquetology. Escatology is all
about the end of the world, isn't it? In
some religions, let me see.
Escatology meaning end of world thing,
right? Not that man. Escatology.
Escatathology.
Oh, they gave me the French.
The branch of Syria, theology, final
events and end of the world and all the
human destiny, death, judgment, all
that. Yeah, that's right. So, um, Jewish
escathology. I will not try to do a
crash course right now with AI but I am
not familiar with Jewish Catholic end of
the world the return of something
Messiah some kind of I don't know what
it's about and uh yeah there have some
they have the concept of Armageddon
right the final battle of humanity and
stuff like that but I'm not sure what
it's like uh and what it's all about and
I'm not sure what the connection it has
if whether if whether there is one with
the so-called Greater Israel project.
So I'm not aware of these things. So I
won't be able to answer give you a clear
answer because I don't know. Right.
Yeah. But it looks like there is a a
greater Israel project based on the
patches you see on the should shoulders
of uh IDF soldiers. It looks like there
actually is a greater Israel project
which was a big surprise to me.
Okay. Deepak dating coach says thank you
sir. uh India Hindu population full
pacifized with BS spirituality Hindu
pacivity spread on massive level imagine
something happening happened to India's
prime minister India will be destroyed
by insiders and outsiders see Iran whole
population is like army one goes next
leader comes and fights yeah India I
understand what you're saying and I to a
very large extent agree with you uh it's
not Hindu pacivity
I disagree with that point Hindu Hindu
passivity if you see Hindu gods they all
carry weapons so so it's not like
Hinduism is a passive religion
right Hinduism is not a passive religion
but the way it is portrayed in the 21st
century in 20th century is as a religion
of pacivity so because of that people
think that relig that Hinduism is a is a
passive religion Hinduism is not a
passive religion Hinduism is a
vigorously active religion but we have
been we are being taught a false version
of Hinduism Hinduism is being misported.
Ainsa
permodharma.
Yeah. Do you know? Do you understand the
meaning of ainsa perma dharma? Ainsa
perma dharma means
peace or nonviolence is the highest
ideal in humanity. Is the highest ideal
in dharma.
Right? So what does it tell you
implicitly? It tells you that if
somebody is being hins or non or
nonviolent, please destroy them.
If you want to achieve a peaceful
nonviolent world, you have to destroy
the adharmic people, the violent people
through violent means. Of course, that's
why gods have weapons. So, please
understand that Hinduism is not a
passive religion, but it has been
portrayed these days over the past
couple of centuries as a passive
religion.
only the peaceful peaceloving elements
of Hinduism are being taught to people
and not the elements that tell you to
resist and kill kill the the evildoers.
So because of that India India's
population is pacifized. India's
population is divided. All we do is
argue and talk and discuss and fight
each other. All our energy is spent
fighting each other. We don't have a
clear direction as a nation. We don't
have a clear mission as a nation. Our
leaders don't know they have not given
us a clear vision, mission, blueprint
for the future, nothing. Right? So
everyone in in in India,
we have shared values. We don't have
shared interests in different parts of
India.
The past 80 years, we've done a great
job of dividing ourselves. Our leaders
have done a great job of that. And we
that's that's the case today that India
is a divided nation. a nation where
different people have different
interests, we don't see ourselves as
having shared interests.
And if you do a center of gravity
analysis of India, it will not be a very
nice thing to do. See, when I use the
term center of gravity, I know it's it's
fun to make it's it's great fun to make
fun of some some Pakistani generals who
use the term center of gravity. But uh
to be serious, center of gravity is a
genuine military term. It originates in
the works of KL Fonclausitz the great
Prussian military strategist and writer
who wrote the book on war. So there is a
genuine concept called center of gravity
and in Iran the center of gravity is
decentralized and distributed.
Iran is a is is a great example of a
fault tolerant
anti-fragile network warfare system.
Okay. So Iran's Iran's center of gravity
is decentralized. There's no center of
gravity. It's spread out. You can't
destroy Iran.
And the people are all motivated. Their
whole population is is like one. Like
you say, you're right. When it comes to
India, what's India's center of gravity?
The what the concept of center of
gravity in the Clausubits worldview is
that one thing which if destroyed
destroys the whole system.
that one thing which is the fulcrum in
the crux of all operations and and
everything you you take that out the
whole system collapses and crumbles. I'm
sure there's a better way of putting it
putting it across.
Explain Clausitz's definition of center
of gravity.
Yeah, there we have it. What's it say?
The hub of all power and movement upon
which everything depends. representing
the primary source of an enemy's
strength or moral force of freedom of
action. The focal point where the forces
are most dense and striking it causes
the enemy to lose balance and the whole
system crumbles. Essentially, that's
what it is.
Now, if I were to if you want, I can do
that's a great actually it's a great
content creation idea.
A Clausowitz analysis
of the top 10 top 10 most powerful
nations. What are their strengths,
weaknesses, fragilities? What is their
center of gravity
and the components of the center of
gravity? There's a deeper decomposition
that you have to do of the center of
gravity. This is all military history.
This is military analysis.
I think India has a very clear
nondistributed system and clear center
of gravity. You take one thing out,
everything crumbles. It's kind of like
that.
So yeah, overall I would say that uh
much much of what you are saying is
true. India needs to really get its
affairs under control. Get its um
India needs a better system essentially.
India needs a much better system. Much
better the system that we currently have
the governance system and everything
else. It is not good for us. It is not
the optimal ideal or even the sub it's
not even a acceptably sub suboptimal
system. It's a terrible system.
So overall sir, I agree with you Deepuk
G. Yes.
WBKT says it send it seems that Sentcom
is as credible as park DGSPR.
Look um
it's perfectly see lying and misleading
is a perfectly legitimate tactic in
warfare. Like they say you know people
try to conflate love and war. Everything
is fair in love and war. Everything is
fair in war. I promise you. So it's
perfectly legitimate to to lie and
mislead in in warfare. Yeah. So they
have been claiming that you know they've
lost only like four soldiers or whatever
and um um they have been trying to um
claim that they haven't lost too many
aircraft and so on. I'm sure the actual
figures are much higher. But see in
India we have this misconception that
you have to tell the truth because
India's national moto was
very stupid. You should not tell the
truth. You should lie. You can tell the
truth 30 years after the operation is
over after the war is over. Don't start
spewing the truth while the military
operation is gone going on. Don't say
you know there's this terrorist attack
in Mumbai and you know on so and so
floor I got a phone call from from so
and so person who is hidden in room
number so and so and say say that on the
media
on live TV. You don't do that
when you just came out of a war with
Pakistan and if you're an army general
or whatever, you don't go to a foreign
nation and give a give give a seminar
there and said that you know what we
lost so many x number of aircraft. You
don't do that. You you don't lie about
these things.
India should learn from the Americans
instead of thinking that they are not
credible. Why should they be credible?
They should not be credible. They should
lie. You should also lie in warfare. I'm
not saying lie in civilian life. I'm
saying in warfare it is perfectly it's a
good thing to not allow the world to
know what's really happening.
Okay. So Tabish Shatabish says with due
respect disagree on average Iranian
engineer being better than average
Indian speaking from my own experience
we are far ahead of any other ethnicity
in merit rewarding environments world
over educational background doesn't
matter beyond
in your opinion. All right, sir. No
issues. No issues. Please feel free to
feel free to disagree with me. But I
stand by what I'm saying. The average
Iranian engineer is better than the
average Indian engineer. It's nothing to
do with ethnicity. It's all to do with
the system, the educational system and
the fact that Iran respects merit. India
does not. So the average Iranian
engineer is better than the average
Indian engineer.
And look at their achievements. Look at
what their missiles can do.
Their missiles can change direction in
the terminal phase of their descent.
Their missiles can change velocity
dramatically
in the terminal phase of their descent.
They can go from Mac 3 to Mac 8 or Mac 9
in the last few seconds. They can
maneuver.
They can slow down. They can speed up.
Look at the drones. They have the best
drones. The Russians have
the Russians imported Iranian drones and
now they're manufacturing the drones
themselves.
Ethnicity.
From that perspective, I'm sure we are
better than anybody else. That's a
different story.
See, the point is let's not overestimate
ourselves. Let's be realistic. Anyhow,
please feel to feel free to disagree.
That's perfectly fine. But I stand by
what I am saying.
Dark side of the moon says
CHPM operation sindur something last per
all right sir thank you so much all
right so you I think you're from
Pakistan are you you're saying that air
superiority was with Pakistan all right
sir Pakistan outstanding brilliant
what's pindabad
listen it's okay somebody said something
and that makes you feel good about
yourself all Right. Look uh from my
perspective,
India
obliterated Pakistan in those three
days. It was a very limited encounter.
It was just aerial warfare.
Right
now, some European publication is saying
something. So, it makes you feel good.
All right, sir.
It's good for you. All right. Someday we
should sit together and have a chai
together and discuss this. All right. in
in the UAE, I suppose. All right.
Anyhow, all right. Thank you, sir, for
your comment. Or ma'am, I don't know.
You're a lady or a gentleman, doesn't
matter. Uh, Adita says, "Do you do you
think CSE engineers dug their own graves
by making AI?" Do you think CE computer
science engineers dug their own grave by
making AI? No, you've got to do progress
has to keep happening.
I don't think they've dug their own
graves by by by making AI.
This was we were always going to reach
this stage where machines will finally
have the ability to start thinking.
Right now machines think we don't know
if they're sentient or not conscious or
not, but they do think. Right? These
machines have long since passed the
Turing test as the way we imagined the
Turing test would be 20 years ago or 10
years ago. they've gone way way beyond
that for sure.
Um,
and of course AI will take jobs and AI
will make certain things redundant. But
AI is like a patient.
AI is is like a patient with amnesia.
Every session you start, you're starting
with a blank mind. So there are issues
that AI has and there'll be there'll be
solutions to those issues as well, of
course. So every session that you start
with with an AI, you you have to give it
context and so on and so forth. Then you
have uh some AI systems that give you
projects in which you already load the
context. So it kind of knows what you're
talking about, but it still doesn't know
who you are and things. So you have to
create your own systems and have your
own local AIs running in your own
powerful local machines in order for the
AI to know you and so on. So we are
going step by step further in AI. But I
don't think engineers have dug their own
graves by making AI. Progress has to
happen. It has to happen. Arin goauti
says uh US but Indian first uh and new
viewer. Well, thank you so much sir.
Welcome to this channel. Thank you so
much for being a new viewer. So you are
an Indian origin uh American. All right.
All right. Uh the question is how can
you see India taking advantage of the
stupid situation by our clearly senile
and bought president? Maybe we see India
take a step into being a superpower.
Jind
uh Jind thank you so much. So now how do
I see India taking advantage of the
situation?
Yeah, stupid situation indeed by our
clearly senile sonile and bought
president.
Um
how can India take advantage of this?
See this situation is actually hurting
India. Uh Iran is not preventing uh tank
oil tankers from crossing the street of
Hormos if they are destined for India
which means that India is still getting
oil shipments through the street of
Hormos. India is also now purchasing
Iranian oil I think. So this that's one
way of taking advantage that we that we
had acquired to American demands to not
buy Iranian oil the past decade or so
roughly but now we are purchasing
Iranian oil.
uh but the real issue the real way it's
hurting India is because our our gas
shipments are impacted India one India's
major supplier of of liquid of of of
natural gas is Qatar and Qatar has now
recently dictated force majour right
they are no longer able to produce gas
their facilities have been hit and
that's a problem that India is facing
and it's already having an effect in
India a bad effect in India
So right now the situation is kind of
painful for India and it could get worse
if the long if the if the war lasts
longer but in the long run how can this
be advantageous to India. In what way
could it potentially be advant
advantageous to India? So one way it
could be advantageous to India is if
Iran actually prevails in this war and
the Americans the United States is no
longer able to hold on to the military
bases it had in the region in the Gulf
region. So the US if we I mean if you
look here if we look at Google
American bases in the Gulf region
I'm sure there's a there is yeah so
these are the uh bases the Americans had
in the region
for example there's this base in Bahrain
okay uh which is a major naval facility
the the the headquarters of the US fifth
fleet that is most likely either
completely obliterated or essentially
non-functional now. So if a situation
arises where the US can't return to its
bases and can't reoperationalize them,
well that changes the equation in the
region. See, for the Americans to
reoperationalize those bases, they're
going to have to first of all ensure
that the Iranians lose their missile and
drone capabilities, which I don't see
happening anytime soon. Secondly, even
if the the Americans are able to defeat
Iran and destroy their drone and missile
capabilities, even then to rebuild those
bases that have been built over decades,
the Americans will have to spend
hundreds of billions of dollars, perhaps
trillions of dollars to rebuild the
bases.
And that is difficult. That takes time.
And I'm not sure the Americans will be
able to do it anytime soon. So if the
Americans lose their power projection
capabilities in the region then the
whole regional balance of power equation
changes. Iran becomes the region's
predominant power. Okay.
And that is a problem for the US and
Pakistan because now on both sides of
Pakistan you have non-friendly nations.
Iran is no fan of Pakistan. No friend of
Pakistan. And because of this, America's
ability to impose pressure on India and
arm twist India diminishes, declines.
Right? We already seeing India take some
steps that the Americans won't like. So
this stupid situation, this stupid war,
if the Americans lose this war and are
expelled from their force, from the
current force posture in the Middle
East, then it gives India more breathing
space and more leverage in negotiations
and other things with the US.
But overall, long-term,
India will have to get stronger on its
own without depending on other nations
like it's trying to do, right? India
will have to do everything on its own.
India will have to build its own
military-industrial complex, its own
weapon systems, its own AI, its own
everything.
There's no shortcuts.
Space, yeah, space capabilities which
India has kind of fallen asleep on. Um,
so yeah, it could be uh this this war
could be advantageous to India in the
long run depending on how it ends. If
Iran prevails then it'll be it'll give
India more options visa with the US
right
um but even if the US is expelled from
the region the US still will come out as
a as a beneficiary of this war because
if the state of Armos remains closed for
many nations and the state of Babal
Mando is also closed by the Houthis then
all other nations that are impacted by
this will have to purchase American
uh products oil and gas which will be
great for the US economy.
Um and if the the war ends up
devastating the region and destroying
the oil production capabilities in the
region that will be a great long-term
benefit for the US. So overall the
whether it's win or lose for the US they
will benefit from the war and India will
if it benefits at all it will be not
major benefits and it will depend on how
the war ends. All right.
Arun Agarwal says chances that Iran ends
the war and petrol dollar remains.
Iran is in no situation to end the war.
Uh the chances are very very low for
Iran Iran to unilaterally end the war or
agree to some some kind of uh ceasefire
with the US. See the the problem is Iran
doesn't trust the US. Iran if the
Americans promise something, you can't
trust them to keep their word. Iran
knows that even if the Americans sign an
agreement, they can walk out of it,
right? Un unilaterally. Trump has done
that before. In 2017, he walked out
unilaterally from the JCPOA, the Iran
nuclear deal. So even if the Americans
and Iranians sign an agreement, an
official treaty, the Americans, the
moment they get an opportunity, will
break it. So how can Iran afford to end
the war when they especially when they
are actually in a position of advantage?
So there's I think there's very little
chance that this war ends soon.
Unfortunately, sadly, the petro dollar
is a different thing. It it depends on a
variety of factors.
You know,
the petro dollar most likely will remain
even if Iran wins because the Americans
may ensure that all the oil production
facilities in the Gulf region are
destroyed or badly damaged and then the
world has to depend on American oil. In
that case, the petro dollar system
remains.
Right. The Americans can certainly
engineer that even if they lose the war.
So I think the petrol dollar system is
going to stay for a while at least. Abu
Singh says how is this Iran Israel war
affecting the Russia Ukraine war? Is
Russia gaining from it? Or maybe Russia
has a hand in prolonging it. See if the
war is hurting the US and Iran is able
to keep fighting
and if because of this the world has to
start depending on Russian oil then it's
advantageous for Russia to to let's say
prolong the war if it can do such a
thing right and in that case Russia does
benefit from it because if the straight
of hormones is closed for some nations
then those nations can't get energy from
there from the Gulf region then they
have no choice but to buy oil from
Russia or some other country and Russia
benefits from this. So that way it's
been especially for let's say for India
uh we certainly can get oil through the
state of Hormos. Iran is not stopping
oil coming from coming to India but gas
is an issue for India and we will have
to look look beyond Qatar for gas. So
maybe we can have Russia deliver gas to
us and that will be good for us and that
will be good for Russia as well. So in
these ways Russia can benefit. But now
the Ukrainians have gone and bombed
three four ports that Russia has which
are the major hubs from where they
export oil and gas.
They've done s the Ukrainians have done
significant damage to these Russian
ports.
So you can see a clear linkage between
the two wars. Russia stands to benefit
from the war in the Gulf region, the war
against Sidan. So Ukraine goes and
destroys Russian ports which now makes
it difficult for Russia to benefit from
that. So the two wars are clearly linked
and the Ukrainians are going to be
sharing their um their drone tactics and
drone knowhow with the Americans
especially counter drone measures. So
there's another linkage. There's
multiple linkages like this. Okay.
Okay. Dear Kamat says some family
members are stuck are still stuck
between Saudi and Bahrain. Could they
leave now? What are the options for
them? Saudi and Bahrain. Saudi and
Bahrain. Bahrain is a small little
nation
which used to host the American fifth
fleet headquarters and it's been
bombarded by the Iranians. Saudi Arabia
is a large nation
and most likely you're safe if you're
there. Even in Bahrain, if you're a
civilian, you're mostly safe. So some
family members are stuck between Saudi
and Bahin. That that's a bridge or
something, right? Let's take a look at
the geography. Give me a second. Let's
take a look a look at the geography.
Saudi Baharin. Let's put the map on the
screen.
Um,
okay. Let's zoom in.
As you can see, Bahin is this tiny
little country.
This, I think, is a Bahini island. Yeah.
And then you have this bridge.
You have a bridge between Saudi Arabia
and Bahrain. So the question is your
parents are stuck between Saudi and
Bahrain
are they struck on the bridge. So this
is Saudi territory
and between the two countries there's a
bridge which is about 10 15 km 20 30 km
long. How how long is this bridge? 35 23
okay 23 straight line.
So I'm not sure what you mean by your uh
parents are stuck there
but if they are stuck in a precarious
situation I would say they should leave
immediately
if they have the ability to do do that.
So I'm not clear where they are stuck.
Are they stuck on the bridge between
Saudi Arabia and Bahin or are they stuck
in Bahin or are they stuck in Saudi
Arabia?
If they are actually stuck on the bridge
they should leave immediately.
So I'm not clear about where they are
stuck but uh
yeah they should move to a safe space
safe place at the earliest
right I'm sure if you are in Saudi
Arabia most parts of Saudi Arabia are
very safe only the military facilities
are being struck by Isra by by Iran so
you're fine so move to a safe place
immediately that's what I would
recommend okay all the best to your
parents
uh GGW poly says how legitimate are
David Gush's claims on UFOs. I am not
aware of who David Grush is and what his
claims are. So, I don't know. I don't
keep track of what's happening in the
UFO world.
Um, and uh, most of these claims I don't
actually take very seriously.
I think UFOs are secret military
technology. I don't think these are
alien visitations to Earth.
I have seen no evidence of that. So um
to answer your question, I'm not aware
of this gentleman and I'm not aware of
his claims. So unfortunately I won't be
able to give my views about that. Sorry.
Aris Manticor, good to see you. The
question is, is Trump aiming for global
collapse or is this war simply leading
to it as both sides are now at an impass
unwilling to compromise? Your thoughts?
See,
whichever way this goes, this is going
to hurt the world world's economy, isn't
it?
It not sure if it will cause a global
collapse but it can actually it can see
in what scenario does it cause a global
collapse? It starts with an escalation
and continuing escalations in this war
and the Americans and Israelis what they
do is that they bombard Iran's oil
production facilities and oil reserves
where they have kept oil in containers
and all that. So that starts destroying
Iran's oil production and and and
storage capabilities. In response, Iran
starts bombarding the Gulf nations,
their oil production and storage
capabilities.
And the worst case scenario is that the
entire Gulf region, all the oil and gas
production and storage facilities are
destroyed. So the region still has
tremendous amounts of oil, but you can't
extract it for the next 10 years.
Then what happens is that the world now
will have to depend on the United
States, Russia
and uh non-Gulf nations for oil.
So apart from the apart apart from
Russia,
the US controls all the other sources of
oil and gas.
Whether it is the North Sea, whether
it's the UK, whether it's Canada,
whether it's Venezuela, whether it's
Brazil, whether it is some African
nations, whoever, the US controls them
all apart from Russia. So that way the
US can exercise way more control over
nations like India.
And even China, they can constrain their
choices, right?
And if the US decides that nobody will
sell oil to India and China, the US can
collapse India and China's economy in in
this scenario.
So I don't know if this is what the US
wants, but it certainly can be a a
a viable outcome of this war, a
plausible outcome of this war. A
plausible outcome, right? So Trump can
collapse various economies like that. I
mean, Trump won't be around for forever
as the US president, but the US can do
it, right? So, the war could lead us to
that kind of situation. It could very
well lead us to that sort of situation.
Things could get really much worse for a
lot of countries because of this war
that the Americans have started, the
Israelis have started.
Yep. Okay. Vive Singh says while we are
doing good in surface combats we are
struggling with undersea strikers when
we have capability to build complex
technology like SSBN.
Um
so we how many submarines does India
have 15 16 17 whatever the number is
less than 20 for sure which is a
pitiable number of submarines for a
nation of India size and a nation that
likes to boast that the Indian Ocean
region is our strategic backyard we like
to boast that right we are a nation of
sloans but we have less than 20
submarines surface vessels can be taken
out very easily it is submarines that
are critical to offensive and defensive
capability ities and how many submarines
does North Korea have for example. Okay.
Uh let's let's uh let's ask our friend
Google how many submarines they have.
How many submarines do China, India,
North Korea and the United States and
Japan have?
Okay. US has about 70 all nuclear. China
has 61. North Korea has uh 70 24 to 70.
Japan has 23 24 and India has 18
including nuclear and and standard
submarines. India has a woefully small
number of submarines.
Right? So India has this is this nation
that doesn't act unless there's a
crisis. So that's what India has always
like been like a passive reactive
nation.
Uh we
can start building more submarines. I
would say that India should have at
least 50 submarines at least. Yeah. So I
don't why are we struggling with
submarines? Because the government
doesn't take the initiative. There is an
initiative. There's we are building some
submarines right now. Like I don't know
three four submarines we're building.
But why aren't we building 20 at a time?
Why not?
Why don't we have the objective of
having by 2050 a 100 submarines? Why
not?
Okay, let's not say maybe not 100. Let's
say 50.
Why not 50 submarines in the next 20 25
years, two a year? Why can't we do that?
I don't see any long-term vision of
anything.
Of course, in in the next few years,
submarines will not instead of
submarines, we will start using uh
unmanned underwater vehicles essentially
under underwater autonomous drones or
maybe non autonomous drones or whatever.
So that will also be useful and that
could be even more dangerous than
submarines essent essentially like
underwater mines that will strike
whenever required that sort of thing. So
technology is going to evolve and we
should keep keep up with that. But
submarines we have to focus on. So why
are we struggling? Because we choose to
struggle sadly. 24 Bat says you said it
you you said if Iran wins it's good for
India as we will have more leverage but
like you said US will also have more oil
controlled and destroy Gulf. So is it
true? It depends right. It depends on
how it goes. If the US ensures the
complete destruction of all oil
production and storage facilities in the
Gulf, then the US will have tremendous
leverage in the entire world. But if the
US simply loses the war and moves out
and Iran Iran becomes the regional
hedgeim and there is still oil
production going on in the region, in
that case it is good for us. It depends
on how it goes. It depends on how it
goes. If the Americans simply nuke the
region, I mean figuratively nuke, not
actually nuke but simply destroy the oil
production capability of the region,
then they are the biggest beneficiaries
of this war. Even if they are forced to
lose, forced to leave the war, leave the
region. Then they lose regionally but
win globally.
Okay? Because now they control most of
the oil production of the world apart
from what Russia produces.
And then they may even prevent India
from buying Russian oil and China from
buying Russian oil unless Russia can
pipe the oil directly into China. But
for India not possible unless it comes
through China. So then the Americans may
force India to purchase only Russ uh
American oil. That will tremendously
constrain India's choices. So that is a
disaster for India. But if the Americans
don't destroy the entire oil
infrastructure reg in the region in the
Gulf region and they are defeated by
Iran and they leave the region then it
gives India more leverage. It depends on
which way the the whole thing goes. All
right.
Okay. Pratep Kumar Royce says why
can't we make our own Starlink? Of
course we can but we don't want to.
We don't want to.
We can make our own Starlink. We can
make our own GPS.
But we only had the ambition to make a
small regional IRSS constellation of
satellites. And that too is no longer
functional now. Despite no matter what
any general says,
right? We don't have the ambition. We
are a nation of low ambition and low
standards. We are a nation with big
slogans but low ambition and low
execution.
There is manteor says regarding the
cookies problem. We have a clause for
them in ST list called inclusion of any
cookie tribe for ST status. We tried to
remove that clause but a certain
ministry has kept that order in
obeyance. Very shameful. Okay. I
am not aware of the specific details.
I've heard of something like this
but a certain ministry has kept that
order in obeyance. Huh.
So the question is what is India trying
to achieve
with respect to Manipur?
What's the long-term plan? Are we going
to make Manipur into Akundi Kistan?
And do we want the complete erasure of
Indian civilization and culture from
Manipur? And do we want the remaining
Hindus in the in Manipur to convert to
be forced to convert to Christianity? It
looks like we are we are pushing the
state in that direction, aren't we?
Unless there is some great master plan
and master stroke coming some somewhere
down the line.
Well, we have been waiting for master
strokes for for more than a decade now.
So, I don't know. It's what's happening
in Manipur is is is absolute disaster.
Sadly disaster.
Dirj Kamad says um Ashikur Rahman Tamim
H7Z is provoking Hindus. You mean on
this on this live chat?
Um
Ashikur Rahman
I there's a thousand live chats which is
why I want to be able to look into that.
Uh, I can't see. And that's the reason
why I only do super chats now because
there's so many live chats. It's
impossible to look into live chats and
select a question and possibly
I'm trying to see where is this Ashikur
Raman person.
I can't find this person. See, I will
request all the viewers,
all those of you who are on the live
chat, please, please feel free to chat
among each other. But let's be
respectful.
Let us be respectful
and I will not tolerate any disrespect
of my culture and my country.
Um
I'm unable to find
the person unfortunately.
Okay. So I Okay. So hopefully the
moderator will look into this but in the
meanwhile I'll continue with the Q&A.
Pycraft Deepak Singh says I am 17 years
old got into the University of Toronto
rank Toronto rank ranked 10 for computer
science by QS global ranking outstanding
and Waterloo also Canada in Minnesota
250 uh unsc
US higher rank in Canada lower in US
choose by country or ranking need
guidance major is computer science
I think if you
Look, um, if you are getting into any
North American university, first of all,
it's it's great. Now, you have multiple
offers, which is fantastic.
Um,
Toronto is ranked 10 in the world for
computer science and Waterloo is also a
good university. Minnesota is 250.
Higher rank in Canada, lower in the US.
Choose by country or ranking. You know
what? In North America, it doesn't
matter.
It depends on your long-term objectives.
If you just want to get a degree from a
great university and return to India,
then I would say go to go into the UN go
for the University of Toronto.
If your objective is to get a degree
from a great 10th rank university, the
highest ranked university you can
achieve, you can get into
and then you want to return to India,
then you should go into the University
of Toronto. But if your objective is to
let's say stay and work in the US in
that case maybe Minnesota makes more
sense because you already getting into
the US I'm not sure exactly how it works
okay I'm not aware of the immigration
procedures and all if you plan to stay
there for the for a long time maybe
immigrate maybe get a green card all
that stuff then perhaps
it will be
better to go into Minnesota if you
prefer the US if you want to become a
Canadian resident or whatever ever then
Toronto or Waterloo makes sense. So it
depends on what you're trying to
achieve, what what your long-term
objectives are. Uh from a purely
academic perspective, clearly Toronto is
the best university, right? So depending
on what you want to achieve, you have to
make long-term long-term what you want
to achieve, you have to make the choice.
From an acade academic perspective,
Toronto seems to be the best. But from
depending on whether you want to stay in
the US long term, maybe Minnesota makes
more sense because if you get a degree
from Toronto then you want to work in
the US then you have to go through a
whole new process which you don't have
to go through if you are already in the
US. So yeah depending on those things
yeah all the best and good job good job
do well. Pratipumar Roy says durand the
two views I haven't seen it yet still
haven't seen it yet. Maybe in a day or
two I'll watch it. I certainly will
watch it but still it hasn't happened.
Shiraak Shinat says
uh two questions. One, how much did the
Marshall plan drive Europe's post-war
reindustrialization? Can it be compared
to China's Barri in the present day?
Secondly, will the US or China lead
post-war reconstruction efforts in Iran?
Okay, the question two is interesting.
Of course, that's uh we'll have to see
about that. The Marshall Plan did drive
Europe's post-war re-industrialization.
After the world, after the second world
war, Europe, Western Europe was
devastated. The UK was bombed to bits.
Uh France had been under Nazi occupation
for several years. You had war raging
across Western Europe. Um the Nazis had
conquered Western Europe all the way to
Normandy essentially and then they
fought their way all the way back to
Germany. So the whole of Western Europe
was devastated. Eastern Europe was also
devastated and the Marshall plan was
about the US giving offering financial
aid not not not donations but loans to
these nations. Uh it was loans right? It
was loans for reconstruction purposes.
Um Marshall Plan was it loans or aid?
Let me just check. Was the Marshall Plan
loans or donations?
It was loans of course
donations, grants rather than loans. Oh,
interesting. Okay. 85 to 90% of the 13
mill billion aid provided as gifts that
did not need to be repaid. The remaining
amount was in the form of low interest
loans. Very interesting because when
because the UK was in debt to the US as
a consequence of the Second World War
and the US insisted that the UK repay
them, right? And the UK was repaying the
American debt until the first decade of
the 21st century.
Okay. But the Marshall plan was was was
grants, gifts. Most of it were gifts was
gifts and the rest was low interest
loans. Obviously that did
drive a lot of the um postwar
re-industrialization in in Europe. So
that's one aspect of this whole matter
that I haven't studied in great detail.
Okay. I have studied the war for sure,
the wars, the first and second world
wars. But the Marshall plan is yeah,
clearly I need to study that in more
detail because it certainly is
interesting. So it was a humanitarian
effort, humanitarian thing that the
Americans did and of course
they were the major dominant power in
Western Europe. They wanted to control
Western Europe. They wanted to have
their military bases all across Western
Europe. They wanted to control the
future long-term future of Western
Europe. Which is why maybe this was even
though it was grants and donations,
maybe it was a long-term investment that
did pay off, you know, because today if
you see Western Europe, it's controlled
by the US. Its fate is in the hands of
the US.
Many of these nations are part of are
are members of NATO, which means they
are not not sovereign. their
sovereignties at least some of their
military sovereignty has been taken over
by the US and the rest of the nations
are members of EU of the EU once again
non-s sovereign nations controlled by
the US indirectly and many nations are
members of EU and NATO at the same time
so this Marshall plan these donations
they may look like gifts etc but they
were actually a good investment by the
US to create a strong prosperous
economically prosperous Europe that they
can control.
So it clearly did drive a lot of
Europe's postwar re-industrialization.
Now can it be compared to China's BRI in
the present day? Not really. China's BR
is not about giving, you know, gifts to
countries. Gyra's BR is about creating
an infrastructure
big large scale you know
intercontinental essentially
infrastructure that will make China the
center of the world or at least the
center of Eurasia and it will connect
China to all the far-flung parts of
Eurasia including especially Western
Europe so that China can export things
to these nations as easily as possible.
So, China's BRRI is totally different
and you can't really compare that with
the Marshall plan. Now, uh will the US
or China lead postwar reconstruction
efforts in Iran? The US definitely won't
lead postwar reconstruction efforts in
Iran unless they take control of Iran.
In that case, they may lead some
reconstruction of efforts in Iran. So
for the US to lead reconstruction
efforts in Iran,
the US has to win this war and achieve
on ground control, control on the ground
in Iran, which means boots on the
ground, which seems extremely extremely
unlikely to happen. So assuming the US
can't control Iran with boots on the
ground, I don't see the US leading any
kind of post-war reconstruction efforts.
Even if the US loses and is kicked out
of the region, the US won't give
reparations or damages or whatever to
Iran. Doesn't I don't see that
happening. Only if they win and take
complete control of Iran with boots on
the ground will they show try to show
some magnanimity in that magnanimity in
that case. Will China lead postwar
reconstruction efforts in Iran? It
depends. Maybe the China and Russia may
certainly give some aid to Iran at
least.
Um
yeah, they will certainly give some aid
and I think Chinese companies may get
involved in the reconstruction efforts
because
it gives China some some kind of
more
I mean you know it gives China
non-military boots boot boots on the
ground in in in Iran. The Chinese will
love to do that. So they will give aid
to Iran and they may even see they may
even send workers, engineers, etc. to
reconstruct roads, bridges, whatever in
Iran. Yeah, you may see that for sure.
Very interesting question. Very
interesting. The Chinese will certainly
love to do this in a post-war Iran.
JRXna said, "Do you says, do you think
Trump is stupid or moronic? If yes, all
evidence points to it. How did he become
president twice? How did the system
fail? Possible that some actor reality
TV star does the same for India.
Very interesting question. I don't think
Trump is stupid or moronic.
I don't think he's stupid. He's a
actually
reasonably intelligent person and in
some things he's really intelligent.
He's he knows how to make money.
Okay, he may not be brilliant in making
money. He certainly nothing compared to
someone like Elon Musk or Steve Jobs or
whatever. He's a real estate guy,
builder, developer, that sort of thing.
But that field understands well. He's
very good at networking. Networking is
very good at um cutting deals and all.
At least that's what he claims. Um so
he's good at that. He's really good at
that.
But I don't think he's stupid. Okay. How
did he become president twice? The first
time he became president,
um he became president because he was an
outsider and the people of the US were
tired of all the same old people, you
know, coming to power all the time. Same
families, whether it is Bush or the
Clintons. You had Obama for 80 years. He
spoke a lot, did nothing.
So people, the people of the US wanted
somebody different and Trump was the
right man for the right time. So that's
how he became president. And he's he's a
showman. He's he's great with with words
and all that, right? He's he's
flamboyant. He's he's he's outspoken.
He's a showman. He's you could say he's
charismatic. Yes. So he has all those
uh attributes and qualities you need to
have in a successful politician. What
makes a politician successful? Not
intelligence,
not integrity.
You need to be a showman or a showwoman,
whatever. You need to be charismatic.
You need to have a way with words
because most people they will fixate on
a person's words. If that person speaks
very well, then they will vote for that
person. Especially if they will if the
person can can reach out and tug at your
heart and your emotions and you know get
your emotions going.
Trump has all those attributes and
qualities
and the system is designed to have to to
bring people like these into power
because the US president isn't really
the person in power, right?
The US president's job is to keep
people's attention away from where the
real power lies. The US president isn't
the isn't the most powerful person in
the country.
You think that you think Joe Biden was
was running the country,
right? So the system is designed to
bring that exactly this kind of person
to power. A person who is flamboyant and
attracts all the attention is is is is
narcissistic and egotistical
that sort of thing. In India system is
even worse.
It's very possible that some podcaster
or some rapper or some reality TV star
or some actor or actress or whatever
could come to power in India. It's very
possible. Maybe some some some Tik
Tocker or or Instagram real person could
come to power in the next 10 10 20 10 15
years. It's very possible. Yeah. That's
why democracy is is is is not a good
system for any country especially if the
p the person who's elected actually
becomes the most powerful person in the
US
the system is the country is safe
because that's that's a different power
center in the country and the president
is is not the most powerful person
says we will lead the parliament now to
remove that any cookie tribe clause it's
a farce and we are we even a serious
this country to have that kind of
clause. WTF?
Let me look into this.
Any cookookie tribe clause.
Okay. Cookie.
What is that?
Any cookookie tribe AKT is a nomature in
the schedule tribes list of Manipur.
Introduced only in 2003 designed to
include various cookie clans and
subtribes under one umbrella for ST
status. It is widely used for
administrative convenience but has
become a major point of contention in
Manipur's ethnic conflict. It's not an
ethnic conflict. It's a conflict between
Indians and foreigners.
So this term was included to encompass
in 2003 who was ruling Manipur. My
question is I don't remember who it was
but
um
so in 2021 again 23 some groups
including THU inp Manipur called for the
removal of any cookie tribe from the ST
list. They argued the term is vague and
ambiguous generic label rather than a
distinct tribe asserting that it could
allow foreigners to claim indigenous ST
privileges which is already happening of
course which is already happening.
The cookie people maintain that this is
a constitutionally recognized ST status
and only parliament under article
whatever has the authority to amend this
list.
Okay.
Okay. Yeah. So,
so what is the parliament doing? We're
going to wait another 20 years until
there's like 10 lakh more cookies in
Manipur.
What can I say?
And and the question is how can a
serious country like India have that
kind of clause? You have no idea of the
kind of laws you have in Manipur.
You know about article 370 in Kashmir
right that non Kashmiris can't purchase
land in Kashmir
you and that's been removed right in
Manipur there is a law an act that was
passed by the state legislative assembly
or whatever that prevents the indigenous
mate people of Manipur to purchase any
land outside of
of of the small Impal
Take a look at let's take a look at the
map of Manipur. Okay.
I I can even drag out dig out um I can
even dig out the actual name of that
act.
So let's go to the map.
So if you go to uh Manipur,
if you look at the size of Manipur,
there is the small Infal Valley region
and the Matey people are only allowed to
have land in this region. They can't
purchase any land outside of that region
in their own state. They are not allowed
by law to purchase land outside. they
can only lease land
from
in other parts of Manipur. So it's an
aparthide policy against the indigenous
people of Manipur. Aparthide against the
indigenous people in their own state
that they can't purchase land
outside of a certain region in their own
state.
How does that make sense? Now, let me
try and find the name of this act or
whatever it is. Give me a second. I'll
have to dig through some some some
stuff.
Um,
where can I find it?
Okay,
it's called the the Manipur Hill Areas.
Let me put this on the screen.
Um,
give me a second. So, uh, let's put this
on the screen.
It's called the Manipur Hill Areas
District Council and District Council.
What is it called?
Manipur Hill Areas
Land Revenue and Reforms Act. Okay.
Okay. It's a different one. One second.
Not this.
Will the PDF open?
So,
these PDFs aren't openable. Government
of India sites don't open. I don't know
why.
Uh
so it's called the Manipur Land Revenue
and Land Reforms Act 1960. Okay. And you
can look into this yourself. It ensures
that the people of Manipur, the the
indigenous mate people of Manipur can't
buy land outside of the small Impal
Valley region in their own state. It's
the worst kind of uh apartheide that you
can imagine in uh a supposedly
democratic and free nation. So you have
all these issues in India and now we
have this any cookie tribe clause. So
the entire system is geared towards
punishing the mate people for the war
they fought against the British in 1891.
They still being punished for that.
And if you are a foreigner, you are
being rewarded for that. You get not
only citizenship, you get ST status
immediately.
That's what you have in India.
Ridiculous. Really
amazing says your stream has conditioned
me to use the word vasal. I can't I
can't even achieve or GSM anyone without
someone whispering the dark word in my
ears.
All right. I'm I'm glad about that. I'm
glad. I'm glad. Thank you.
Missy alien says, "Do you think a being
from fourth or fifth dimension etc would
be able to understand the universe
better than they better given that they
can travel time and even different
realities?
Um look if multiple extra dimensions
exist
then we are also part of that."
Okay,
dimensions. What are dimension? What are
dimensions? Length, breadth, height. You
see a room, you see the see a corner of
a room, you will see three different
things coming together, right? Three
different lines coming together. Length,
head, breadth, and height. These are the
three spatial dimensions that we have in
the universe. There is a fourth
dimension called time. So, we live in a
fourdimensional universe. But there are
theories of physics in which you have
additional dimensions which we can't
somehow perceive for some reason. Maybe
they are compactified or whatever.
So in Kutza client theory you you have a
fivedimensional universe. In various
string theories you have 10 11 26
dimensional universes universe. Bzonic
string theory talks about 26 dimensions.
Super string theory is 10 11 etc. Right?
So these are simply dimensions. It
doesn't mean that this is a separate
universe where other people live.
If the universe has let's say 11
dimensions then we inhabit those 11
dimensions without knowing without
realizing that okay
and if you inhabit those dimensions it
doesn't mean you can travel through time
it doesn't mean that doesn't mean that I
remember when I was a kid I used to
watch what Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles
it was a cartoon show and there were
some beings who would come from
dimension X and dimension Z and all
That's
it's nice for uh for cartoon shows and
all
but in in this universe whatever
dimensions exist we all inhabit those
dimen dimensions. If there are extra
dimensions we are in those extra
dimensions they are around us even if we
don't realize that.
Okay. So if there is a fourth or fifth
fourth dimension is there time. If
there's a fifth dimension, we inhabit
that fifth dimension without without
knowing it, right? And we can't
certainly we certainly can't travel
through time and experience different
realities.
So, u if you actually study
physics
and study strings theory study, you will
see that it's not quite the case. Okay.
Okay.
Vivec Singh says how much do you think
Indian rail can help in mobilizing our
troops and missiles because government
is focusing heavily on infrastructure
boost on borders across fronts. I think
the railways can play a great role in
mobilizing troops especially missiles
especially ICBMs and various kinds of
ballistic missiles. You could have
missiles launched from trains
from train compartments or or or special
launchers put on rails on railway
tracks. You can do that. Yes. And the
Indian railways can certainly be of
great help in fing troops from place to
place as and when required. So certainly
the railways can be a major component of
mobilizing troops and missiles
especially troops of course but missiles
also depending on what kind of missiles
we want to of course it's it's way
easier to launch missiles and mobilize
missiles and transport them on roads
compared to railways but railways are
also a viable option. So they certainly
can play a significant role.
Okay. Bat says I meant please explore
Iran Pakistan relations not Israel which
what was the question?
Iran Pakistan relations.
Okay you asked me listen when we discuss
Iran. Okay you are asking
I don't remember which question it was.
I must have taken 50 by now. So I don't
remember what it was. Iran Pakistan
relations if you want me to explore they
are not very good relations they are
both Islamic countries but Pakistan is a
Sunni Islamic country Iran is a Shia
Islamic country not friendly and in Iran
doesn't trust Pakistan because Pakistan
is a US fasal US puppet Iran is a
sovereign nation the US and Iran are
enemies and that's why Iran doesn't
trust Pakistan in 2024 or thereabouts
Iran and Pakistan launched missiles at
each other there was a brief war very
limited conflict between Iran and
Pakistan and Iran accused Pakistan of
sending terrorists into Iranian
territory. So the relations aren't good
in the past before the Islamic uh
revolution.
See the Islamic revolution happened in
1979. Before that Iran was ruled by u
the the puppet Sha of Iran Muhammad
Razabhavi who was an American puppet. At
that time Iran and Pakistan had good
relations. In 1965 when Iran when India
and Pakistan were at war the Pakistanis
took all their fighter planes and flew
them into Iran so that India can't
destroy them. So Iran gave Pakistani
fighter planes refuge and shelter. A so
they had good relations then but after
1979 when there was an Islamic
revolution in Iran and the regime of the
ayatas came to power. Since then Iran
and Pakistan have been enemies and they
still are.
Ankita Kachab. Good evening ma'am G says
uh there's quite a divide of opinion
among GP experts
geopolitics experts uh some say IRGC is
a government system governed through
Islamic law it represents radical Islam
not democratic Iran so needs to be taken
out what's my views what's my view on
this
um the IRGC is the core
organ that or or or body
that governs the
Iran and the IRGC has its own you could
say military. Okay. So the IRGC is is
the actual
um system or organization that embodies
the power and controls that that holds
the power in Iran and the power is
decentralized. There is no one leader.
We have a supreme leader of Iran, but
you kill if the Americans kill him, it
makes no difference to the functioning
of the IRGC because they will put up a
successor immediately or as and when
they please.
So in Iran, the IRGC is the actual
government and the actual um body that
that holds all the power in Iran and it
governs through Islamic law.
It represents Shia Islam. It represents
a it represents a tradition that has
existed in Iran since the Safavidid
dynasty
1500 AD onwards last 500 years
since the Safawid dynasty came to power
in Iran. Iran has been Yeah. Let me just
double check. When did the Safavid
dynasty come to power? I think it's
around 1500 AD.
Let's just quickly double check that.
Safavid dynasty.
Yeah. 1501. So I was almost almost 100%
correct. So uh so they ruled for about
more than 200 years. And that's when
Shia Islam becomes the u dominant form
of Islam in Iran. Today about 95% of
Iran is Shia. So the IRGC governs
through Islamic law, Shia Islamic law.
And that represents a tradition that's
been there in Iran for about almost 500
years.
It and I am sure that the majority of
the people of Iran do support this. See,
we can see because of social media and
the Iranian diaspora
disagreement or opposition to the IRGC
and Sharia law in Iran.
There have been protests in various
Iranian cities before the Americans and
Israelis launched the war. The protests
were against the government of Iran.
They want these people wanted democracy,
freedom, human rights and all that
stuff, right? The secularism in Iran.
But that's only in the big cities. The
big cities are where you have the
western educated English-sp speakaking
people. But the vast majority of Iran's
population is in the rural areas where
you don't have English speaking people
and those people most likely support
Sharia law and Shia Islam. They're more
traditional.
See, one of the reasons why the sha of
Iran, Muhammad Bhaw, became unpopular
was that he outlawed the hijab and the
chador and the the burka.
Most people in Iran wanted that.
So in the big cities women went around
wearing western clothes but in the rural
parts of Iran women remain traditionally
dressed.
So
the question the the true question is
the question that actually matters is
what does the average Iranian person
want? Not what does some critic or some
journalist sitting in London want.
Right? If the average Iranian person
wants Islamic law, Sharia law, uh, Shia
Islam, then let them have it. It's their
choice,
right? We should respect people's
choices.
So why is there a need to take out this
government? If if most Iranians are in
support of the government, if 51% of
Iran supports his government in in a
democracy, that's a victory, right?
So then let the people of Iran make
their own choice is my point.
U
that's how I see it. I believe that we
should respect every country's own
traditions.
Now in in Iran Islam is the tradition
now for the past what 1300 or so years
1200 1300 years it is their religion
now. Shia Islam is the religion for the
past 4 500 years.
Respect it.
And if Iranians don't want it, they
should do something about it instead of
asking Uncle Sam to come and flatten
Iran. Right?
So that's my view. I am of the view that
if we genuinely respect humanity, if we
genuinely respect every country as we
are supposed to in a democratic world,
then we should allow each country to
determine its own future in the way it
thinks best. It thinks is best. That's
what I believe.
Uh Krishant Bordaloy says, "Have you
watched Durand yet?" I'm watching it the
second time. I haven't watched it even
once yet. Yeah, I I most likely will
watch it in the next two or three days.
Okay, I look forward to that.
Anka Kachab says, "How did Porsche
become Iran?" So, the name was changed
in the
early in the first half of the 20th
century.
So
in 1925 or thereabouts the British
appointed a puppet as the sha of Iran.
So until 1925 or thereabouts you had the
Kajar dynasty. Kajar Q A J R Kajar
dynasty that ruled Iran. Okay.
And from 1800 or so onwards Iran becomes
slowly progressively more and more
influenced by the west because the west
was ruling the world at this time right
the European colonization was going was
happening everywhere.
So
Iran also became just like we were you
know in some way or the other influenced
and penetrated by the west in the early
19 20th century. Oil was discovered in
southwest Iran and Iran did not have the
technological knowhow to extract the
oil. So the Kajar dynasty's ruling king
or whatever he was, he gave a contract
to an English man to bring his expertise
into Iran and you know extract the oil
and give Iran
uh royalties for that.
So that's how the Anglo Persian Oil
Company was founded and they gave Iran
16% of the revenues 16% one six and the
rest they they took but eventually the
British what they did was they did a
coup in in Iran and they placed a puppet
in power in Iran whose name was Raza
Bahali
Razasha Raj Razasha and Razasha was was
a British puppet. He continued this in
the whole thing that of of giving the
vast majority of Iran's oil oil wealth
to the British
and Razasha was not a big fan of Islam
and uh he said that you know the word
Persia is an exon it's a name given to
us by foreigners which is not true but
he said it's an exon
and so he he changed the name of the
country to Iran the land of the Arya
people okay so he was was a believer in
in in the civilization of the country in
the Persian civilization but he didn't
like the name Persia. So he was all
about Iran is a civilization not not not
uh just a nation. We have a rich 3,000
year history and he especially gave
emphasis to the pre-Islamic history of
the country and he renamed the country
to Iran, the land of the Arya people.
Yeah. So that's how Persia became Iran
sometime in the first half of the 20th
century. So Raza Sha was in power from
1925 to 1941. In 1941 he was ousted by
the British and the Russians and his son
Muhammad Raalvi was placed as the puppet
leader of Iran. So it's before 1941 and
after 1925 that the name was changed to
Iran.
Anik says
bro at least this is not a question for
me is it
watch the full statement ba Modi said
for Indian Jews Israel is the fatherland
and India is motherland for not for all
not for all Indians okay okay JRxna says
why doesn't India change its name to bat
officially just like Iran discarded the
western Persia name or is it better to
remain a bit anglicized. I am of the
opinion India should rename itself
officially completely to Bharat. Why not
right? But as long as people speak
English, some people people like even I
do I I still use the the word in India
right when I speak English. So uh I
think it's a habit that will go that
will slowly slip away over time. There
was a time when uh Chennai was called
Madras but now most people call it
Chennai. So it happens over time right?
So the word Madras was probably of
British origin. I don't know what what
it means but it's now Chennai right. So
I think India should change the name to
Barat officially. I agree.
Pratipar Roy says are we going to have a
COVID style lockdown in the future due
to oil and gas shortage? Pakistan is
already doing this. I hope it doesn't
happen. I think uh as long as Iran
allows oil tankers to reach India from
straight of hormones, we should be fine
and we can also keep buying oil from
Russia.
So I think we'll be fine. So we won't
have oil shortages hopefully most likely
we won't have it but gas could be a
problem. So in the case of gas shortages
I think some vehicles like autoic etc
may not work.
So there could be some issues but it
won't be a full lockdown in India. It
won't be a covid style lockdown.
If this war continues let's say 6 months
there could be some effects like that
but not a full covid like lockdown in
India. That could be
rationing some measures like you know
flights become more expensive so most
people don't fly and trains keep rolling
and the goods vehicles keep rolling but
maybe autoic go out of order action
something like that could happen but the
major problem is gas not oil and lots of
restaurants and other establishments
could at least temporarily shut down.
Yeah.
Krishan Bordal says parents are even
bringing their kids to the movie. Well
good for them.
Okay. Sashwat Aim says, "Can you tell in
brief about Kir Empire history of
Southeast Asia?" That's a very long
question, sir. The Kir Empire, it was
this empire based in Cambodia. Okay. And
they were a Hindu empire. Later they
became Buddhist.
Uh just like the Champa Empire was Hindu
then became Buddhist. The Kir were also
Hindus and the Shivites.
And they had great kings who had
Sanskrit names and uh they built great
temples like the Priya Vihar temple like
the uh Ankorwat temple. The Ankorwat
temple is in Cambodia rights.
I think the I think even Ankorwat was
built by the Kar most likely. Yes. So
they built great temples etc. and
eventually they like all empires
eventually they declined.
Pratib Kumar Royce says, "What is this
Palanteer Technologies in their links
with the US military?" US Iran war
links. Palanteer Technologies is a
company that builds,
you know, high-end weapon systems like,
uh, you know, drones and whatnot, all
kinds of weapons,
uh, and cutting edge weapons, weapons
that are AI enabled, etc. And u uh one
of the members of the PayPal mafia, I
forget his name. One of Elon Musk's
mentors essentially is the founder.
Peter the isn't it? Peter the let me
just double check that. Palanteer
technologies founder.
What happened?
Let me do it again.
Palanteer technologies founder.
There we have it. It's Peter Theal also
Alex Karp Joe blah blah blah blah blah
etc. Yeah.
Um
but this company now makes weapons
doesn't it? Palanteer.
It's a software company.
So is Anduril the weapons company?
Okay. Interesting.
Okay. So Palanteer is is is a software
company. What about Anduril
anduril? Okay. Anduril is the defense
company. It's the weapons company. Okay.
It's the other way around. Palanter is
the software. Anduril is the Okay. Okay.
Okay. Just like the Lord of the Rings,
Palanteer was that looking glass of
spherical object and you could see
through it. And Anduril was the sword,
the successor of Narcil. So Andrew is
the weapons company and Palanteer is the
software company. Okay. So it's all
about military software and surveillance
software and things like that. Pretty
nasty stuff I suppose.
Shatabish says Rishi Karad indeed
mentioned Dwi Nuka and Tria Nuka
paralleling what we know today as a
molecule including concepts of
metaphysics with amazing clarity. Okay,
I wasn't aware of that but thank you for
letting me know. Very interesting. Di
Nuka and Tria Nuka. That's interesting.
Very interesting. I look into that.
Okay,
that does indeed sound like molecules.
If you have combinations of atoms, that
that obviously is a molecule. Very
interesting.
Ankitakab says, suppose Iran gets hold
of the state of Hormos, what will be the
geoeconomic, geopolitical repercussions,
good or bad for India?
If Iran continues to control the state
of Hormuz
and
the war ends that way and this Gulf
region can still produce oil, then it's
perfectly fine for India
because we have good relations with Iran
and Iran won't stop uh oil from coming
to India. So in that case, it's fine for
India. There's no issue. It's not bad
for India. But if the war ends such that
the entire region is devastated and can
no longer produce oil
but Iran cons control the state of
Hormos then it makes no difference to
India because we can't get oil from the
region.
So it all depends on how this war ends.
If the war ends such that the region
still produces oil then it's great for
India. Even if Iran controls this
region, who cares? We are we are on good
terms with Iran. Even if they control
the state of Hermus, they won't stop us
from from um from
importing oil from the region. So that
will be fine for India. So whether Iran
controls the state of Hermos or doesn't
control makes no difference to India.
Whether the region can still produce oil
or not is what is what makes all the
difference.
So that's that's the thing. Okay. JRXna
says, "Hydration reminder." Thank you,
sir. Thank you. Uh, also a suggestion.
You should play Sidmer Myers
Civilization
7 on live stream because your strategic
thinking make you a world champ. Well,
that's interesting. I've never played
the game. I've seen screenshots of the
game with various maps and things. Never
played it. Okay, I I'll I'll look into
it. Interesting. Very interesting. Very
interesting. Thank you. Arismanor says
my plan to solve the manipul crisis. We
strip ST status from the separatists
from the foreigners.
We stop giving them money. We establish
an Indian army base not CRPF inal.
Drown them in pragmatic subsidies. Build
economy and deport illegals ASAP.
Interesting. Um a lot of it makes sense.
I don't know about the subsidies. Uh my
plan would be first of all deport the
illegals ASAP. That's the first thing
that has to be done. Deport all
illegals, even those who have acquired
Indian documents, deport them all.
Deport all foreigners from Manipur.
Secondly, fence the border. Thirdly, put
the armed forces, not BSF, CRPF for 10
years. Put the Indian army on the
border. Not just in Manipur, but also in
Misoram.
Okay?
and then give subsidies to the people of
Manipur for all the losses they've
incurred because of the this this war
against them
and um yeah and if there are any other
separatist elements in Manipur
non-cookie separatist elements deal with
them too no separatism should be
tolerated no matter what ethnicity it is
right
so that's what needs to be needs to be
done and stop the apart that certain
ethnicities can't own land outside of
the Infal Valley. What sort of horrific
apathide is that?
So the root cause of the Manipur crisis
is the presence of foreigners in
Manipur. Lack lacks of them. Deport them
all. There should be a cut off. The
cutoff should be 1891. Anybody who's
who's settled in Manipur after 1891
should be deported. Simple.
Is it unfair? So be it because those
people have no allegiance to India it
it's and its culture
that's what I think should happen
Divu says can you please explain the
physics of Homie Baba three-stage
nuclear program
look I am not exactly I don't remember
exactly what the three stages are the
last stage is thorium
so
to
how does it work
so you have multiple isotopes of
uranium. Okay.
Uranium 235, 230, 239, 238 is also
there.
And the nice one is 235. Nice as in the
dangerous one. It can be used for
nuclear weapons. It can be used for
obviously nuclear power plants also. How
does a nuclear power plant nuclear
reactor work? You have uranium which
gives off heat and that heat heat boils
water. It produces steam and generates
you know drives a steam engine that
generates electricity. That's how it
works. So we don't have a lot of we have
very little uranium. I think we have
tremendous amounts of thorium but for
the thorium to power nuclear reactors we
need
certain a certain c certain isotopes of
uranium I don't remember which one so in
the first phase you use uranium the
second phase you you what is it
you do some breeding right breeder
reactors that that breed a different
isotope either plutonium or or unanim
And in the third phase, you use that
isotope that you have bred large
quantities of to then do the thorium
reactions and then you can have as much
thorium power as you want. That's kind
of what it is like. I don't remember
exactly what the specifics and details
are. But if you want, I can make a video
about that. So yeah, right. So right now
where are we? The main question is where
is India right now? Are we in stage one?
Are we in stage two? Are we in stage
three? We want to be in stage three.
We want to have a 100 reactors all
generating electricity, power, energy
using thorium. But stage three is the
end goal. Stage three means we are
there. We have come. But where are we
right now? We are somewhere between
stage one and stage two. We have been
very lazy in this matter.
There are some experts who will say we
are almost at stage three. Those experts
have no idea what they're talking about.
Okay, we are somewhere at the beginning
of stage two and that's a problem. Very
slow, very lazy, very unambitious thus
far.
Despite being the nation with the
largest thorium reserves, we are not
even close to stage three. So that's
where we are. Okay. Minimalist Maverick
says new conversion strategy by showing
Jesus as Indian. I think it's an old
conversion strategy.
And if you want these strategies to
fail, you have to educate the people of
India. But the education system is
garbage. It's rotten. It doesn't give
you the tools to understand what these
strategies are. Yeah. Okay. Uh Hersh
Patel says my model extracted core
pattern of your thinking. First
principles reasoning, avoiding dogma,
developing your own mental models and
using writer writing to structure
thoughts to thought. Uh yeah, that
actually is uh how I think kind of.
Yeah. first principles reasoning. Yes, I
think if you have your model go through
all the transcripts
that's like I don't know hundreds maybe
maybe more than a couple of thousand
hours of me speaking I think you will
find everything you need to know about
how I think right yeah so yes certainly
first principles thinking is what I am
very what I emphasize avoiding dogma
very much so yes uh developing your own
mental models models yes I don't know
what my mental models are called but I
have my my own mental models that I have
you that I use that I've developed over
years and then using writing to
structure thought very much so yes if
you write then you you structure your
thoughts better your thoughts
crystallize much better and you can dig
much deeper into your thoughts if you
write if you just think you can't go
very deep so please do post your answer
in comments that'll be very interesting
very interesting maybe I should make a
system like this of my own
all right echo says any change in your
power index after the war USA doomed. I
haven't recalculated the the scores yet.
I think now it's the time to for me to
start that the process. It will take a
few days. Recalculate all the all the
scores.
I think um the the the rankings
the scores will change. I'm not sure the
rankings of the top five, top 10 may
change too much, but the scores will
change. The hard power scores will
change for sure. Is the US doomed? It's
not doomed. It's not doomed but
definitely there's going to be changes
in the scores.
Arismantic says the manipur crisis is
already a conflict economy. It's going
to keep ramping up. We are sleepwalking
into this. Don't be surprised if cookie
terrorists suddenly emerge and cause
havoc across India. I hope it doesn't
come to that. But understand that these
people have no allegiance to India. They
don't even have any allegiance to Burma.
It's a conflict economy. What drives
their economy? ille I mean it's
obviously illegal if you if you plant
poppies poppies are the the plant that
produce opium that can be turned into
heroine and other other horrible
horrible horrible drugs.
So these people what they do is that see
the the hills of Manipur are beautiful
green hills but if you fly over Manipur
today if you're landing in I infal
whatever you will see that the hills are
all brown now and the smoke everywhere
these infiltrators these squatters on
Indian territory they're destroying all
the forests of Manipur
including sacred forests
they're burning everything
the AQI air quality in Manipur must be
like Delhi now I suppose or close to
And they are planting poppies all over
the place. Poppy plantations
and that you can sell to drug lords
across the border in the Golden Triangle
and you can make huge amounts of money
that you can use to buy arms, weapons,
ammunition and do all kinds of illegal
activities.
And I'm not sure why the government of
India is tolerating this. What are we
getting out of it? I just don't get it.
Soldier boy says where do you see India
in the next 10 years considering the US
loses this war and we are on the point
of no return by civilizational
perspective what gives you hope
um where do I see India in the next 10
years if the US loses this war
if the US loses this war they're going
to have to move out of West Asia they
will not be able to reopen their
military bases in the region Iran will
become the regional hedgeim
um Israel will probably still exist, but
it won't be that powerful. It won't be
able to bully Iran anymore.
Um, and the if if the oil economy is not
destroyed, then most likely these
nations will sell oil not in US dollar,
but it's some in some other currency
maybe Chinese, yuan or whatever.
Um, so if that happens, then India will
have more leverage via the US. But
leverage with for what? For less tariffs
and all.
India will need to
to militarize
over the next 10 years. Yeah. India will
have to become um will have to reform
itself. Will it happen? I think it's
unlikely that we do too much too large
of a change in India unless something
drastic happens to India. So I think
India will keep on growing at that 6 7
8% growth rate that is of course all
contingent on whether we have enough oil
and gas. So I think it's going to be
challenging for India next 10 years
and that obviously is the long-term goal
of the US to not not allow India to grow
quickly to India's growth so they
will achieve it even if they lose this
war.
uh especially when it comes to cooking
gas and all that. So I think the the
situation is going to be difficult for
India next 10 years. Now yeah that
optimistic scenario that we had that we
will India will keep growing at a 7 a
six 6 7 8% per year for the next 20
years that seems a little unlikely right
now.
So um maybe the situation stabilizes in
5 years by 2030 but who knows how things
will go. So I think it's going to be
challenging time now for India.
uh from a civilizational perspective,
are we at a point of no return? Not yet.
I don't think so. Not yet. But the way
things keep going, I think we may be at
a point of no return by 2050,
which means that you know just too many
conversions have happened in India and
they the people are too dassinated and
we just give up on our culture. That
could happen.
Minimalist Maverick says if raw can
infiltrate Pakistan like shown in
Durander why not use ro agents like
Jamil Jamali to infiltrate Indian
politics and destroy corruption
because we don't want to destroy
corruption
maybe the objective is to not ever
destroy corruption
maybe I don't know I can't say
if we can do it in Pakistan we can also
do it in India but it's not being done
in India so maybe the objective is to
not do
Okay. Uh, Pratam Sony says, "Is US
standard increasing or lowering?" Same
question for India.
Are India's first of all answer for
India. Are India's standards are is
India increasing its standards? Is India
raising its standards? No. India
standsards are where they are. Not too
much of change happening. Is the US
raising its standards or decreasing or
or lowering its standards? Well, if you
lose a war to Iran, you are lowering
your standards, I suppose. Yeah.
Uh, so the US standards also seem to be
lowering, but they are still way higher,
way higher than India's.
JRXna says, "Making shorts on decoding
ancient Indian Hindu paintings. Have
70,000 views. Started in January 2026.
Shout out, please. A shared view would
be nice." A shared view. How do I do a
shared view?
I'm not sure how to do a shared view,
but uh but I'm glad that you're doing
this. And here's a shout out to you,
JRxna. I suppose that's the uh that's
the URL of your channel, right?
YouTube.com/jrxna.
So yeah, I I'll I'll go and check it out
and I will recommend to all viewers,
please go and check out the channel of
JRxna. All right, good job. Good job.
Keep going.
Aman Singh says, I like to watch your
live stream. Thank you so much. Thank
you so much. I really appreciate that.
Thank you. Aman Singh
Jagenat Vignesh says, "Your moto is
great. Keep raising your standards.
Hydration check. Thank you. Reading the
book delimitation. Must check it with
sense 27 coming." Census 27 coming.
Hydration check. Thank you.
It's almost 4 hours. Good god.
Okay. Um reading the book delimitation
must check with census 27 coming. It's
been sometimes some time since actually
seeing the live stream live. Well, thank
you so much for being on this live
stream. Thank you for reminding me to
have some water. Um, my motto is great.
Yes. And I need to apply it to myself as
well. Uh, reading the book delimitation
by by professor by Dr. Dr. Sik. Now,
what am I saying? By professor Goautam
Desi Raju. Right. Yes.
I It's a great suggestion having 75
states instead of whatever we have now.
it makes a lot more sense. So I agree
completely with with his views and what
he has written in the book. I completely
agree with that and yeah now we hear
that the census is happening census 27.
So let's see if the government takes his
recommendations seriously or not. I hope
so.
Pratik Kumar Roy says what's the
difference you know what is time
difference between space and time? What
is time?
I don't know. No physicist knows what
time actually is. Uh we treat time
differently in different uh theories of
physics. In quantum mechanics, we treat
time as an external classical parameter.
We have no idea how time emerges in
quantum mechanics. When it comes to
general relativity, we treat time as a
as a dimension, as a coordinate.
Once again, we don't know where it
emerges from between the difference
between time and space.
Space is
How do I explain the difference between
time and space? Time is something we
perceive vaguely. Space is something
that that is concrete. We can actually
measure it. Time it's measured in
ticking of seconds and all that. Right?
So time is much much more vague for us.
We vaguely perceive the passage of time.
I don't even know if dogs, cats,
peacocks, turtles, such a try, they even
understand that time is passing. Do they
sense the passage of time? I'm not sure.
And what is time? It's the biggest
mystery in physics.
We don't know what time is. We don't
know where it comes from. We don't know
whether it's something that's inherent
to this this universe or whether it's
something that comes from outside the
universe. We don't know what it is. So,
it's a big mystery in physics. But
that's a great question to ask. And uh
yeah, more physicists need to look into
these fundamental questions. Arismatic
says we should have leveraged our large
population and started biogas plants at
least two decades ago. I completely
agree with you. The technology is here
in and the population is there. When
will we start creating timely backups?
Why are we slow? I don't know. I don't
know. I don't know. Why don't we have
strategic reserves of oil that are much
larger than what than 25 days? Why not
100 days? Why not 365 days?
This also could have been started a
decade ago, two two decades ago. We have
a 1.4 billion population.
If we have bio gas plants everywhere and
when we use all the waste products of
all our population
then we will be self-sufficient in terms
of cook of of uh you know cooking gas
industrial gas completely
self-sufficient
why haven't we done this why didn't we
do this two two decades ago I just don't
get it really I don't get it
okay
Shukla says General Narayan answered
your statement will India go blind of if
operation
two takes place when he said there are
seven eight LO satellites he did not say
that Navik was operational okay the
discussion is about Navik
H
the discussion is about Navik what is
the difference between a Navic satellite
my dear friends please let's let's
unpack this what is the difference
between a Navic satellite and a low
earth orbit satellite what's the
difference a Navic satellite is
a satellite that gives you positioning
data on the planet on the surface of the
planet. So that satellite a Navic
satellite has to be in a geostationary
orbit. A geostationary orbit is roughly
36,000 kilometers from the surface of
the planet. 36,000 kilometers. A LEO
satellite
is about between 150 to 500 km above the
surface maybe 700 km maximum
typically 150 200 300 km above the
surface that's a LEO satellite do you
understand the difference between 36,000
km and 500 km do you understand the
difference in your LEO satellites can't
give you positioning data so if you are
using GPS and you want your missile to
strike exactly at so and so coordinates.
Your LEO satellites can't help you with
that.
Your LEO satellites can't give you
positioning data. Only the Navic
satellites can. But the Navic satellites
are the Navic constellation is now
inoperational.
Which means your even if you have LEO
satellites, your missiles are now blind.
Do you understand?
Your missiles are now blind.
If you are if you have a tank column
going into let's say enemy territory and
they need to know exactly where they are
then they are not getting LO data in
real time
right they don't get LO data in real
time
so how will they know exactly what the
coordinates are
so you see LU is not an excuse you have
7 8 9 satellites it makes no difference
if your Navic is not operational
Okay, it makes no difference whatsoever.
So India will indeed go blind if
operation will indeed be blind if
operation sundur takes place in the
sense that we will not get real time on
demand satellite positioning data if the
Americans switch off GPS it won't work
China won't give us their buu we may
have to rely on Russia Russia's glownas
possibly if Russia shares that with us
my question is why do we have to rely on
others we should have had a Navic
constellation that was fully
operational. Why did we let it slip away
over over 10 years?
So your 78 L Elo satellites will make no
difference to your positioning
requirements.
In the absence of GPS, your 78 alos will
do nothing. They will see what is the
what is a LO satellite? It's a low Earth
orbit satellite close to the surface of
the Earth but above the atmosphere. So
it it's essentially a military spy
satellite. It can take detailed
photographs, zoomed in photographs,
maybe even give you a live video feed
possibly of things on the surface and
depending on what band it's operating
in. It it can even peer through clouds,
but it can't give you positioning data
and position. Why does the US then have
GPS if LEO satellites will do everything
for you? Why has China invested in a
global GPS constellation, BU
constellation? If LEO satellites will do
everything for you, every
self-respecting nation operates LEO
satellites, spy satellites and
positioning satellites at geostationary
orbits because they play different roles
and both are required. If America's GPS
satellites are destroyed,
their LEO satellites won't make a
difference in in their GPS requirements.
Do you understand this fundamental
thing?
Do you understand?
So, Elio satellites
will not make up for the shortfall
that comes out of our Navic
constellation
becoming no longer operational. All
right, that is the correct answer.
And look, I did not want to argue with
the general. He is a much older
gentleman. He's a distinguished
gentleman. He has served in the armed
forces. I have not. So I thought I
should not argue with him and contradict
him. So I stayed quiet. But it doesn't
mean
that what you are saying is correct.
Pratip Kumar Roy is a new member. Thank
you very much Pratip Kumar Roy.
Appreciate that very much. Thank you and
welcome back to the channel's
membership.
Arin Gauti says thank you for the answer
and perspective. Appreciate it. Also
appreciate the honest insight and
analysis. Breath of fresh air from US.
From the US. Okay. You are based in the
US. Okay. Okay. Uh you're very welcome.
You're very welcome. I really appreciate
you being on this live stream and uh and
being a subscriber and asking great
questions. Thank you so much.
Vision says, "Your views, your thoughts
on how the US rescued their pilot and
gunman versus the way India rescued
Abinandon. Just speculation, not bias.
Look, the Americans are claiming they've
rescued their guys. I don't know if
they've actually done it, but let's
assume they've actually successfully
done it. So, how did the Americans
rescue that guy? They sent a bunch of
planes and aircraft which landed in Iran
somewhere and uh then they were able to
extricate the guy and they lost a bunch
of aircraft in the process. Let's see
what kind of aircraft they lost in the
process. Okay, in just one operation.
So the they lost the Americans lost
confirmed losses. One F-15 Strike Eagle,
two HH60 helicopters
damaged. Strike Eagle is destroyed. One
MH6 little bird helicopter destroyed.
One A10 Thunderbolt
um aircraft destroyed.
Two C130 Hercules aircraft destroyed.
And about two MQ9 Reaper drones
destroyed. And there's more damage as
well. So the Americans to save one guy
were were willing to, you know,
have all this equipment destroyed. So
the Americans are sending a message to
the world that we value our
our military personnel and we will do
whatever it takes to bring them back. We
may not value our citizens who may be
homeless, some of them at least. We may
not value the people who are addicted to
fentinil.
We don't care about that. But if our guy
is fighting in another another country,
we're going to do our best to bring him
back. That's the message they are
sending to the world. I think uh that's
a good message to send to the world.
Yeah. Essentially, what they're telling
the world is that our people are more
valuable than your people. An American
citizen's life is more valuable than an
Iranian citizen's life or a citizen of
any other country. That's what they're
telling the world. So, I think if the if
what they're claiming is true, then
great job. You did a great job rescuing
your guy.
How did India rescue Vinandan? We
rescued Abhinandan by arm twisting the
Pakistanis. I think uh what we said to
the Pakistanis is that if you don't send
Abidan back by so and so date so and so
time then we're going to flatten you
with our Brahma missiles and those
missiles and the Pakistanis knew that
India was not bluffing. So they send
Abidan back. So it's a very different
way of sending sending of of getting a
guy back and that's also a great way
great thing to do. Okay.
Monster visualization says a hinsa perma
dharma appears five time in the
mahabarat. Can we analyze each of the
slokas now to understand what it really
says in each of those five five slokas?
It will clear a lot of your of our
doubts. I don't know where to find the
mahabarat full text and find the exact
position in the mahabarat. So I won't be
able to do it now in real time right
now. Okay. Analysis of each of the
shlokas and all that. It's not possible
in a live stream like this unless the
purpose of the live stream is to do
that. This is a general live stream
mostly based on the Iran war of the war
against Iran. So we will not do that.
But my point is very simple. Ainsa perma
dharma appears in the Mahabharat five
times. But what is the Mahabharat about?
The Mahabharat is about war.
Okay. Lord Krishna Shri Krishna tried
his best to have a diplomatic
settlement.
He negotiated with the Koravas on behalf
of the Pandavas. He tried his best. He
gave diplomacy
a lot of chances
right he said just give us five villages
you keep the rest of the kingdom of the
empire just give us the pandas five
villages five brothers and that will be
enough for them the kowavas were
unwilling to do even that so eventually
lord krishna said okay that's it enough
with diplomacy kill them all and then
Arjun has his doubts so Shri Krishna
says
Do not doubt yourself. Your job is to be
a warrior. Be a warrior. I know they are
your cousins. They're your elders.
They're your family members. They're
your blood relatives. But they are on
the side of a dharma. So destroy them
all.
So if you want dharma to prevail, you
have to destroy a dharma
violently if required.
And that is the message of the
Mahabharat. To have dharma, to establish
the rule of dharma, you have to
violently destroy a dharma. That's the
message of the Mahabharat.
I think that's enough of doubt clearing
for me.
Ishan Ishan Baka says
Bara is Ishan K. Bara says if Trump
loses the midterm due to Iran war, can
we call it indirect regime change in the
US since it's due to external factors?
Just curious. See, if Trump loses the
midterms, what happens is that his
party, the Republicans, will lose the
majority in the House. That's what
happens.
Uh it doesn't mean that the Trump goes
out of power. Trump will still be US the
American president, but it will become
much more difficult for him to pass
legislation.
He will still be US president. He will
still decide what happens. He can still
launch new wars if he wants. Nobody can
stop him from doing that. So it won't be
a regime change as such. It will be a
change in the composition of the US
house and possibly senate. Yeah. But not
in the presidency. The president won't
won't go out of power. So it won't
really be a regime change. Okay. Mr.
Rohit says why can't India build jet
engine technology? Can't they reverse
engineer? I think we should reverse
engineer the hell out of everything. Get
a few rafals, open them up, take out
their jet engine. dis dis
uh disassemble every component.
Put them under scanning electron
microscopes if required.
Figure it out.
The French anyway are unwilling to to
share source code and whatnot with us.
So take one Rafal, keep one Rafal as a
guinea pig. Take out the engine, reverse
engine the hell out of it. And then take
a General Electric engine, right? The
Americans are selling. We have paid for
a bunch of those but they are not
selling them. I mean they're not
shipping them to India at the rate that
we are supposed to receive them. But
take one of those engines, disassemble
it, put that under electron microscopes
to see the metallergy of the of the
turbine blades.
So that's how the Chinese did their
thing, right? They acquired a bunch of
Russian Sukhoys, Sukhoy 27s. I think
they took out the Saturn engines and
they reverse engineered the thing. Still
it took them a couple of decades to to
make their jet engine work. The Chinese
jet engine. So India should also do the
same thing. I agree.
Uh Pratip Maroy says cryptocurrency
future. Do you invest in it? I do. I
invest in cryptocurrency. I I've I've
put about $100 worth into crypto just to
see how it works.
No. So I don't invest in it.
Um
and that I did a a bunch of years ago
just as an experiment. What does it look
like? what is what do you do with it?
That sort of thing. So, I don't invest
in crypto. Cryptocurrency future, I
don't know. I think it could all turn
out to be a big fat bubble that just
pops into nothingness possibly.
Vir Kak says they keep traveling back
and forth. Who who does who who is it?
Where?
I don't know. I don't know. Is it
related to some other question that you
asked in the past earlier today? I I
don't know. I don't remember because
it's been 4 hours and 9 minutes and I no
longer remembered what questions I
answered. So I'm not sure what you what
you're referring to unfortunately.
24 BAT says if Russia fought the US
directly who would win
who would win is the nation look if it's
a conventional war the nation that wins
it's going to be
how does Russia fight the US directly?
It can't be fought.
It can only happen if it's a proxy war
like like Ukraine which becomes a direct
confrontation
because otherwise you will need a
Russian invasion of the US or a US
invasion of Russia. In that case the two
nations can fight or they can fight on
some third nation's territory.
If it's on a third nation's territory,
who would win?
It depends on who is able to bring how
much force in that
in that country or the geography
and it will depend on who has more
drones and missiles.
I think Russia could have the upper hand
in the in this case.
Yeah, possibly Russia. And if it's a
non-conventional war, we all lose.
Everybody loses.
Because yeah so it it depends on a lot
of factors. It depends on what kind of
war it is. Where is it happening? Is it
happening on either of these two nations
territories? It is is happening
somewhere else. If it is happening
somewhere else where is it who has how
much force position there? It depends on
so many factors. So yeah, Rich Blaze
says, "Any information on pre-artition
Cindy and Punjabi migrants? Was the
partition fair if they contributed more
to the economic ecosystem? Wild
minority?" I have no understanding of
this this aspect of Indian history. Uh I
don't know anything about preparation,
Punjabi, Hindi migrants. I just know
that they suffered a lot that we know
and they started entirely new lives in
India and many of them did a great job
of it. So great job. Kudos. Was the
partition fair? Of course the partition
was not fair.
The partition was not fair and it was
illegitimate. It was illegal. It was
undemocratic. I don't recognize Pakistan
as as as
a legitimate country. I have nothing
against the people of Pakistan. Nothing
whatsoever.
They are also victims. But Pakistan is
is an illegitimate country.
It's the land of our ancestors. All of
us, all of all of us have have some
ancestors who were from that that
region. How can it just given up? So the
partition was not fair and it has to be
reversed at at the right time. Not
immediately. Not immediately, but
eventually. Okay. WBKD says, "Many say
attacks on Russian refineries are
directed by the CIA." Well, it's a big
possibility. It's a significant
possibility, right?
Pratep Kumar Roy says, "Why do you sound
so logical and others don't?" Okay. I
don't know. I I am just who I am. I'm
just what I am.
Uh are you brainwashing us? I am not
trying to brainwash you or anything. I'm
simply answering your questions based on
what I understand of the world. That's
all I'm doing. That's all I'm doing.
Okay. Someone asked this question to
Professor Jang.
Oh, okay. You're asking this. Okay.
Okay. You're not asking this to me.
Someone asked this question to Professor
Jang, the Chinese gentleman. Why do you
sound so logical and others don't? Are
you brainwashing us? And Professor Jang
responded by further brainwashing.
All right, good to know that.
Okay,
Jiganathan Jiganath Vignesh says, I
asked AI about the efficiency of biogas,
cowdung plus wet waste versus LPG and it
said that biogas is less efficient. So
is there a way to refine where its
efficiency goes up? Also give your POV
on fast builder reactor nukes nuclear
reactors.
Um
I I don't know what the truth is. Okay.
I am not a chemical engineer. I'm not
aware of the See, generally this gas is
methane, right? I think it's methane. Uh
methane. And uh what's the specific
impulse? I don't know what the specific
impulse of methane is. Obviously
specific impulse you're talking about
rocket engineering all so I'm not sure
which gas is how much efficient which
gas is
um
is there a way to refine it and make its
efficiency go up I'm sure there are ways
and means of doing it
but if it is even reasonably efficient
I'm sure it can power a lot of um the
cooking requirements the other
requirements that you have in India
and uh so I'm sure you can use bio gas
for all cooking purposes across India
and use LPG, LNG, whatever for
industrial applications, commercial
applications, right? You can do that.
So, I'm sure that works and I'm sure
there are ways of making it more
efficient also. I I don't know the
details, but I'm sure there is. uh my
point of view on fast breeder nuclear
reactors. Fastreeder reactors
are reactors that use one type of
uranium isotope to breed plutonium I
think or other isotopes
right
nuclear engineering.
A reactor is a machine
in which something reacts and that is
typically the file material that is
typically a uranium isotope
in most reactors and some reactors they
they breed plutonium.
Plutonium is an element that is not
found on earth naturally. It doesn't
occur on our planet but we can breed it
using fast breed reactors. So I think
that's what pass B reactors are used for
and plutonium is much better
uh
facile material for nuclear weapons than
uranium because you need less plutonium
to have a nuclear explosion. Right.
Mlevin is a new member. Thank you very
much McLevin. Thank you very much and
welcome back to the channel's
membership. Really appreciate that.
Kishan Patel. Thank you very much Kishan
Patel.
Scotch2 says, "What are the key areas
India must focus on to not be bullied
even by the US?" Anything an individual
can do. I understand on global scale our
country leadership plays key role than
an individual.
Um, anything an individual can do. As
individuals, all we can do is raise our
standards and that raises the standards
overall of the country. Now, what are
the key areas India must focus on to be
not bullied by even the US?
First of all, India needs to have ICBMs,
intercontinental ballistic ballistic
missiles that can reach anywhere in the
world, any place in the world. That's
one thing India needs to have. Secondly,
India needs to have a tremendous number
of conventional
of ballistic and other missiles for
conventional use, not not necessarily
nuclear uh delivery, you know, not
necessarily for nuclear delivery, for
conventional weapons delivery,
conventional payloads. So India needs to
have a tremendous number. Maybe a few
hundred thousand possibly. India should
possibly have a few hundred,000.
Is it too much? No number is too much.
At least 100,000 missiles of various
kinds. Probably a few hundred thousand
missiles of various kinds. And India
needs to have millions of drones.
Millions of drones of various ranges and
various various capabilities.
Military drones. Um, India needs to
invest in submarines at least minimum 50
submarines and a much more augmented
navy. So I'm saying India needs to
militarize in a 21st century manner.
Yeah, India should really very quickly
develop sovereign AI systems, sovereign
AI and not just chat bots
but uh thinking systems, reasoning
systems, uh audiovisisual systems and
much more. And India should reenter the
space race. We have fallen asleep and
India should develop a global
constellation of geostationary
satellites for our an extended IRS
system you know Indian version of the
GPS all these things need to happen okay
all these things need to happen over the
next 5 10 years and it's certainly
possible to do it and I'm sure there's
more that and India needs to reform
itself have I have I mentioned the
education system today no I have not
India needs to reform its education
system from top to bottom
Yeah, in order to decolonize properly.
Okay.
Kathan explains says, "Hey, see, wanted
to do a podcast with you. Please check
your DMs on Instagram. We go on convo.
We go with convo with Katan. There are
lots of geopolitical developments. Okay.
It will depend on various things like
first of all, where are you based? If
you are based in a place that's outside
of where I'm based, that it will be
difficult for us to do it." And so but I
I'll check your your DMs and I'll check
it out. All right. All right. I will I
will check it out um soon. Uh it's
already very late in India here. So not
tonight but uh tomorrow I'll check it
out. All right. Thank you. 24 Bat says
both D and R both Democrats and
Republicans in the US are similar or the
same on foreign and economic policy.
Both serve the deep state, not the
common man. One side is ultra woke, one
is ultra racist. Well, that's a pretty
I think it's not an inaccurate way of uh
of explaining uh the political landscape
in the US.
Both of the deep state completely true.
Uh both have a very similar foreign
policy. Both have a very similar
military policy. Both have very similar
economic policies.
But ideologically they are different,
right? they are different in their the
policies they may implement or not
domestically perhaps in some less
important areas right and one is
ultravoked the Democrats of course and
the Republicans I could say are
significantly racist so yes I would
agree with you overall yes
known Jack says two factions in the deep
state question mark old money bankers
want to keep the current debt system
alive while tech elites push for a
controlled reset
The tech elites are not quite part of
the deep state but they aspire to become
part of the deep state. So they are
trying to demonstrate the value of tech
especially new tech AI robotics etc to
the deep state and the deep state is
sitting and watching interesting good
good we certainly need the technology
but do we need to make these people part
of the deep state or not? That's what's
happening. So it's not two factions in
deep state. There's only one deep state.
There's only one deep state and all
these tech tech bros and all they're
auditioning for the deep state. They
would like to become part of that. Okay.
Okay. Vijay Singhal says India was
buying Russian oil even after the US
told we didn't stop buying Russian oil
but all of a sudden we reduced the
Russian oil. Can you guess how the US
might have armisted India? See arm
twisting happens in behind closed doors.
It doesn't happen
in public.
So I wonder how the US might have armed
in India. They must have threatened
India with all kinds of consequences.
They must have threatened India that we
will impose huge tariffs on you and uh
deny you access to our economy and we
will no longer deliver any um um um um
jet engines to you.
We may even impose sanctions on you. We
may cut off cut you off from the swift
system which means your economic
crashes.
there's all kinds of threats they can
you know make towards India and threats
that are that they can genuinely
um execute operationalize. So there's
all kinds of threats they could have
used to arm twist India and yet India
did not completely stop buying Russian
oil. We reduced our consumption of
Russian oil for sure. We didn't
completely stop buying Russian oil. We
bought Russian oil we've been buying
Russian oil since 2022 right in large
quantities. We were buying earlier but
after 22 we really really ramped up our
import of Russian oil. So that still
continues and now we are I think once
again increasing our intake of Russian
oil.
Okay. Jaganath Vignesh says what might
be the what might be the future fuel
source for the milit for in the military
vehicles and rockets any new energy
source will be found question mark. And
will there be nukes without radiation?
You can't have nukes without radiation.
You can't have nuclear weapons without
radiation. Okay, that's number one.
Future fuel source in military vehicles
and rockets. Well, when it comes to
rockets,
we currently use chemical rockets. Okay.
Um, you can have nuclearpowered rockets,
but they will
there will be radiation if you use
nuclear rockets. What is a nuclear
rocket? It's a gigantic rocket that that
is powered by nuclear detonations,
nuclear explosions. That can work. Yes,
it can work. Uh so that will have a much
better specific impulse than your
chemical fuels, right? Uh then you have
drives, but those they work in space,
not on earth as far as I know, right?
And the future fuel sources for military
vehicles and rockets. Well, you can have
electric vehicles, but um I'm not sure
if electric vehicles can give you the
kind of power and acceleration and
pickup that that your conventional fuel
vehicles can give you, but eventually
we'll we'll get there. So, most likely
military vehicles, electric vehicles,
electric,
they they'll they'll run on electricity
instead of fossil fuels possibly.
Right. Apart from that, I can't think of
any other fuels.
Can't think of any. Yeah, you know in
science fiction antimatter is a good
fuel but for that you have to produce
large quantities of antimatter or decent
quantities of antimatter which is uh
still science fiction right now. Any new
energy source will be found very hard to
see that happening.
The world is now pivoting towards green
energy but in military in the military
domain it's still all fossil fuels. It's
still all fossil fuels. uh so only
proven technologies are used in the
military speculative technologies and
new emerging nasent developing
technologies are not uh are are not
utilized in the military only proven
technologies
uh I don't know if any new energy source
would be found antimatter is one
promising thing which is in science
fiction but for that hey it's still
going to take decades if not years a
nuclear fusion could be could become
a viable fuel source in the next 20 30
years possibly. Yeah. Okay. After burn
says recently Chicago nuclear startup
CCTE announced a thorium based fuel for
reactors.
A thorium based fuel for reactors.
People involved include India's former
NSA, former chairman of India's atomic
energy commission. What do I think of
this? I think the government of India
needs to get its act together
and not allow these things to happen. A
former former chairman of India's AEC, a
person whose pen drive led to the hack
of certain critical establishments in
India.
This is Yeah, I've heard about this.
This is incredible.
India's former NSA I don't know about
that but the ch former chairman of
India's AC at American energy commission
is now involved in an American startup
for thorium fuel based thorium based
fuel for reactors
this most likely is Indian technology
India doesn't seem to be a serious
nation at this point does it when things
like these keep happening what can I say
it's very disappointing and infuriating
pratip kumares your views about the book
intelligent investor by Benjamin
Benjamin Graham I haven't read it don't
know sorry
Anoj art says is it safe to move to the
UK getting a big opportunity
I'm sure it's pretty safe lots of
Pakistani origin people there but in the
UK it's still pretty safe as long as
well
more or less still safe in the UK but
long in the long term the UK will become
London Londonistan
okay and if If you have daughters,
please please be very careful about your
daughters because you have grooming
gangs all over the UK. Okay. So just
studying you honestly what my opinion
is. Overall it's safe. Overall it's safe
but you have to be careful. Okay. All
the best. All the best.
Uh Rohan Sharma says is the Sassan
surname in JNK related to the Senian
Empire? Those people migrated east after
Arab and Mongol conquests. Bahi records
trace 15 generations. I am not aware
about this. I I don't know about the
history of the sasan surname in in the
history as such of this senians post
their migrations. I know that senians
migrated into India.
There have been Indo-Canian
dynasties in western India.
There have been Indo-sacian dynasties in
western India.
Um
and though they migrated east not after
the Mongol conquest but after the Arab
conquest. Okay. The Mongol conquest came
much later. There was no Senian dynasty
left when the Mongol conquest happened.
There was a Turk dynasty there. The
Quarasma Empire in the 1300s uh 1200
sorry 13th century. So I don't know
about the history of the Sasan surname.
I have absolutely no idea. I don't even
know that it existed. But interesting
that they have a there's a surname like
this in JNK. Could potentially be
connected to the Senians, but I don't
know. I don't know.
Okay. Dave says, "Read Trump's recent
truth social. What a language."
Uh, really? There's something some
something he said. Uh, do you do you
mean this one?
Do you mean this this tweet of this this
post office? Tuesday will be power day,
power plant day and bridge day all
wrapped up in one in Iran. There will be
nothing like it. Open the effing
straight you crazy bastards or you'll be
living in hell. Just watch. Praise be to
Allah.
It sounds unhinged, doesn't he? The
president of the United States sounds
unhinged. But that's just him being
himself. Yeah. Pratip Kumar Roy says um
somebody Gir Girija Prasana Chotaare
says your views about BSF deploying
snakes and crocodiles in India
Bangladesh border. So it's not happened
yet. It is under consideration.
I believe it's the uh respected home
minister I think who has um perhaps made
this uh suggestion this recommendation.
I think uh the phys I think a
feasibility study is being done of this
of deploying snakes and crocodiles in
the Indo Bangladesh border.
Um I would say just try it out. Just try
it out.
The question is how many crocodiles can
you deploy in the region
and at what stage does a crocodile no
longer feel hungry? And if you have a
crocodile sitting there who is no longer
hungry, who can't eat anymore, then what
do you do about that situation? So there
are these logistical problems will be
will have to be looked into. And then
when it comes to snakes, what kind of
snake? Pythons. Pythons can eat one or
two meals
at a time.
Then python goes to sleep for a month,
right? So it can be a python, can be
cobras, sure. But the cobras and
crocodiles should not come into
conflict. Of course, cobras and
crocodiles don't come into conflict. So,
we'll have to look into the logistics of
of this matter, but it's it's it's an
interesting
um yeah, it's an interesting concept for
sure. Deepak dating coach says, "Why
many Hindu farright bow down to western
goras, Trump, MAGA, cheer for the US?
They're not aware that the US
far majority far right uh see us brown
Indians as secondass. I wish we
inherited from our ancestors that we
brown we brown people are superior. So
the problem in India is that in most
Indians one of the biggest problems in
India is the infamous inferiority
complex that we have in India.
I would say most Indians have an
inferiority complex. Most Indians have
been taught that their culture is
worthless. Their ancestors achieved
nothing of value. that India's history
is a history of defeats to superior
peoples and that sort of thing that's
all we are taught
right and the education system is such
that it dassates us
so most Indians have this deep
inferiority complex they see everybody
uh from outside of India as being
superior to them especially white people
and that's why they give full support to
some nations
full support and I remember that when
Trump won his second term
There were some Indians who were praying
in temples for Trump and putting tilak
on Trump's forehead
on his on the forehead in his images in
his pictures and so on.
It's it's a problem of Indians being
being deeply mentally colonized and and
laboring under this massive inferiority
complex. And the way to address this is
to reform the education system without
which Indians will forever perceive
themselves as inferior.
So the education system has to be
reformed but it's not being reformed.
There is no danger of the education
system being reformed over the next
decade at least.
Uh so that's the issue. Why do Indians
and Hindus have this uh this this this
this issue? Because they labor under a
massive inferiority complex and they are
deeply deeply mentally colonized. That's
why we see this phenomenon over and over
again.
Surajbini says this. Is this the worst
side of Trump or are we yet to see
something even worse? On the poly
market, there are 60% chances that Trump
will be impeached before the end of the
term. Well, the end of his term is still
about more than two years away. So,
we'll see about that. Is this the worst
side of Trump? Have we seen the worst of
him? We haven't.
I promise you, we haven't seen the worst
of Trump. There is much worse
lying
behind the scenes. He has the potential
to do much worse than what he is doing
thus far. Okay? Much worse.
And I'm talking about the Iran war. He
could do much worse than what he has
done thus far.
Ready or ready? Says Hindu, the punakata
started and reared by the Mahatma.
A lot
comes from there. A lot.
Yeah,
I agree. I agree.
Shatabish says, "Agree with you on Iran
education system better than India's.
What I was trying to acknowledge is yet
our ability compared to other
countries." Yeah. Yeah. Totally. Uh to
to get into high skill niche tech jobs
world over all the way up to the top
management positions where merit goes.
But it doesn't serve India in any way
whatsoever. See Indians they have the
ability. See
the education system is trash. The
average Indian educ engineer is is not
as good as the average Iranian engineer
because they have not been taught
properly etc. And yet because of our
huge population, you have a large number
of people who are still world class,
better than world class and who go
westwards and they go and get into
highkl niche tech jobs world over and
then they end up serving those countries
and India loses its talent year after
year after year.
Is that a nice thing? It's a terrible
thing. So I agree with what you're
saying
but that's nothing to celebrate. That's
actually
India losing talent year after year
after year.
Wenadesh says, "Hypothetically speaking,
if you were given the chance to join one
ministry in government, which will you
choose and why?" I will choose, if I
were to be hypothetically minister of
something,
what would I choose? I would choose to
be the minister who runs the PMO
which means the prime minister
and then I will declare India to be to
be a presidential system and then I'll
declare myself president
just kidding. Uh hypothetically speaking
if I were given chance to join ministry
well if I'm given full control and full
authority to do whatever I want maybe
I'll start with the education ministry.
Yeah, if there is one. I think we have a
human resources ministry or something
like that.
Yeah. So maybe that maybe that maybe a
space we don't have a space ministry do
we? We don't. We don't.
Okay.
Pratipar Roy says does
uh Pratipar Roy says Ashwini Sharma says
does sir plan to continue the Indian
industries? If not he requests sir to
continue it. Okay,
maybe I should resume that.
It's not permanently stopped.
So maybe I can resume that Indian
interest. Okay, I'll I'll
I could do it potentially. Let's see.
Okay, thank you for the recommendation.
Thank you.
Um Manit says name change would be
perfect at a time when park land is
required.
Yeah, okay. Name change of India to Bat.
I think we can change India's name to
bat now not wait for Ashuba Mahurat
right just do it do it if that's what
you saying change of name from India to
Bat yeah but yes uh Parkland it's not
Parkland it's our land Pakistan is an
illegit illegitimate nation
it was created illegitimately
okay anu says uh you are awesome
allegedly thank you thank you how can
This escalate to World War II. want
India, China, Africa etc etc simply
refused to participate see in a world
war everybody doesn't have to
participate in the first world war was
did various African etc nations
participate no they did not they did not
there was fighting on African nations
territory but by outsiders not by them
in the second world war again there was
fighting in Africa but it was not those
nations who were fighting right so a
world war doesn't mean that every single
nation has to fight
but If you have nations from Europe and
Asia and America all fighting in the
same war, it kind of becomes like a
world war. The more nations get
involved, the more you can call it a
world war.
So right now it's the US which is in
North America fighting against Iran
which is in Asia. And along with the US,
there's another nation Israel that's
fighting against Israel against Iran.
Israel is
politically a western nation but in
geographically in Asia and then you have
the Gulf nations that are also being
dragged into this by as collateral
damage by the Americans and Israelis.
Now if more nations get involved if
Pakistan gets involved for example or if
the Americans force EU or NATO nations
to get involved in this then it starts
then obviously it's it will cause a
chain reaction which because of which
Russia and China may get involved. So
you have more and more of the most
powerful nations getting involved in war
and that is when we start calling it a
world war II.
We will refuse to participate
but if China, Russia, the US, Iran,
EU, NATO nations are all fighting it, it
already becomes a World War II, right?
Kunglay says wishing you a blissful
night. Thank you very much Kanglay G.
Thank you.
Deepak says Tuesday power plant day.
Please explain. Trump has promised that
he will blow up more Iranian power
plants on Tuesday by if Iran does not
open the straight of Hormos by that
time. That's what it means. It means
that Trump wants to blow up and destroy
more Iranian power plants on Tuesday.
Okay.
Yeshuan Praash says retired bodybuilder
from Great Britain. Please please Google
Yashant bodybuilder that's me with
Indian flag. I have watched literally
all your podcasts and videos have helped
me raise standards greatly. Thank you
very much. Yes. Let me Google that. Um
uh let me Google your name. Give me a
second.
Okay,
let's see. Yes,
bodybuilder.
Yes, bodybuilder.
Okay.
So that is you Yeshu Praash.
Outstanding. That is quite a physique
that you had built up during your compet
during the time when you competed.
There we have it. That is an impressive
physique, sir. Outstanding. Really,
really amazing. And thank you so much
for having been a longtime viewer of
mine. Thank you so much. It's it's uh I
really appreciate that sir. All right
sir. I really appreciate it. I really
appreciate you. Do well. All the best
and please keep watching. Please keep
interacting. Thank you so much. Yeshuan
G.
Anu says you forgot to mention a certain
geopolitical expert and YouTube
sensation in the list of people who can
come to power in the next decade or two.
a certain geopolitical a certain Indian
geopolitical expert or YouTube sensation
in a list of people who can come to
power in the next decade or two. Who
could that be?
Well, I don't know who it is. So, I I
don't know if I forgot. I didn't forget
because I don't know who you're
referring to.
A certain Indian YouTube sensation.
I
don't Are you talking about
are you referring to me? I don't know. I
don't know.
Okay. Uh the poster says the poster co
says do you think the Navic failure is a
scop or government armed forces may be
battly baiting Pakistan to act terrorist
attack to take advantage thoughts? Well,
it is
possibly a possibility and if that is
the case, I'll be very pleased that it
is a scop, but um most likely it's not a
scop. I hope I'm completely wrong. I
hope I'm completely wrong, but um yeah.
Yeah. Okay. Pratipar Royce says,
"Unpopular opinion, Arnab Gowami is the
best Indian journalist right now
according to me, far better than than
others in the mainstream media." Well,
you will notice that I go on Arnab's
debate from time to time. Not very
frequently, but once in a while I do go
there, right? And I generally generally
discuss matters related to India's
national interest and geopolitical
interests. So, so yes and he does
discuss uh um matters that other
other channels don't discuss.
Yeah. and and matters that need to be
discussed. So I appreciate that.
Definitely. Right. Ishwar says soldier
boy asking you sir why don't you thought
don't you think UNO is de facto
presidential system and his take on
that? What's an onu o n o e
one nation one election?
Is it a def factor presidential system?
I'm not sure. I've not thought about it.
I'll have to examine one nation election
in detail and what its consequences
could be. I have not given it any
thought. So I don't know is it a de
facto presidential system?
I have to think. I cannot give you a
knee-jerk reaction because that is a
complex matter. So I'll have to think
about it. But interesting question.
Interesting question for sure.
I shall think about this and maybe I'll
speak about this in the next liveream.
ready always ready says hinsa dharma
dharma hsa
I think it's I think the original quote
is only a perma dharma I don't think in
any of in the mahabharat it says dharma
hinsa I don't think it says that but
it's something that people are adding
these days uh to to give this you know
more context and nuance but I think we
should uh we should be faithful to what
the mahabharat the original text says
But yes, the the point of the the whole
Mahabharat story of the events and the
lessons we are supposed to learn from
that is that it is perfectly legitimate
to destroy those who do a hinsa through
through hins means.
Okay. Pratiparroy says technos j bharat
asks despite having so many
semiconductor design engineers why is
there no global India Indian fab chip
design company? If we have one then we
could have easily outsourced production
to TSMC.
We have some of the best software
engineers in India but we have no global
company that that you know produces
worldleading software products.
Right?
So it's the same problem that we have.
We don't have any uh any any any
entrepreneurs who want to take this big
risk of investing tremendous amounts of
money and not getting a profit
immediately but having a profit only
after 5 10 years. The Indian businessmen
and business business women they want
returns immediately quickly. That's why
they will go into
kirana shops business. They will go into
pet foods business. They'll go into all
these things but they will not go into
strategic sectors. Adani goes into
strategic sectors. Do you know that? And
why is Adani the prime target of all the
in all the India haters? Because they go
into strategic sectors sectors that are
not public facing. That's what the
public doesn't know what talk does.
So um that's the issue with India. lack
of ambition, lack of um ind Indian
companies don't do R&D.
Indian companies simply want to get the
products. I mean you have Indian car
manufacturers.
Okay. But the core technology is still
imported under license from Germany or
wherever. That's an issue with India,
you know. So we have so many
semiconductor design engineers but we
don't have any semiconductor company any
any global fabrication company. Very
very unfortunate, right?
Matt Blackbeard says, "India is buying
oil and gas from Iran. Does that reduce
the possibility of being American vasal?
Does US lose leverage on us due to West
Asia war?" Yes. Yes. Both both answers
both questions. Yes. If India is buying
buying oil and gas from Iran, it reduces
the likelihood of India becoming an
American massal. If the US,
you know, if if the result of the war is
is not favorable to the US, the US does
lose leverage over India. Not all of it
leverage over India, but sign certainly
some of the leverage, a decent amount of
leverage they will lose over India if
they lose the West Asia war. Indeed.
Indeed.
Pushina says NATO fought with the US
shoulder-to-shoulder in Libya, Iraq,
Syria, but hesitant to go into Iraq.
Despite North Atlantic organization, it
got engaged out outside of the region.
So why are they hesitating now?
Because this US government is very
different from previous US governments.
In the past, the US has always treated
the NATO nations as equals.
And that's why NATO was willing to fight
in Libya. You had Rafals flying over
Libya. The French send Rafals to Libya,
right? And Iraq. NATO was there in Iraq,
Syria, all that. So the US historically
always treated NATO nations as equals
with due respect and all that. So NATO
was willing to do whatever the US said
and NATO. Yeah, that's why today the US
is treating NATO nations like third
world nations.
There's no respect given anymore. They
are treated like the the US would treat
Sri Lanka. No disrespect intended.
That's how the US is treating NATO
nations and the US is losing in Iran. So
why should NATO now if they are being
disrespected so badly go and shoulder
the burden of the American disaster in
Iran? Why should they? Right? Doesn't
make sense.
Okay. Pratipar Royce says the
brainwashing question was meant for you.
Actually junk part was added later.
All right. All right. Got it. Got it.
Okay. Uh, Pratip says, "Good night, sir.
Sweet dreams." Thank you very much,
Pratip. Good night to you as well. And
we shall now very quickly wrap up this
session.
Um,
news
sai says, "Jit Dwal sir son, UK citizen,
SJ Shankar,
son, US citizen. I think facts are
facts. What can I do about facts?
Facts are facts.
Aditya yada says, "What do you think of
sand back batteries?" Sand batteries.
What is that? Let's quickly Google that.
Sand batteries.
So, I'm not aware of this new
technology. Sand battery. A large scale
high temperature thermal energy storage
system that uses sand or similar
materials as its storage medium. What
are sand batteries? D.
Okay. So, it's some kind of technology.
I'm not aware of it. I'll have to look
into it. I'm sure it's some
um you're storing thermal energy means
heat inside sand overnight or something
and then you can Okay. So, I'm not sure
exactly how it works. I'll have to look
into it which may take some time but
looks like some innovative new
technology. It looks like
Parici Raja says Durand is based on
Indian spy raind Koshik question mark
possibly. Possibly. I don't know for
sure, but it looks like it could be.
Yes.
Aim Sapion says, "I feel my motherland
is being choked. I feel sometimes very
worried about bigger nations like China.
USA will stop all growth like US did
with Japan by forcing it to sign Plaza
Accords. Your views?"
So the US was able to force Japan to
sign the Plaza Accords because Japan is
under US military occupation and Japan
can't say no.
See, Japan is under permanent US
military occupation. It was in the 1980s
when the Plaza Accords happened. It's it
still is. The US has more than 130
permanent military bases in Japan, which
means it's got a whole armed force
deployed across Japan, Army, Navy, and
Air Force. Japan is under full scale
American military occupation. So when
the Americans then say to Japan, sign
the sign this piece of paper, Japan has
no choice. they have to do it right. So
the Americans can't do that to India.
They can arm twist India which they do
but they can't force us to sign
something which is harmful to us. They
can bribe us into doing something I
suppose and so on. So that depends on
the quality of the leadership and so on.
Today the leadership is much better than
than in the past. So you are right to
feel worried about the future of India
because India is not a very powerful
country.
It's more powerful than most countries
but still not compared not powerful
compared to the US, China or Russia.
Russia is not a problem for us. The US
and China are and the US is treating
India as an adversary. The US is not
being friendly to India at all. Okay?
Look at all everything they're doing.
It's it's not being friendly to India.
It's being hostile to India.
So it is right, you're right to feel
worried and hopefully I would say that
you know as long as we have the right
leadership as long as in this democratic
system people keep voting the right way
for the right people as long as that
happens we we will have a good chance of
doing well and uh
yeah if we can hold out without being
without becoming a vasal by 2050 then I
think by even 2040
yeah then I think then eventually we'll
become unstoppable.
Yeah. So I think both China and the US
have a similar approach towards India
but in different ways. Pinas says
hydration reminder Sji did saluted
dedication. Thank you. Five hours
straight almost five hours. Even PW
class 12 marathons don't go so far. Good
night. Good night. I don't know what PWA
is but all right. Thank you. Oh, physics
walla. Oh, physics walla. Oh, I see. I
am not aware of that. Uh thank you so
much. Thank you so much. and I shall end
this soon now. Thank you. Matt
Blackbeard says, "Prioritizing Synind
Baljasthan over P could
Pakistan's trade via Karachi, protect
Hindu minorities and secure energy via
Iranian pipelines, though it presents
immense geopolitical risks.
I think Sindaran Maljasthan
prioritizing them makes more sense. They
are way less radicalized than Punjab
than the Pakistani Punjab for sure.
Right.
Um yeah I I I agree with you. So if you
can somehow you know
have Pakistan balconized and Synind and
Balojasthan become independent nations
then it could offer India significant
opportunities to uh first of all have a
peaceful neighborhood. Yeah. and and
help the people of these two regions,
right, as a friendly nation and also
access Iranian oil and potentially even
gas uh through Sund Maljasthan.
Yeah. But obviously balconizing Pakistan
is easier said than done because
Pakistan is under US protection. So and
and trying to do that would entail
significant risks. Yeah. But if it
happens, it'll be beneficial not just
for India but for Synind, Baluchasthan
as well as for Iran.
Okay. And that was the last of the super
chats. So I think I shall now call it a
night. It's been almost 5 hours. We did
not quite cross the five hour mark.
Okay. There's one more question. Gorav
Chavda says, do you see any move Trump
can do and win the next election in the
United States? A president can be
elected twice, two terms. And Trump has
already he's he's already into his
second term as president. So he can't
stand one more time for election as per
the current rules, current laws. So um
Trump is not going to get a chance for a
third term anyway, right? Next
presidential election won't happen.
Well, if you're asking about the
midterms,
do I see any move Trump can do and win
the midterms that happen in November
this year? Well, he has to win this war
against Iran. And that's why he's so
desperate. But that is easier said than
done. All right, that brings me finally
to the live stream to the end of this
live stream. All right, thank you very
much everybody. Thank you very much. I
shall now call it a night. I take your
leave. We shall do a live stream about
this matter very soon in the coming
week. So, keep learning, keep asking
questions, keep raising your standards,
and take care. I shall see you very soon
in the next one. Good night for now.